<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl" type="text/xsl" media="screen"?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css" type="text/css" media="screen"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
    <title type="text">al3x</title>
    <subtitle type="html">Where Alex Payne blogs.</subtitle>
    <link href="http://al3x.net/" />
    
    <updated>2009-01-12T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Payne</name>
      <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
    </author>
    <id>http://al3x.net/</id>
    <geo:lat>38.885337</geo:lat><geo:long>-77.09512</geo:long><link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/al3x" type="application/atom+xml" /><entry>
      <title>The Thing About Security</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2009/01/12/the-thing-about-security.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2009-01-12:2009/01/12/the-thing-about-security.html</id>
      <updated>2009-01-12T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com" title=""&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, the thing I work on, had some security issues. Earlier in the week a phishing attack started going around. Then, someone used a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dictionary_attack" title=""&gt;dictionary attack&lt;/a&gt; to grab the account of one of our support staff, who has administrative privileges on the site. We cleaned up both of these issues just as fast as we could. The company communicated quickly and openly about what happened, and if anything, the press seemed to encourage more people to check Twitter out. It was a stressful week, but it forced some positive changes.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;It stings a bit to have experts like &lt;a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2009/01/bad_password_se.html" title=""&gt;Bruce Schneier&lt;/a&gt; call us out &amp;#8211; and  rightly so &amp;#8211; for not shoring up holes like this sooner. Defending against a dictionary attack &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; basic stuff. Our fix for it was an afternoon&amp;#8217;s work. But dictionary attacks just aren&amp;#8217;t something that&amp;#8217;s defended against by most web authentication stacks out of the box, which means the vulnerability lingers until a security review or a successful attack. In part, I think this is due to increasing specialization in computer security education, but that&amp;#8217;s a topic for a longer post.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The thing about security is that it requires stakeholders. I have a security background, but Twitter&amp;#8217;s security isn&amp;#8217;t my job. In fact, my job is pretty much the opposite: I open up as much of Twitter&amp;#8217;s functionality as I can without (hopefully) making the system insecure. So while I&amp;#8217;ve usually been a &amp;#8220;first responder&amp;#8221; to security incidents because of my background, it requires a major mental context switch from the work I normally do.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Several months after I joined Twitter in early 2007, I suggested to the team that we do a full internal security audit. Stop all work, context switch to Bad Guy Mode, find issues, fix them. I wish I could say that we&amp;#8217;ve done that audit in its entirety, but the demands of a growing product supported by a tiny team overshadowed its priority. Now we&amp;#8216;re in an unwelcome position that many technical organizations get into: so far into a big code-base that&amp;#8217;s never seen any substantial periodic audits that the only way to really find all the issues is to bring in some outside help &amp;#8211; something I sincerely hope we end up doing, but is not my call.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Outside security review is about spending enough money that your organization becomes its own security stakeholder. Invest in a high-priced security consultancy&amp;#8217;s time for a week and you&amp;#8217;d damn well better do something with their findings, right? It&amp;#8217;s still a reactive model for a product&amp;#8217;s security life-cycle, rather than a proactive one, but it&amp;#8217;s something. Ultimately, outside security audits are the price a company pays for not building security mindfulness and education into day-to-day development.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;My advice: be a stakeholder in your organization or product&amp;#8217;s security from day one. If you don&amp;#8217;t have time to be that stakeholder, find one, either inside or outside of your company. Make sure that dollars are on the line, or it won&amp;#8217;t get done. There are hundreds of security issues in any complex system that fall under the heading of &amp;#8220;basic stuff&amp;#8220;, and they won&amp;#8217;t get fixed until that happens.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Though maintaining users&amp;#8217; privacy and trust is incentive enough, the cruel reality is that good security is fueled by more than just good intentions and best efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/510245627" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>My Interview with Waferbaby</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2009/01/02/waferbaby-interview.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2009-01-02:2009/01/02/waferbaby-interview.html</id>
      <updated>2009-01-02T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href="http://waferbaby.com/" title=""&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt;, perhaps better known as Waferbaby, has started a new section of his ever-evolving web presence that features interviews with people about their hardware and software setups. It&amp;#8217;s called, appropriately, &lt;a href="http://waferbaby.com/setup" title=""&gt;The Setup&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;#8217;m flattered to be the &lt;a href="http://waferbaby.com/setup/2009/01/02/al3x" title=""&gt;first person Daniel interviewed&lt;/a&gt; for it.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve reproduced my answers here for my own record-keeping. In case you&amp;#8217;ve ever wanted to know basically anything about how I compute, I tried to answer Daniel&amp;#8217;s questions in extreme detail. The speculative final question was the most fun to answer.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;So who are you, and what do you do?&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m &lt;a href="http://al3x.net/" title=""&gt;Alex Payne&lt;/a&gt;. I go by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/al3x" title=""&gt;al3x&lt;/a&gt; around the Interwho. I work at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/" title=""&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco as their &lt;a href="http://apiwiki.twitter.com/" title=""&gt;API&lt;/a&gt; Lead. Our API is how we expose the things you can do with Twitter in a way that programmers can use in their own applications and websites. Part of my workday is spent writing code to make the API go, and part is spent helping developers out with their questions and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;In my free time, I&amp;#8217;m working on a book about the &lt;a href="http://scala-lang.org/" title=""&gt;Scala&lt;/a&gt; programming language. I geek out on programming languages, economics, culture, and theory. I &lt;a href="http://seriousdjs.net/" title=""&gt;DJ&lt;/a&gt; with a friend once a month.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;What hardware are you using to get your work done?&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I have a 15&amp;#8221; &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macbookpro/" title=""&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, one of the final revisions before the current black-bordered unibody design. It&amp;#8217;s got a 2.6 GHz Core 2 Duo processor and 4 GB of memory. I hook it up to a 30&amp;#8221; &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/displays/cinema/" title=""&gt;Cinema Display&lt;/a&gt; when I&amp;#8217;m at work, and I prop it up on &lt;a href="http://www.raindesigninc.com/ilap.html" title=""&gt;Rain Design iLap&lt;/a&gt; when I&amp;#8217;m at home. I type &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dvorak_Simplified_Keyboard" title=""&gt;Dvorak&lt;/a&gt;, but I leave my keycaps in their factory default QWERTY layout.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Instrumental to having just one machine is a good networked storage and backup strategy. I have a &lt;a href="http://www.readynas.com/" title=""&gt;ReadyNAS NV&lt;/a&gt; at home with about 750 GB of expandable RAID storage. Most of the disk goes to store media that I&amp;#8217;d flip out if I lost, and the rest goes to &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/timemachine.html" title=""&gt;Time Machine&lt;/a&gt; backups. I&amp;#8217;ve also started backing up essential files with &lt;a href="https://www.backblaze.com/" title=""&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I always have my original (pre-3G) 8 GB &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/" title=""&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt; with me. I listen to &lt;a href="http://store.shure.com/store/shure/en_US/DisplayProductDetailsPage/productID.106610400" title=""&gt;Shure SE110MPA&lt;/a&gt; headphones on the go and &lt;a href="http://www.audioengineusa.com/a5_home.php" title=""&gt;Audioengine 5&lt;/a&gt; speakers over an &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/airportexpress/" title=""&gt;AirPort Express&lt;/a&gt; at home. My home network is tied together by a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linksys_WRT54G_series" title=""&gt;Linksys WRT54GL&lt;/a&gt; wireless router running the &lt;a href="http://www.polarcloud.com/tomato" title=""&gt;Tomato&lt;/a&gt; firmware.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;And what software?&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I spend most of my day flipping between &lt;a href="http://macromates.com/" title=""&gt;TextMate&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/technology/unix.html" title=""&gt;Terminal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/safari/" title=""&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href="http://fluidapp.com/" title=""&gt;Fluid&lt;/a&gt; app for &lt;a href="http://mail.google.com/" title=""&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt;. I write Scala and Ruby code in TextMate, run tests and such in Terminal, and answer hell of email with Gmail. I keep Safari mostly ad-free with &lt;a href="http://safariadblock.sourceforge.net/" title=""&gt;Safari AdBlock&lt;/a&gt; and speed up searching with &lt;a href="http://www.inquisitorx.com/safari/index_en.php" title=""&gt;Inquisitor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/ichat.html" title=""&gt;iChat&lt;/a&gt; for IM and &lt;a href="http://iconfactory.com/software/twitterrific" title=""&gt;Twitterrific&lt;/a&gt; to interact with Twitter. &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/300.html#ical" title=""&gt;iCal&lt;/a&gt; syncs up to &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/calendar" title=""&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt; for scheduling, and &lt;a href="http://culturedcode.com/things/" title=""&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt; keeps track of my tasks on both my MacBook and my iPhone. I&amp;#8217;ve recently started journaling, and I use &lt;a href="http://www.marinersoftware.com/sitepage.php?page=85" title=""&gt;MacJournal&lt;/a&gt; for that. I keep a big library of PDFs (academic papers, presentations, books, &amp;#38;c.) in &lt;a href="http://www.yepthat.com/yep/index.html" title=""&gt;Yep&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ve taken to storing sensitive files in encrypted disk images managed by &lt;a href="http://www.knoxformac.com/" title=""&gt;Knox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I also run some of the usual &amp;#8220;power user&amp;#8221; Mac enhancements: &lt;a href="http://www.smileonmymac.com/TextExpander/" title=""&gt;TextExpander&lt;/a&gt; to make emails go faster, &lt;a href="http://www.obdev.at/launchbar/" title=""&gt;LaunchBar&lt;/a&gt; to get to what I need quickly and to keep my clipboard history accessible, &lt;a href="http://growl.info/" title=""&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://growl.info/documentation/hardwaregrowler.php" title=""&gt;HardwareGrowler&lt;/a&gt; to get visual notifications from software, and &lt;a href="http://lightheadsw.com/caffeine/" title=""&gt;Caffeine&lt;/a&gt; to keep my Mac awake while watching web videos and such. I keep tabs on my machine with &lt;a href="http://islayer.com/apps/istatpro/" title=""&gt;iStat pro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href="http://www.getdropbox.com/" title=""&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; at Twitter to share documents, and we make pretty extensive use of &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/apps/intl/en/business/index.html" title=""&gt;Google Apps&lt;/a&gt;. We use &lt;a href="http://trac.edgewall.org/" title=""&gt;Trac&lt;/a&gt; for ticketing internally, but I keep API-related tickets public on &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/twitter-api/issues/list" title=""&gt;Google Code&lt;/a&gt;. We do code reviews with &lt;a href="http://www.review-board.org/" title=""&gt;Review Board&lt;/a&gt; and browse our &lt;a href="http://git.or.cz/" title=""&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; repositories with &lt;a href="http://hjemli.net/git/cgit/" title=""&gt;cgit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve usually got &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/" title=""&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/" title=""&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; playing, though lately I&amp;#8217;ve been listening to &lt;a href="http://linktoapp.com/bloom" title=""&gt;Bloom&lt;/a&gt; play itself when I need to focus. Speaking of focus, I use &lt;a href="http://willmore.eu/software/isolator/" title=""&gt;Isolator&lt;/a&gt; to get distractions out of the way. When I need distractions again, I see what&amp;#8217;s on my &lt;a href="http://www.instapaper.com/" title=""&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/reader/" title=""&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;What would be your perfect, ultimate setup?&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Joy" title=""&gt;Bill Joy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LN2shXeJNz8&amp;#38;feature=channel_page" title=""&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; at this year&amp;#8217;s TED conference, &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;d argue today that we have incredibly powerful computers, but we don&amp;#8217;t have very good software for them&amp;#8220;. I&amp;#8217;m of the same mind.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Hardware-wise, my current setup is a dream. I love having just one machine to look after, and I love that it&amp;#8217;s both portable and powerful; my only wish would be for a workday&amp;#8217;s worth of battery life. I can get decent network access nearly anywhere via &lt;a href="http://www.wireless.att.com/businesscenter/broadbandconnect_b2b/?_requestid=42465" title=""&gt;HSDPA&lt;/a&gt; if Wi-Fi isn&amp;#8217;t available. The Cinema Display lets me sprawl out. My ReadyNAS gives me a sense of security about my data. My iPhone lets me leave the house with just my keys, my wallet, a pair of headphones and this one little magical device that can connect me to anyone, direct me anywhere, and entertain me for days. It&amp;#8217;s a good time for hardware.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Software is another story. I&amp;#8217;m &lt;a href="http://al3x.net/2008/10/22/on-flight-to-old-text-editors.html" title=""&gt;perpetually dissatisfied with my text editor&lt;/a&gt;, the tool I spend the most time with. &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/" title=""&gt;OS X&lt;/a&gt; is the best Mac experience there&amp;#8217;s ever been, but it&amp;#8217;s hardly the best computing experience I can imagine. The iPhone is an incremental improvement, but I can&amp;#8217;t accomplish the majority of my daily computing tasks on it comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I want to interact with my computer in a fundamentally different way. The desktop metaphor is dead; a generation of children have grown up never working with the physical objects that the virtual desktop represents. What I really want is a modernized &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plan_9_from_Bell_Labs" title=""&gt;Plan 9&lt;/a&gt;, a software platform that&amp;#8217;s designed from the ground up for our networked, distributed world. If you try to placate me with the assertion that the Web is this new operating system I will become violent.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I want better software: more usable, more accessible, more open, more secure, more integrated, more seamless. I want a better software development experience. I want better programming languages with better development toolkits. Fundamentally, I want better abstractions for the same computation I can do today with all that lovely hardware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/501221539" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Why I Don't Work In Information Security</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/31/why-not-infosec.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-31:2008/12/31/why-not-infosec.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-31T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the web was abuzz with news about a &lt;a href="http://www.win.tue.nl/hashclash/rogue-ca/" title=""&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; released at the &lt;a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2008/" title=""&gt;2008 Chaos Communication Congress&lt;/a&gt;. This paper details an attack against the SSL certificates that web browsers and other software use to verify and encrypt communication between client and server.  Some of my younger security industry friends were feverishly announcing that the attack &amp;#8220;breaks the Internet&amp;#8220;. Old security hands like &lt;a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2008/12/forging_ssl_cer.html" title=""&gt;Bruce Schneier&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=2343" title=""&gt;John Viega&lt;/a&gt; said, respectively, &amp;#8220;[t]his isn&amp;#8217;t a big deal&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;there is little to worry about&amp;#8220;. Which is it?&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Over lunch, I commiserated with a coworker at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com" title=""&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; about this odd event, as it&amp;#8217;s a prime of example of why he and I no longer work in information security.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Much of the tech world is obsessed with engaging in macho pissing contests, but no part more so than computer security. In the case of yesterday&amp;#8217;s announcement, the researchers in question were more concerned with their ability to present their findings at a popular hacker conference than with guaranteeing the safety of the Internet. Why else would they &lt;a href="http://blog.wired.com/27bstroke6/2008/12/berlin.html" title=""&gt;put the organizations they disclosed their findings to under NDA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.links.org/?p=480" title=""&gt;not consult the authorities on the most widely-deployed SSL implementations&lt;/a&gt;? Building reputations and managing PR is the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;This culture of one-upsmanship doesn&amp;#8217;t mean that computer security is a stagnant discipline. It does, however, mean that the people who choose a path of humility about their work don&amp;#8217;t get the rewards &amp;#8211; financial and otherwise &amp;#8211; that they deserve. This is a shame, and it&amp;#8217;s to the detriment of digital security as a whole. My coworker suggested that an academic, peer-reviewed approach to security research would ultimately be more beneficial to the Internet community as a whole. I don&amp;#8217;t have the authority to comment, but I do feel that most anything else would be an improvement on the traveling hacker conference circus we have today.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Secondarily, I don&amp;#8217;t work in information security because of the technologies that have become prevalent in the industry. Not that I have any particular talent in them, but both exploit development and reverse engineering are all about Windows, and have been for several years. Working with Windows day in and day out is a mind-numbing prospect, even if the theoretical payoff is control of 90% of the computers on Earth. Application-level attacks are mostly about the web, and honestly, I&amp;#8217;m deathly bored of the client-side web.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;These reasons are a big part of why I&amp;#8217;ve ended up working in the &amp;#8220;under-the-hood&amp;#8221; part of web application development for the past two years, even though I spent most of my adolescence dreaming of getting paid to hack. Interestingly, I&amp;#8217;m not alone. I&amp;#8217;ve met a number of ex-security people who&amp;#8217;ve ended up building high-performance systems for the web. It&amp;#8217;s still a pissing contest, of course, but a much less public one, and with much less of an agenda.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Someday, I expect I&amp;#8217;ll come back to information security. Despite the politics, it&amp;#8217;s compelling, high-impact work. I hope, though, that the field&amp;#8217;s culture has changed by that time. I&amp;#8217;m not holding my breath.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Addendum, Jan 17, 2009:&lt;/em&gt; Two of the people involved with the SSL hack replied to me about this post via email. Alex Sotirov said:&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;#8220;We already have an academic, peer-reviewed approach to security and it is not&lt;br /&gt;working. Academic papers about the problems with MD5 collisions have been&lt;br /&gt;published since 2004. The exact same attack that we did was described in an&lt;br /&gt;academic paper in 2007, but even this was not enough to get the CAs to&lt;br /&gt;discontinue using MD5.&lt;/blockquote&gt;	&lt;blockquote&gt;When we got up on stage and presented our real rogue CA certificate, the CAs&lt;br /&gt;were finally forced to do what they should have done years ago. Verisign&lt;br /&gt;stopped using SHA-1 just 5 hours after the talk.&lt;/blockquote&gt;	&lt;blockquote&gt;I am not disputing that this is a pissing contest and that my personal&lt;br /&gt;motivation to do this work is far from altruistic, however the result is that&lt;br /&gt;the Internet is a safer place today than it was on Dec 29.&amp;#8221;&lt;/blockquote&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Jake Appelbaum had this to say:&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;#8220;[W]e were actually working towards making the internet safer; we weren&amp;#8217;t harming anyone and that harm reduction is a large part of how we planned our release. We informed the relevant parties and we didn&amp;#8217;t release anything that could harm anyone. The information to do the chosen prefix attack had been public since 2007.&amp;#8221;&lt;/blockquote&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Both are smart guys, and they know the security world far better than I do. It sounds like had the right intentions, along with their professional interests, in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/499784480" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Journaling vs. Blogging vs. Twittering</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/29/journaling-vs-blogging.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-29:2008/12/29/journaling-vs-blogging.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-29T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve begun to keep a private journal/diary/logbook. The format I&amp;#8217;ve adopted is simple: one entry per day consisting of two paragraphs. The first paragraph has a sentence for everything noteworthy I&amp;#8217;ve done that day. The second paragraph consists of what I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about. Activities and thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Since I already record my activities and thoughts on this blog and via &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/al3x" title=""&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ve had to rationalize the effort of keeping an additional record. Please excuse the meta while I explore as much.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;vs. Blogging&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The primary and obvious difference between journaling and blogging is that a journal is private. A journal exists only for the author&amp;#8217;s personal consumption, or possibly as a posthumous record of a life. Without the modest audience my blog has accrued, I have no incentive to filter what I write for content or style. I can be as dry or as flowery as I like and nobody need suffer.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;My earliest blogging was more diary-like. Over the years the frequency of my posts has decreased, but my personal satisfaction with what I write here has increased in kind. Now, rather than forcing myself to write every day (as I am with the journal), I wait to blog until I have a mostly-formed idea to share that I hope will appeal to others. I do this because it&amp;#8217;s the style of blogging that I most enjoy reading. Daily, guaranteed, newspaper-like output is fine on the web, but it&amp;#8217;s not what I think of as blogging, and neither is an open diary.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I was asked while musing on journaling via Twitter if there&amp;#8217;s a practical reason not to simply keep a journal in a local installation of one&amp;#8217;s favorite blogging software. I think the difference is in the aesthetics of the tools. When I see the &amp;#8220;frame&amp;#8221; of a blog around a collection of words, I&amp;#8217;m conditioned to read and write a certain way. You wouldn&amp;#8217;t write a novel in a paper diary; I&amp;#8217;m sure someone has, but the tool doesn&amp;#8217;t fit the task. A private blog for oneself seems to me like a different animal than a journal or logbook.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;vs. Twittering&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Twitter is a convenient way to record each activity of significance in my day, the sum of which comprises the first paragraph of my daily journal entry. But doing so would pollute my timeline with (even more) inanities, and I wouldn&amp;#8217;t wish that on the more than five thousand lovely people who follow my updates.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The solution would be to create a second account, but I don&amp;#8217;t want to use Twitter this way. Even though the question posed by Twitter is &amp;#8220;what are you doing?&amp;#8220;, I rarely answer it. In large part this is because my answers would be uninteresting. My favorite Twitterers crack jokes, link to engaging content, and post all manner of non-sequiturs and odd mutterings. I try to make my updates as enjoyable to read as theirs. Again, my primary barometer for style and voice is dictated by exemplars of the medium in question.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Using Twitter as nothing more than a log of one&amp;#8217;s activities ignores the service&amp;#8217;s social aspect. As well, not everything I want to record about my day or the ideas kicking around in my head will fit into 140 characters.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The difference between journaling and blogging or Twittering isn&amp;#8217;t simply that a journal is private, it&amp;#8217;s stylistic. Good blogging is not journaling. Good Twittering is not journaling. Good journaling may have elements of both media, but journaling entails a distinct voice shared within a well-considered context.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Because I have my own particular format for my journal (but one that may change), I&amp;#8217;m considering storing it in &lt;a href="http://couchdb.apache.org/" title=""&gt;CouchDB&lt;/a&gt; as a way to experiment with that document database. I&amp;#8217;m curious to see what intelligence I can programmatically extract from the journal once the corpus of entries is sizable. Until then, journaling is purely an act of mental discipline, and one that will remain separate from the other ways in which I share my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/498123779" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Software I Paid For But No Longer Use</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/24/paid-dont-use-anymore.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-24:2008/12/24/paid-dont-use-anymore.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-24T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As much as I like open source, I enjoy paying for software. Give me a good solution with a nice interface, and I&amp;#8217;ll give you some reasonable amount of money.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Digital life being fluid and transient, even paid software can quickly fall to the bottom of the virtual junk drawer. Sometimes I feel that an application was worth paying for if only for temporary use, and sometimes not.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of discovering which purchases I valued and which I regret, two lists.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;Desktop Apps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://acquisitionx.com/" title=""&gt;Acquisition&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;file sharing has long since moved on from Gnutella. I&amp;#8217;ve heard it said that there&amp;#8217;s no sense in paying for file sharing software, and I think I&amp;#8217;ve come around to that. Moderate regret.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mirasoftware.com/BPE2/" title=""&gt;BluePhoneElite&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;worth every penny, even though its days are over. The iPhone can&amp;#8217;t do all the tricks that my &lt;a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/cell-phones/sony-ericsson-t616-at/4505-6454_7-20912537.html" title=""&gt;Sony Ericsson T616&lt;/a&gt; could do when hooked up to BluePhoneElite. No regret.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nullriver.com/products/connect360" title=""&gt;Connect360&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;worked great while I had an Xbox, but I&amp;#8217;ve long since sold it. Moderate regret.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://growlichat.com/download.php" title=""&gt;GrowliChat&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;deprecated by &lt;a href="http://www.ksuther.com/chax/" title=""&gt;Chax&lt;/a&gt;, which I also no longer use but never paid for. I&amp;#8217;m not sure why I ever wanted Growl notifications for IM presence, as it&amp;#8217;s distracting and useless. Little regret, though, as it was all of $5.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php" title=""&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;slight regret. I have enough of a personal organizational system set up that this automated filing utility didn&amp;#8217;t really provide much benefit for me.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.red-sweater.com/marsedit/" title=""&gt;MarsEdit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;I always just wanted to write blog posts in my text editor, and now I can. No regret, though, as I got MarsEdit for free when I bought a license for&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newsgator.com/INDIVIDUALS/NETNEWSWIRE/" title=""&gt;NetNewsWire&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;no regrets here. I&amp;#8217;ve long since switched to &lt;a href="http://google.com/reader/" title=""&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt; by way of &lt;a href="http://www.newsfirerss.com/" title=""&gt;NewsFire&lt;/a&gt; (see below), but at the beginning of my blog-reading days, NNW was essential and a pleasure to use.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.newsfirerss.com/" title=""&gt;NewsFire&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;paid for it, loved its simplicity compared to NNW, but then it was made free. Moderate regret.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bitcartel.com/pandorajam/" title=""&gt;PandoraJam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;this was useful when Twitter had a shared AirPort speaker in the office, as it took most of the personal taste out of what got played. (&amp;#8220;Don&amp;#8217;t blame me, I put it on the Joy Division station.&amp;#8220;) Now that I use &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm" title=""&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; whenever I want streaming music, I don&amp;#8217;t really need this app. Moderate regret.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.techspansion.com/" title=""&gt;Visual Hub&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;used it a few times, but then the app got discontinued and open-sourced. I recall buying this right before a trip, desperate to find an easy way to convert some movies to an iPhone-friendly format. It wasn&amp;#8217;t worth it, and I regret not using open source tools for this specialized task. Deep regret.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.xtorrentp2p.com/" title=""&gt;Xtorrent Pro&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;integrated search and feed subscriptions are killer features for a BitTorrent client. My need for Xtorrent was obviated by &lt;a href="http://www.hulu.com" title=""&gt;Hulu&lt;/a&gt;, though, which carries all the shows that used to, uh, magically appear on my hard drive. Slight regret, but probably worthwhile.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;iPhone Apps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.pangeasoft.net/iphone/enigmo/info.html" title=""&gt;Enigmo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;deep regret. I bought it when it was $9.99 without remembering that I don&amp;#8217;t actually enjoy playing games. Beat a few levels, deleted it.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sketchesapp.com/" title=""&gt;Sketches&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;I can&amp;#8217;t draw on paper, much less on a touch screen, and I&amp;#8217;ve never had the desire to do so since the day I bought Sketches. Moderate regret. I keep it on my iPhone in case the need/desire to sketch arises anew.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spore_Origins" title=""&gt;Spore Origins&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;same story as Enigmo. I was eagerly awaiting Spore, because I thought it was the sort of game I might enjoy, and bought this tedious thing instead. Deep regret.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.mustacheinc.com/summizer" title=""&gt;Summizer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;a great app, but most of its functionality can now be found in &lt;a href="http://www.atebits.com/software/tweetie/" title=""&gt;Tweetie&lt;/a&gt;. Moderate regret, but I&amp;#8217;d have none if it had been cheaper.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://iconfactory.com/home/permalink/2009" title=""&gt;Twitterrific&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8212;pretty the same deal as Summizer. Twitterrific has a much stronger design sensibility than Tweetie, but Tweetie does more and does it faster. No regret, though, as I used it happily for months.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;The Morals&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;	&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t buy games (if you&amp;#8216;re me).&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t buy file sharing apps.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t buy apps for things you only need to do once in a blue moon. Find a free/open solution.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t buy iPhone apps on impulse.&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;Expect that software you buy to integrate with a particular piece of hardware probably won&amp;#8217;t have a long life, so budget accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/494452907" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Life As A Series of Queues</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/22/life-as-queues.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-22:2008/12/22/life-as-queues.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-22T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A downside of many information architectures is the reduction of data to items in queues that must be manually processed. Though information technology has saved the &amp;#8220;knowledge work&amp;#8221; generations from a lifetime of manual labor, we have our own assembly lines.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Here are the queues I process in a given work day:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;	&lt;li&gt;work email (by far the most insidious queue)&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;personal email&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;instant messages (they queue while in meetings and away from the computer)&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;text messages&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;missed phone calls and voicemail&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://help.twitter.com/index.php?pg=kb.page&amp;#38;id=70" title=""&gt;@replies&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;direct messages on Twitter&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;requests for links to applications by Twitter API developers&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;requests for whitelisting by Twitter developers&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;code review requests&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;tickets on our internal bug tracker&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;tickets on the &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/twitter-api/issues/list" title=""&gt;Twitter API tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;items in my personal to-do list&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;calendar event requests&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;unread items in my feed reader&lt;/li&gt;	&lt;li&gt;unread items in &lt;a href="http://www.instapaper.com" title=""&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;	&lt;p&gt;My suspicion is that there&amp;#8217;s a market in making each and every one of those queues smaller, if not making them disappear entirely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/492731564" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Recession Engineering</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/04/recession-engineering.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-04:2008/12/04/recession-engineering.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-04T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It seems like everyone&amp;#8217;s taking guesses as to how the &lt;a href="http://money.cnn.com/2008/12/01/news/economy/recession/?postversion=2008120115" title=""&gt;recession&lt;/a&gt; will impact their little corner of the world. This is my guess.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://thisisindexed.com/2008/12/might-as-well-own-this-meltdown/"&gt;&lt;img src ="http://thisisindexed.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/card1945-380x230.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The trend in engineering and architecture during the &lt;a href="http://www.businessweek.com/the_thread/techbeat/archives/2008/10/is_that_the_sou.html" title=""&gt;now-bursting&lt;/a&gt; Web 2.0 bubble has been one of precious little &lt;em&gt;engineering&lt;/em&gt; at all. It&amp;#8217;s become the common wisdom to ship first and scale later, and Hoare&amp;#8217;s old &lt;a href="http://www.acm.org/ubiquity/views/v7i24_fallacy.html" title=""&gt;chestnut&lt;/a&gt; of &amp;#8220;premature optimization is the root of all evil&amp;#8221; is a favorite flippant dismissal of any suggestion to the contrary.  Technologies that enable a fill-in-the-blanks approach to rapid development at the expense of performance have become the default choice for new companies in this environment. It&amp;#8217;s taken for granted that &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing" title=""&gt;The Cloud&lt;/a&gt; will solve scalability issues because, of course, why optimize when you can just fire up more servers to run your sluggish code? Or, when you get popular, rewrite, and never mind the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second-system_effect" title=""&gt;second-system effect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The difference between investor-responsible, cost-driven development and put-the-prototype-in-production hackery can be serious money.  In a recession economy, my hunch is that this haphazard latter approach to engineering is going to be one of the first things to go.   What&amp;#8217;s different, now, is that there needn&amp;#8217;t be a tradeoff between performance and expressiveness, or between reliability and developer satisfaction. The tools have improved over the last several years as more organizations have faced scaling challenges, and tools matter.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m first to admit that I have something of an agenda with this prediction. I spend a fair bit of my time working with and writing about the &lt;a href="http://scala-lang.org" title=""&gt;Scala programming language&lt;/a&gt;, which provides the expressiveness and flexibility of dynamic and functional languages like Ruby, Python, and Lisp with the performance of C++ or Java.  But Scala is just one of a number of tools that can be applied to do engineering right on a budget without being miserable. The open source community has become rich with &lt;a href="http://www.opensourcetesting.org/performance.php" title=""&gt;performance testing tools&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_unit_testing_frameworks" title=""&gt;libraries to aid test-driven development&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.r-project.org/" title=""&gt;powerful statistics suites&lt;/a&gt;, and much more. Even &lt;a href="http://www.metabrew.com/article/a-million-user-comet-application-with-mochiweb-part-2/" title=""&gt;sharing optimization stories&lt;/a&gt; goes a long way towards encouraging the type of performance- and correctness-oriented engineering that&amp;#8217;s going to succeed in a tight market.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I think this recession is an opportunity for a minor &lt;a href="http://www.catonmat.net/blog/edsger-dijkstra-discipline-in-thought/" title=""&gt;Dijkstrian&lt;/a&gt; renaissance in the values of the tech community, and particularly the web application development community. It&amp;#8217;s important to remember that software engineering is a &lt;em&gt;practice&lt;/em&gt;, like medicine or law, and that as engineers it&amp;#8217;s our responsibility to make the right choices on behalf of our stakeholders. My hope is that other developers survey the landscape of tools and approaches and choose those that best fit the current economic constraints.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/475196508" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>How I Use TextMate</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/03/how-i-use-textmate.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-03:2008/12/03/how-i-use-textmate.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-03T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having &lt;a href="http://al3x.net/2008/10/22/on-flight-to-old-text-editors.html" title=""&gt;explored other text editors&lt;/a&gt; and remained unsatisfied, I&amp;#8217;ve committed to using &lt;a href="http://www.macromates.com" title=""&gt;TextMate&lt;/a&gt; for the foreseeable future. My only hesitation was that TextMate was getting to be practically (although hyperbolically) &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abandonware" title=""&gt;abandonware&lt;/a&gt;. Thankfully, this fear was assuaged by a recent update over the Thanksgiving holiday. It lives!&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;I keep an eye on the &lt;a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=textmate" title=""&gt;discussion about TextMate on Twitter Search&lt;/a&gt; to see how people use it; it always pays to learn about one&amp;#8217;s tools. Daily, I see complaints from new and seasoned TextMate users alike that are easily addressed. To that end, I&amp;#8217;d like to share the add-ons I use that keep TextMate and I on friendly terms.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://ciaranwal.sh/category/textmate" title=""&gt;ProjectPlus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;This plug-in for TextMate transforms its homely, outdated project drawer into a stylish, Leopard-style panel. ProjectPlus then imbues this new drawer with &lt;em&gt;powers&lt;/em&gt;: carrying over color labels from the Finder, preserving the state of the project tree between openings, QuickLook previews, sorting options, overlaying files with their version control status, and more.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;This plugin alone spruces TextMate up enough that you won&amp;#8217;t be pining away for the next major release. But read on!&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://svn.textmate.org/trunk/Review/Bundles/GetBundles.tmbundle/" title=""&gt;GetBundles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;No, not old, inscrutable GetBundle. GetBundles, plural, is the more modern way to get new bundles for TextMate.  Bundles are tidy packages of code and resources that let TextMate work with additional languages and file types, or add features. If you&amp;#8217;ve ever wondered &amp;#8220;does TextMate support &lt;em&gt;Foo&lt;/em&gt;?&amp;#8220;, chances are good that there&amp;#8217;s at least a bundle in development for it.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;GetBundles is totally sweet. It goes out and checks not just the official TextMate bundle repositories but &lt;a href="http://github.com" title=""&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; as well. Once it&amp;#8217;s got an authoritative list of all the bundles out there, it lets you install them with a click. You don&amp;#8217;t even need to restart TextMate to make use of newly installed bundles. GetBundles is how you should get bundles.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;To install, make sure you have &lt;a href="http://subversion.tigris.org/" title=""&gt;Subversion&lt;/a&gt; (you do unless you&amp;#8217;ve done something dreadful to your Mac), then fire these commands off from Terminal:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;pre&gt;  cd ~/Library/Application\ Support/TextMate/Bundles  svn co http://svn.textmate.org/trunk/Review/Bundles/GetBundles.tmbundle/  &lt;/pre&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Head back to TextMate and click &lt;em&gt;Bundles / Bundle Editor / Reload Bundles&lt;/em&gt;. Then click &lt;em&gt;Bundles / GetBundles / Get Bundles&lt;/em&gt; and you&amp;#8216;re off the races. The, uh, bundle races.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://github.com/protocool/ack-tmbundle/tree/master" title=""&gt;Ack In Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;One of the frequent complaints I see on Twitter about TextMate is that its Find In Project feature is slow. And, well, it is. That&amp;#8217;s why there&amp;#8217;s Ack In Project, which uses the speedy &lt;a href="http://petdance.com/ack/" title=""&gt;ack&lt;/a&gt; tool to search your code ASAP. What&amp;#8217;s more, you get beautiful, clickable results that appear as the search progresses. With Ack In Project overriding the keyboard shortcut for Find In Project, there&amp;#8217;s no more need to complain about TextMate not keeping up with your searches. Install it right now&amp;#8212;via GetBundles, of course.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8216;re working in a language that ack doesn&amp;#8217;t support out of the box, be sure to toggle the &amp;#8220;Advanced options&amp;#8221; panel of Ack In Project and check the &amp;#8220;Load defaults from .ackrc&amp;#8221; box. In your home directory, create a &lt;code&gt;.ackrc&lt;/code&gt; file that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;pre&gt; --sort-files --color --context=1 --follow --group --all &lt;/pre&gt;	&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;ll give you some handy defaults, and the &lt;code&gt;--all&lt;/code&gt; option will ensure that your searches are comprehensive, even for files with weird extensions like &lt;code&gt;.scala&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;These three additions are my TextMate secret sauce. Depending on your particular needs, you might also get serious mileage out of the Git bundle and the Copy As RTF bundle, which is great for popping syntax-highlighted code into Keynote presentations.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Generally, get in the habit of periodically pulling up GetBundles and seeing if there are new ways that TextMate can help you out with the languages and tools you work with. Once you&amp;#8217;ve installed new bundles, explore what they can do either via their Help command or by browsing their contents in the Bundle Editor.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Since I stopped fussing about with trying to make aging editors as smart as TextMate, I&amp;#8217;ve been productive and satisfied. Hopefully, with these tips, you&amp;#8217;ll be too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/474159466" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Alternatives to FileVault</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/02/alternatives-to-filevault.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-02:2008/12/02/alternatives-to-filevault.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-02T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s good to be secure, or at the very least, to make it as difficult as possible for someone to compromise your security.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;#8217;s FileVault disk encryption technology exists to solve a straightforward security problem: your machine is stolen or accessed without your permission and you don&amp;#8217;t want your files exposed. By encrypting your home directory, FileVault makes it difficult (although &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FileVault#Criticism" title=""&gt;not impossible&lt;/a&gt;) to access your private files.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;But FileVault has issues.  There plentiful anecdotal reports of decreased performance, general system instability, lost preferences, and so forth. I&amp;#8217;ve experienced as much myself, with the additional fun of lost Spotlight indexes, which screws up Spotlight-dependent applications like &lt;a href="http://www.yepthat.com/yep/index.html" title=""&gt;Yep&lt;/a&gt;. Backup is also complicated by FileVault. A run of ol&amp;#8217; reliable &lt;a href="http://www.shirt-pocket.com/SuperDuper/SuperDuperDescription.html" title=""&gt;SuperDuper&lt;/a&gt; after enabling FileVault failed for the first time since ever.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Beyond bugs, FileVault&amp;#8217;s strategy to disk encryption sits oddly in the middle between two more standard approaches. One school of thought suggests encrypting one&amp;#8217;s entire disk; the other suggests that only sensitive files need to be encrypted, saving precious cycles. FileVault, encrypting one&amp;#8217;s home directory as it does, ends up encrypting both sensitive files and generic support files, but not all of the system caches and cobwebbed corners of one&amp;#8217;s disk.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Taking these peculiarities into account, it&amp;#8217;s clear that an alternative to FileVault would be nice.  But what to use? I asked on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com" title=""&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, and here&amp;#8217;s what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;Whole-Disk Encryption&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The most thorough approach to securing one&amp;#8217;s files is to secure &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of one&amp;#8217;s files. The most-recommended solution in this category was &lt;a href="http://www.pgp.com/products/wholediskencryption/" title=""&gt;PGP Whole Disk Encryption&lt;/a&gt;, which provides pre-boot password protection in addition to encrypting arbitrary disks. One review reports that PGP WDE &lt;a href="http://echeng.com/journal/2008/10/01/pgp-whole-disk-encryption-for-mac-benchmarks/" title=""&gt;drastically impacts performance&lt;/a&gt; and provides numbers, while another &lt;a href="http://paulstamatiou.com/2008/09/06/review-pgp-whole-disk-encryption-for-mac-os-x" title=""&gt;casually says it does not&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m inclined to believe the review with numbers.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;#8217;s possible to use &lt;a href="http://www.truecrypt.org/" title=""&gt;TrueCrypt&lt;/a&gt; to encrypt an entire disk on other operating systems, the open source encryption suite doesn&amp;#8217;t cover the Mac in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;File &amp;#38; Directory Encryption&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Any Mac running OS X has a built-in, free solution to encrypting specific files or directories. The Disk Utility application can be used to create password-protected encrypted disk images. Move your files onto such an image, securely delete the originals, and you&amp;#8216;re done. Unfortunately, mounting and un-mounting your collection of disk images will quickly become a hassle.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;To lubricate the use of encrypted disk images, there&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://knoxformac.com/" title=""&gt;Knox&lt;/a&gt;. Knox keeps track of your &amp;#8220;vaults&amp;#8221; (still Apple standard disk images under the sharp suitcase icon), and will automatically mount them and back them up on a schedule. It&amp;#8217;s essentially a very polished wrapper around what Apple already provides, but it came highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The other tempting option for encrypting just a few files is Espionage, which looks to be part of the so-called &amp;#8220;Delicious Generation&amp;#8221; of high-gloss single-purpose apps. Unfortunately, &lt;a href="http://theappleblog.com/2008/10/31/espionage-brings-folder-encryption-to-os-x/" title=""&gt;this detailed review&lt;/a&gt; suggests that Espionage is more style than substance, as there&amp;#8217;s a number of scenarios in which the protection it provides is rendered moot.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;#8217;s a zillion other &amp;#8220;secret folder&amp;#8221; shareware apps out there, but I&amp;#8217;m just attending to what was recommended to me. Again, TrueCrypt is an option, but reviews suggest that its interface needs a lot of work to compete with other Mac solutions. I always prefer to use something purpose-built for my operating system when possible.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;What I Picked&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Needing only to secure work-related files and a small selection of personal files, I decided to give Knox a try. I&amp;#8217;ve created a vault for each of those needs, securely deleted the old content from my drive, and set Knox to keep two daily backups of each vault around. Setup was easy and painless, and I&amp;#8217;ve found the briefcase icon in my menu bar comforting throughout the work day.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;The only issue I&amp;#8217;ve run into was Knox claiming that the vaults were in use when it came time to run the backup; I closed all applications and the complaint remained, puzzlingly. I manually un-mounted the vaults and ran the backup, which worked just fine.  If this bug comes up again, I&amp;#8217;ll investigate with under-the-hood tools, but it&amp;#8217;s fairly minor.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;An advantage of using Knox is that I can continue to back up with SuperDuper, which simply treats the Knox vaults as big files and carries on. I&amp;#8217;m going to give it my requisite two week minimal trial, but I think Knox will be getting my $30 before long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/472879356" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Emerging Programming Languages</title>
      <link href="http://al3x.net/2008/12/01/emerging-programming-languages.html" rel="alternate" />
      <id>tag:al3x.net,2008-12-01:2008/12/01/emerging-programming-languages.html</id>
      <updated>2008-12-01T5:40:14-05:00</updated>
      <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was originally an email to a private mailing list, but it seemed like it would be of interest to regular readers. Below are several interesting languages that have popped up on my radar.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://kenai.com/projects/ioke/" title=""&gt;Ioke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;An experimental language by Ola Bini, one of the principal committers to the JRuby Java Virtual Machine (JVM) port of Ruby. Ioke borrows heavily from Steve Dekorte&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://iolanguage.com" title=""&gt;Io&lt;/a&gt;, as one might guess from the name. The author&amp;#8217;s goal seems to be an exploration of syntax and abstractions for high-level programming; performance is not a priority, according to his &lt;a href="http://olabini.com/blog/tag/ioke/" title=""&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; on the language.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.impredicative.com/ur/" title=""&gt;Ur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;[M]eant to be the ultimate host for embedded domain-specific languages&amp;#8221; according to author &lt;a href="http://adam.chlipala.net/" title=""&gt;Adam Chlipala&lt;/a&gt;, a PhD in CompSci from Berkeley and a big fan of strict, provably correct, strongly-typed languages. Ur is a pure functional language in that vein, and it appears to be the technical foundation of a startup that the author is involved in. Examples suggest that Ur allows for XML literals, as the &lt;a href="http://scala-language.org" title=""&gt;Scala language&lt;/a&gt; does. The feeling of the language seems closer to Ocaml than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://prog.vub.ac.be/amop/at/introduction" title=""&gt;AmbientTalk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;[A] distributed programming language developed specifically for writing programs to be deployed on mobile ad hoc networks&amp;#8220;. If you can get past the buzzwords, you&amp;#8217;ll find that AmbientTalk is a research language built on the JVM. The language is dynamic, prototype-based, and uses an Actor model to manage concurrency &amp;#8211; so, very much like Io. Despite reading up on the language, it remains unclear to me what benefits it offers for network programming that aren&amp;#8217;t available in Io, Scala, and other Actor-centric languages.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="http://cobra-language.com/" title=""&gt;Cobra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Quite a nice if unambitious object-oriented language with baked-in support for software contracts (remember those?). It supports both static and dynamic binding, like Objective-C, and is built on .NET (and so runs on Mono as well). With a bit of love, Cobra could be a superb general-purpose language for the .NET environment. Its clean, practically punctuation-free syntax is reminiscent of Python.&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;p&gt;Hope at least one of those sparks the interest of the other language geeks out there. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/al3x/~4/471881228" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</content>
      <author>
        <name>Alex Payne</name>
        <uri>http://al3x.net/about.html</uri>
      </author>
    </entry>
  </feed>
