<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl" type="text/xsl" media="screen"?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css" type="text/css" media="screen"?><!-- generator="wordpress/1.5.2" --><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Blogniscient Blog</title>
	<link>http://blog.blogniscient.com</link>
	<description>The bird's eye view to the Blogosphere</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 14:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=1.5.2</generator>
	<language>en</language>

		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/blogniscient" type="application/rss+xml" /><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site, subject to copyright and fair use.</feedburner:browserFriendly><item>
		<title>test</title>
		<link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/blogniscient/~3/80838817/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2007/01/24/test/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 15:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Administrator</dc:creator>
		
	<category>Uncategorized</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.blogniscient.com/2007/01/24/test/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[	



]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[	<p><object classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://fpdownload.macromedia.com/get/flashplayer/current/swflash.cab" width="100%" height="400px"><br />
<param name=movie value="http://www.toptensources.com/forum/client/topten.swf" />
<param name=quality value="high" />
<param name=flashVars value="forum=tts.american-idol-news&#038;root=3680" /><embed src="http://www.toptensources.com/forum/client/topten.swf" quality=high pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="100%" height="400px" flashVars="forum=tts.american-idol-news&#038;root=3680" ></embed></object></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2007/01/24/test/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2007/01/24/test/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Blogniscient Launches Television Category</title>
		<link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/blogniscient/~3/76607135/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/12/18/blogniscient-launches-television-category/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2005 17:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Administrator</dc:creator>
		
	<category>Uncategorized</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/12/18/blogniscient-launches-television-category/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[	Blogniscient is proud to announce the launch of its new Television Category within Entertainment.  Whether you are interested in finding out what people are saying about this week&#8217;s controversial Apprentice finale or catching up on the Lost episode that you missed, Blogniscient&#8217;s Television section will provide the most up to date information from the [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[	<p>Blogniscient is proud to announce the launch of its new <a href="http://entertainment.blogniscient.com/index.html#tv">Television Category</a> within <a href="http://entertainment.blogniscient.com">Entertainment</a>.  Whether you are interested in finding out what people are saying about this week&#8217;s controversial Apprentice finale or catching up on the Lost episode that you missed, Blogniscient&#8217;s Television section will provide the most up to date information from the world of TV.  This represents an addition to Blogniscient&#8217;s coverage of <a href="http://entertainment.blogniscient.com/index.html#gossip">Celebrity Gossip</a> and <a href="http://entertainment.blogniscient.com/index.html#music">Music</a> within the Entertainment space.  </p>
	<p>Over the coming weeks and months, Blogniscient intends to continue adding new categories to expand our coverage of the Blogosphere (see <a href="http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/10/30/a-vision-for-blogniscient/">A Vision for Blogniscient</a>).  Some of the categories we are planning on adding in the near future include:</p>
	<p>US Politics - Moderate Politics</p>
	<p>Technology - Gadgets</p>
	<p>Sports - Basketball</p>
	<p>Entertainment - Movies</p>
	<p>Business - Law</p>
	<p>By continuing to expand our offerings to different blogging communities, we hope we can achieve our goal of becoming your portal to the Blogosphere.
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/12/18/blogniscient-launches-television-category/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/12/18/blogniscient-launches-television-category/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>A Brief History of Blogniscient (Part I)</title>
		<link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/blogniscient/~3/76607136/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/12/a-brief-history-of-blogniscient-part-i/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2005 21:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Administrator</dc:creator>
		
	<category>Uncategorized</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/12/a-brief-history-of-blogniscient-part-i/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Okay, I'll admit it.  Up until about a year and a half ago, I had never read a blog.  Now, I am a reasonably early adopter of technology.  I did my first Linux install in 1995 and I had a 5 digit ICQ number.  That being said, I didn't stumble upon the world of blogs until the 2004 Presidential election started heating up. ]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[	<p>This past week, I presented about Blogniscient at the <a href="http://www.seedwiki.com/wiki/bostonweb/">Boston Web Innovators Meetup</a> sponsored by David Beisel (of <a href="http://www.mvpartners.com/">Masthead Venture Partners</a> and <a href="http://www.genuinevc.com">Genuine VC</a> blog).  It was a great event attend by 50-60 people including entrepreneurs, investors, and students.  Three early-stage startups, <a href="http://www.reddit.com">reddit</a>, <a href="http://www.kiko.com">Kiko</a>, and <a href="http://www.blogniscient.com">Blogniscient</a> presented.  David&#8217;s follow-up post on the Meetup can be found <a href="http://www.genuinevc.com/archives/2005/11/boston_web_inno_2.htm">here</a>.</p>
	<p>After the brief presentations we all mingled and networked to our heart&#8217;s content.  Being one of the presenters, people asked me quite a few questions about Blogniscient.  One of the questions that kept coming up was, &#8220;How did you come up with the idea for Blogniscient?&#8221;  As this was a topic so many people asked me about, I thought I would capture my answer here as well to preserve it for posterity.</p>
	<p>Okay, I&#8217;ll admit it.  Up until about a year and a half ago, I had never read a blog.  Now, I am a reasonably early adopter of technology.  I did my first Linux install in 1995 and I had a 5 digit ICQ number.  That being said, I didn&#8217;t stumble upon the world of blogs until the 2004 Presidential election started heating up.  I followed a link here or there and ended up on a political blog that analyzed the statistics of all the polling that was taking place to draw more certain conclusions.  To me, this was amazing because it was information that I could not get any other place I knew of.  As I wandered further and further through the Blogosphere, I kept accumulating blogs that I liked&#8230;like picking up little pieces of gold and putting them in my knapsack.</p>
	<p>Well, eventually my knapsack got a little too heavy.  I found myself with 50 or so blogs that I really enjoyed keeping up with, but it was just too much.  I tried <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS_%28file_format%29">RSS</a> and thought I had found the answer.  Instead I found that I was still sifting through all of the same information, this time it just happened to be all in the same place (my RSS reader).   At the same time I was being overloaded with information from blogs, I was still telling all of my friends and family how wonderful blogs are.  My friends indulged me patiently (not an unusual occurence) while I extoled the benefits of blogs, but they didn&#8217;t really seem to get it.  </p>
	<p>So now I had two problems.  I was trying to drink from the Blogosphere firehose  and I was quickly losing my technical &#8220;early adopter&#8221; credibility with my friends.  At this point, I began thinking about how I could create a service that would simplify my life as a begining/intermediate blog reader as well as showing others the significant value of blogs.  Based on the problem, I conceived of a website that would take into account all of the blogs I read regularly (and many more) yet only show me the blog posts which were most relevant.  This would allow me to get my information much more efficiently as well as distilling the Blogosphere firehose to a water fountain that my friends (non-blog readers) could drink from.</p>
	<p>Thus the idea for Blogniscient was born.  (More to come)
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/12/a-brief-history-of-blogniscient-part-i/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/12/a-brief-history-of-blogniscient-part-i/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>What’s Next?   Personalized Categories!</title>
		<link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/blogniscient/~3/76724004/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/02/whats-next-personalized-categories/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2005 07:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Administrator</dc:creator>
		
	<category>Uncategorized</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/02/whats-next-personalized-categories/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[	In my last post, I outlined Blogniscient&#8217;s vision for having a large taxonomy of blog categories to help organize the information available within the Blogosphere.  This works well for high level categories like politics and even lower level areas like specific baseball teams.  If people want to browse their way through the Blogosphere, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[	<p>In my <a href="http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/10/30/a-vision-for-blogniscient/">last post</a>, I outlined Blogniscient&#8217;s vision for having a large taxonomy of blog categories to help organize the information available within the Blogosphere.  This works well for high level categories like politics and even lower level areas like specific baseball teams.  If people want to browse their way through the Blogosphere, this is a very effective organization strategy.</p>
	<p>However, what if I am interested in an even smaller niche than what the categories cover?  This is where customization comes in&#8230;allowing people to create their own personalized Blogniscient categories.  Let&#8217;s look at an example of how this would work.  </p>
	<p>Let&#8217;s say that while someone only moderately enjoys reading <a href="http://entertainment.blogniscient.com">Celebrity Gossip</a>, they are particularly interested in stories about Paris Hilton.  They would be able to create their own Paris Hilton category on Blogniscient, complete with RSS feed.  Blogniscient will then apply its Article Ranking System to provide the reader the top stories about Paris Hilton in their customized category.  Let&#8217;s face it though, there maybe alot of posts about Paris.  As a result, the personalized category also must have a sensitivity setting.  Does the person want to see most posts that come through about Paris, or do they only want to see the stories that are really important&#8230;it&#8217;s their choice.  Also, as Paris Hilton may be their guilty pleasure that they don&#8217;t want others knowing about, the person creating the category would have the option of keeping their Paris Hilton category private or sharing with the rest of the world.  </p>
	<p>By having both the pre-defined taxonomy along with the ability to create personalized Blogniscient categories, users will be able to access the top information from the Blogosphere to best meet their needs.   </p>
	<p>I would very much like to get feedback from Blogniscient users about this capability as described above.  Is this functionality something that you would find useful?  In the next couple months, would you rather see more categories or the personalized category functionality?   Now for the hard question&#8230;.think about your friends or family who don&#8217;t currently read blogs on a regular basis.  If they were to come upon Blogniscient, do you think they would rather see a broader range of categories or the ability to create personalized categories?  If you have a spare minute, please email me at:   ben.ruedlinger -at- blogniscient -dot- com and let me know what you think.  We want to know!
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/02/whats-next-personalized-categories/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/11/02/whats-next-personalized-categories/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>A Vision for Blogniscient</title>
		<link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/blogniscient/~3/76724005/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/10/30/a-vision-for-blogniscient/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2005 16:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Administrator</dc:creator>
		
	<category>Uncategorized</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/10/30/a-vision-for-blogniscient/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[	Vision is what helps others see where we are going before we get there.  It is also something which allows us to focus our efforts towards achieving a set of goals.  So what is our vision for Blogniscient?
	You can read the taglines.  
	“The bird’s eye view of the Blogosphere” 
	“Blogniscient…your portal to [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[	<p>Vision is what helps others see where we are going before we get there.  It is also something which allows us to focus our efforts towards achieving a set of goals.  So what is our vision for Blogniscient?</p>
	<p>You can read the taglines.  </p>
	<blockquote><p>“The bird’s eye view of the Blogosphere” </p></blockquote>
	<blockquote><p>“Blogniscient…your portal to the Blogosphere”  </p></blockquote>
	<p>I can even give you my 30 second elevator pitch about what Blogniscient is and its value proposition to users.  </p>
	<p>However, that doesn’t nearly capture the breadth and depth of what we plan on achieving.  This blog is a way for us to communicate our vision for Blogniscient to the larger community.  We don’t expect this to happen overnight through a single post.  Rather, we hope that our posts will create a dialogue between the people using Blogniscient and the people developing Blogniscient.  </p>
	<p>As the second tagline suggests, Blogniscient’s main goal is to become a portal to the Blogosphere for millions of users.  Ten years ago, only the technical elite were connected to the Internet.  If you had told people that within a decade, most Americans would have internet connections in their homes, they probably would have called you crazy.  How did this revolution happen?  Companies like AOL developed as service providers to making it easy to connect.  Companies like Yahoo! and Google made it easier to find information on the Web.  </p>
	<p>Blogniscient aims to be one of the companies that helps take blogs from being within the domain of the technical elite to being accessible by everyone.  Currently, many people don’t know how or where to find blogs on their favorite subject.  By categorizing and ranking blog information, Blogniscient provides a quick and easy way for people to access the top information on a particular topic.  Currently, Blogniscient has categories for some of the most prolific and mature blogging communities such as Conservative and Liberal Politics, Technology, and Entertainment (Celebrity Gossip and Music).  </p>
	<p>As we grow, we intend to keep expanding our list of categories to encompass more and more of the Blogosphere.  As an example, this weekend we launched our new Venture Capital category (under Business at <a href="http://business.blogniscient.com">business.blogniscient.com</a> ) and our new Poker category (under Sports at <a href="http://sports.blogniscient.com">sports.blogniscient.com</a> ).  Be proactive, let us know what categories you want to see next!  </p>
	<p>While categorization is an important part of making the relevant information accessible, the ranking of that vast quantity of information presents an even more challenging problem.  Blogniscient’s Article Ranking System (ARS) is responsible for distilling the enormous number of blog posts indexed everyday down to the most relevant 10 or 20 (ARS will be the topic of future posts here).</p>
	<p>By continuing to grow our taxonomy of blog categories and continuously improving the quality of our rankings, we strive to provide increasing value to our ever growing user community.  In addition, we hope that those who find our service useful will tell their friends, family, and coworkers as a way to illustrate the value of the Blogosphere.  Finally, we want to make sure that our users understand that their feedback (positive or negative) is highly valued and always taken into consideration.   Achieving these three things will bring us one step closer to realizing our vision for Blogniscient.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRSS>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/10/30/a-vision-for-blogniscient/feed/</wfw:commentRSS>
	<feedburner:origLink>http://blog.blogniscient.com/2005/10/30/a-vision-for-blogniscient/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
