<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bronte Media</title>
	<atom:link href="http://brontemedia.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://brontemedia.com</link>
	<description>There are those who experiment and those who follow the formula</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 01:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.5</generator>
	<language>en</language>
			<item>
		<title>Bonus Wrap: EBAY&#8217;s Quarter</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/bonus-wrap-ebays-quarter/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/bonus-wrap-ebays-quarter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 01:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=783</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In my quest to analyze all public companies who have significant online advertising revenues, I thought I would throw in a bonus - the venerable eBay.
eBay had a disappointing quarter (although I am sure we will redefine the meaning of disappointing in the next few months) with revenue in its marketplaces business down 16% year [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In my quest to <a href="http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/07/help/">analyze all public companies</a> who have significant online advertising revenues, I thought I would throw in a bonus - the venerable eBay.</p>
<p>eBay had <a href="http://idea.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1065088/000089161809000008/f51189exv99w1.htm">a disappointing quarter</a> (although I am sure we will redefine the meaning of disappointing in the next few months) with revenue in its marketplaces business down 16% year on year, driven by a meltdown in car sales. But what does all this mean for online advertising?</p>
<p>Well eBay is important for two reasons:</p>
<p>1) It is the largest buyer of online advertising and in particular search advertising on Google. The company buys both directly but also indirectly through its humongous affiliate program where thousands of laser sharp independent micro-businesses efficiently purchase and price keywords.</p>
<p>And the news is even worse on this front for Google and others. Sales and marketing revenue for the quarter, of which a large portion is online ad buying related, plummeted 17.5% from $507m in Q407 to $418m last quarter.</p>
<p>This suggests that the company (and its affiliate network) pulled back on spending driven by lower ROI because consumers are spending less (i.e. conversion rate went down). This shift suggests the ultimate in media buying efficiency and if I were an eBay investor I would be happy that they can control and react so quickly to the environment.</p>
<p>But that doesn&#8217;t help Google. I always hear the nails on the chalkboard when people say that search offers a great ROI because it&#8217;s measurable. This is a complete fallacy. In fact because it is measurable then the industry will always offer a very low ROI: over time marketers will bid up the value of keywords to their natural break even value. That&#8217;s great for Google&#8217;s bottom line but not for a marketer&#8217;s ROI (the two forces are absolutely and completely mutually exclusive).</p>
<p>2) eBay has a growing online ad business of its own, mainly consisting of classifieds business and shopping.com with various ad sundry in Skype and other businesses. </p>
<p>How did these do? Marketing services revenues were essentially flat year over year for their main market place (classifieds+shopping.com) going from $222m to $221m.</p>
<p>Flat revenue in this climate is likely to be a decent bellwether for what is to come. I expect the fourth quarter to be worse than the first simply because people freeze in the face of such a crippling event of what went on in October and there is some demand that is shifted to the coming quarters.</p>
<p>Conclusion: It&#8217;s not pretty but eBay managed to lower their online ad spend in line with the detoriation. That&#8217;s bad news for Google, whose biggest customer essentially shifted their spend down 17.5% year on year. eBay&#8217;s ad businesses had a ho-hum vanilla quarter, essentially flat year on year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/bonus-wrap-ebays-quarter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quote of the Day</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/quote-of-the-day-40/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/quote-of-the-day-40/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=782</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Comes from John Kay of the Financial Times [via Kedrosky]:
&#8220;The British government plans to provide insurance for new asset-backed securities. That is like helping a junkie to detox by guaranteeing drug supplies until the local dealer resumes normal service.&#8221;
]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Comes from <a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c08a764a-e70f-11dd-8407-0000779fd2ac.html">John Kay of the Financial Times</a> [<a href="http://paul.kedrosky.com/archives/2009/01/21/quote_du_jour_d_2.html">via Kedrosky</a>]:</p>
<p>&#8220;The British government plans to provide insurance for new asset-backed securities. That is like helping a junkie to detox by guaranteeing drug supplies until the local dealer resumes normal service.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/quote-of-the-day-40/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Schemer Age</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/schemer-age/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/schemer-age/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:07:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=781</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Random thought of the day: I wonder if there is a correlation between the number of years to retirement and ponzi scheme participation. Firstly  the latest in the line of ponzi schemes:
&#8220;Mr. Nadel, the 76-year-old head of a Sarasota fund management company, was reported missing by his family a week ago. Two days later, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Random thought of the day: I wonder if there is a correlation between the number of years to retirement and ponzi scheme participation. <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123256845289403387.html?mod=rss_whats_news_us_business">Firstly  the latest in the line of ponzi schemes</a>:</p>
<p>&#8220;Mr. Nadel, the 76-year-old head of a Sarasota fund management company, was reported missing by his family a week ago. Two days later, investors began complaining to police that possibly hundreds of millions of dollars were missing from funds he ran.&#8221;</p>
<p>Bernie Madoff, the king of them all, is currently 70 years old.</p>
<p>I wonder if it is simply a case of having a good enough reputation to be able to commit the fraud against which takes a lifetime to build or if there is an incentive to commit such frauds later in a working life since there is very little left of it anyway (both Madoff and Nadel were over the normal retirement age)?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/schemer-age/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Because it all worked out so well the first time around</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/because-it-all-worked-out-so-well-the-first-time-around/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/because-it-all-worked-out-so-well-the-first-time-around/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 22:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=780</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There will be plenty of lessons Richard might offer Citi on how to successfully let a company destruct, although a lot of the work probably has been done already. The WSJ:
&#8220;Citigroup named former Time Warner chief Richard Parsons as chairman, succeeding Win Bischoff, following calls for new leaders at the bank. &#8220;
]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There will be plenty of lessons Richard might offer Citi on how to successfully let a company destruct, although a lot of the work probably has been done already. <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123257451678903687.html?mod=rss_whats_news_technology">The WSJ</a>:</p>
<p>&#8220;Citigroup named former Time Warner chief Richard Parsons as chairman, succeeding Win Bischoff, following calls for new leaders at the bank. &#8220;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/21/because-it-all-worked-out-so-well-the-first-time-around/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Diaries of an AdWare Developer</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/19/diaries-of-an-adware-developer/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/19/diaries-of-an-adware-developer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 22:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=779</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fantastic interview with one of the core developers for the original Direct Revenue [hat tip to Andrew Chen].
Choice quote:
&#8220;That’s pretty cool that you kicked all the viruses off. Why don’t you kick the competitors off, too?”
It was funny. It really showed me the power of gradualism. It’s hard to get people to do something bad [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://philosecurity.org/2009/01/12/interview-with-an-adware-author">Fantastic interview</a> with one of the core developers for the original Direct Revenue [<a href="http://andrewchenblog.com/2009/01/19/twitter-links-for-jan-19-2009/">hat tip to Andrew Chen</a>].</p>
<p>Choice quote:</p>
<p>&#8220;That’s pretty cool that you kicked all the viruses off. Why don’t you kick the competitors off, too?”</p>
<p>It was funny. It really showed me the power of gradualism. It’s hard to get people to do something bad all in one big jump, but if you can cut it up into small enough pieces, you can get people to do almost anything.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/19/diaries-of-an-adware-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prospects for Macau Casinos</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/19/prospects-for-macau-casinos/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/19/prospects-for-macau-casinos/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 22:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=778</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I believe this is what they call a reduction in the addressable market:
&#8220;According to a study of 99 high rollers from mainland China whose gambling habits propelled them into the headlines, 44 per cent were either sentenced to death, murdered, committed suicide or were serving long jail sentences after committing crimes to fund their visits.&#8221;
]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://business.smh.com.au/business/dice-with-death-bad-news-for-packer-20090119-7ktm.html">I believe this is what they call a reduction in the addressable market</a>:</p>
<p>&#8220;According to a study of 99 high rollers from mainland China whose gambling habits propelled them into the headlines, 44 per cent were either sentenced to death, murdered, committed suicide or were serving long jail sentences after committing crimes to fund their visits.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/19/prospects-for-macau-casinos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Delicious Twist</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/15/delicious-twist/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/15/delicious-twist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 22:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=777</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I guess this is what they call &#8216;focusing on your core competency&#8217; and simplifying everything else:
&#8220;As investigators try to untangle the scheme that Bernard L. Madoff hid from investors and regulators for a decade or more, one basic fact is emerging: He may not have been making any trades at all.&#8221;
]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I guess this is <a href="http://www.ritholtz.com/blog/2009/01/madoff-never-traded/">what they call &#8216;focusing on your core competency&#8217;</a> and simplifying everything else:</p>
<p>&#8220;As investigators try to untangle the scheme that Bernard L. Madoff hid from investors and regulators for a decade or more, one basic fact is emerging: <strong>He may not have been making any trades at all</strong>.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/15/delicious-twist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wake Me Up When We Get There</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/13/wake-me-up-when-we-get-there/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/13/wake-me-up-when-we-get-there/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 21:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=776</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Probably why they hired Carol Bartz:
&#8220;A former Yahoo executive yesterday told us that inside the company, Carol is considered an ally to Yahoo president Sue Decker and Yahoo ad sales boss Hilary Schneider &#8212; a sign that both top executives may stay with the company under the new boss.&#8221;
To be honest I am not really [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.alleyinsider.com/2009/1/carol-bartz-to-become-yahoo-ceo">Probably why they hired Carol Bartz</a>:</p>
<p>&#8220;A former Yahoo executive yesterday told us that inside the company, Carol is considered an ally to Yahoo president Sue Decker and Yahoo ad sales boss Hilary Schneider &#8212; a sign that both top executives may stay with the company under the new boss.&#8221;</p>
<p>To be honest I am not really sure about who I could get excited about for the new hire. </p>
<p>My $0.02: Yahoo needed a passionate consumer web service person at the top to reinvigorate themselves. All the candidates I heard whom were vetted were either slap-on-the-back, smooth talking public company CEOs or young up and coming sales and monetization folks. Anyone from either of the two groups, in my humble and worthless opinion, are a mistake.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/13/wake-me-up-when-we-get-there/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Modern Movie Marketing</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/12/modern-movie-marketing/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/12/modern-movie-marketing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 07:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=775</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fantastic profile piece in this week&#8217;s New Yorker on modern Hollywood marketing set to the context of Tim Palen of Lionsgate trying to figure out a way to promote the movie &#8216;W&#8217;.
To be perfectly honest, the whole process was like watching goldfish swimming around the bowl and completely-scary-in-a-train-wreck-kind-of-way.
The strategy of buy more TV ads and [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2009/01/19/090119fa_fact_friend?currentPage=all">Fantastic profile piece</a> in this week&#8217;s New Yorker on modern Hollywood marketing set to the context of Tim Palen of Lionsgate trying to figure out a way to promote the movie &#8216;W&#8217;.</p>
<p>To be perfectly honest, the whole process was like watching goldfish swimming around the bowl and completely-scary-in-a-train-wreck-kind-of-way.</p>
<p>The strategy of buy more TV ads and re-frame it as like some movie in the past seems terribly overdone. Still a gripping article that you should read.</p>
<p><strong>Choice quotes:</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;Each maneuver and ad buy in Palen&#8217;s campaigns is detailed in a confidential playbook. For marketers, much of the science of marketing is determining which old movie your new movie is most like, so you can turn to that movie’s playbook as a rough guide.&#8221;<br />
<strong><br />
Competitive Advantage:</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;The big studios’ average marketing budget of thirty-six million dollars is one-third the total cost of making a film; Lionsgate’s average marketing budget is twenty-two million dollars, about two-thirds of the film’s total cost. In other words, Lionsgate is making much cheaper films that rely disproportionately on their marketing.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>The Morning After:</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;The trailer cutter David Schneiderman says. “We’re in the business of cheating, let’s face it. We fix voice-overs, create dialogue to clear up a story, use stock footage. We give pushup bras to flat-chested girls, take people’s eyes and put them where we want them. And sometimes it works.”</p>
<p><strong>The Result:</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;When the film wound up a close fourth for the weekend, at $10.5 million, he pronounced himself “relieved and a little depressed.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>On how the business has changed:</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;It’s the same meeting we were having five years ago, except now there’s a girl in a sweater who does the Internet.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/12/modern-movie-marketing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Help</title>
		<link>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/07/help/</link>
		<comments>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/07/help/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 04:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikiscevak</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brontemedia.com/?p=774</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Given that the fourth quarter of last year is likely to be the new normal in online advertising, I thought I would scour each and every publicly listed online advertising company&#8217;s fourth quarter earnings and 10-Q I can find. 
Here is my target list so far. Just let me know if I have missed any [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Given that the fourth quarter of last year is likely to be the new normal in online advertising, I thought I would scour each and every publicly listed online advertising company&#8217;s fourth quarter earnings and 10-Q I can find. </p>
<p>Here is my target list so far. Just let me know if I have missed any one by commenting. I&#8217;ll give each firm a post and opinion as they announce.</p>
<p><strong>Big 4</strong><br />
Google<br />
AOL<br />
Yahoo<br />
MSN</p>
<p><strong>Searchy/Local</strong><br />
IAC (Ask.com, Servicemagic)<br />
Marchex<br />
Web.com<br />
Local.com<br />
DarkBlueSea</p>
<p><strong>Vertical</strong><br />
Internet Brands<br />
Move<br />
NCI (real estate)<br />
Monster<br />
Housevalues/Market Leader<br />
Bankrate<br />
TheStreet</p>
<p><strong>Ad Networks</strong><br />
Valueclick</p>
<p>UPDATE: Added TheStreet thanks to Kwan, Valueclick thanks to Henrik and local.com/web.com/darkbluesea thanks to Sandy. Keep the suggestions coming.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brontemedia.com/2009/01/07/help/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
