<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Five Years Too late</title>
	<atom:link href="http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Two New York City VCs</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 17:09:54 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=MU</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<image>
		<url>http://www.gravatar.com/blavatar/184cd8590b904907fd44156bcb9ff8b3?s=96&#038;d=http://s.wordpress.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Five Years Too late</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
			<item>
		<title>Pitching 101: Say What You Do</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/13/pitching-101-say-what-you-do/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/13/pitching-101-say-what-you-do/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 15:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
I&#8217;ve been thinking about putting together a series of posts about pitching, not just to RRE, but in general. Some other bloggers, particularly my friend Mark Davis at DFJ Gotham Ventures, have done an admirable job of putting together well thought-out and structured guides that go through a lot of best practices around pitching, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=167&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><div id="attachment_45" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><img class="size-full wp-image-45" title="Eric Wiesen" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Eric Wiesen" width="60" height="64" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Eric Wiesen</p></div>
<p></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking about putting together a series of posts about pitching, not just to <a href="http://www.rre.com">RRE</a>, but in general. Some other bloggers, particularly my friend <a href="http://www.markpeterdavis.com">Mark Davis</a> at <a class="zem_slink" title="Draper Fisher Jurvetson" rel="homepage" href="http://www.dfj.com/">DFJ Gotham</a> Ventures, have done an admirable job of putting together well thought-out and structured guides that go through a lot of best practices around pitching, and I&#8217;m frankly not looking to recreate those efforts. Rather I occasionally see a poor practice repeated so frequently that I think it might be helpful to point out a few &#8220;hot spots&#8221; in pitching methodology that I think are important.</p>
<p>Today&#8217;s topic is one of the absolute most important: SAY. WHAT. YOUR. COMPANY. DOES. I am continually amazed by the number of PowerPoint decks, executive summaries and in-person pitches that don&#8217;t tell the investors being pitched what the company&#8217;s product or service does until halfway through. This is not the right approach. If you&#8217;re sending around a deck, the second slide should be a succinct description of what you want to do. In an executive summary it&#8217;s the first paragraph. If you&#8217;re pitching in person you should plan to tell investors what you&#8217;re doing shortly after introductions have been made and you have all sat down to &#8220;get down to business&#8221;. If you need a script, it&#8217;s something like this:</p>
<p>&#8220;Thanks for meeting with us. We&#8217;re [ScoobyDooCorp] and we&#8217;re [the first ad network for pet-related websites].&#8221;</p>
<p>Instead, the first half of the pitch is often one of three things:</p>
<ol>
<li>Long-form description/discussion of the management team&#8217;s accomplishments.</li>
<li>Lengthy discourse on the problem or pain point being addressed.</li>
<li>Treatise on the technology, how it works and why it&#8217;s superior.</li>
</ol>
<p>Don&#8217;t misunderstand me - every one of these is important and I want to hear them all. But if you tell me these things before you tell me what your company does, it makes it much harder for me to contextualize the value of these other parts of your presentation. This isn&#8217;t a &#8220;VC ADD.&#8221; issue. It&#8217;s not that we&#8217;re so impatient we can&#8217;t listen to a well-structured pitch. But it&#8217;s much more valuable to you as an entrepreneur if I&#8217;m hearing your accomplishments, the problem you&#8217;re solving or the virtues of your technology in the context of what you&#8217;re going to do after I fund you.</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><a class="zemanta-pixie-a" title="Zemified by Zemanta" href="http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/8289b797-f96b-4023-ba41-d770f3b5ab76/"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:medium none;float:right;" src="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=8289b797-f96b-4023-ba41-d770f3b5ab76" alt="Reblog this post [with Zemanta]" /></a></div>
Posted in Uncategorized&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=167&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/13/pitching-101-say-what-you-do/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Eric Wiesen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=8289b797-f96b-4023-ba41-d770f3b5ab76" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reblog this post [with Zemanta]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Mad Men Day&#8221; at RRE</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/09/mad-men-day-at-rre/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/09/mad-men-day-at-rre/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 19:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=162</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our esteemed Managing Partners declared today &#8220;Mad Men Day&#8221;, the anti-casual Friday!

Posted in Uncategorized&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;     <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=162&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><p>Our esteemed Managing Partners declared today &#8220;Mad Men Day&#8221;, the anti-casual Friday!</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-163" title="mad-men-1" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/mad-men-1.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" alt="mad-men-1" width="300" height="224" /><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-164" title="mad-men-2" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/mad-men-2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=209" alt="mad-men-2" width="300" height="209" /></p>
Posted in Uncategorized&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/162/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=162&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/09/mad-men-day-at-rre/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/mad-men-1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mad-men-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/mad-men-2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mad-men-2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Death of Venture Capital (again)</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/08/the-death-of-venture-capital-again/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/08/the-death-of-venture-capital-again/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 16:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=157</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In these last months, the drumbeat proclaiming the death of venture capital has grown louder, even becoming mainstream. Some of what&#8217;s appeared in the press sparked an interesting conversation amongst us about what all this means for venture capital as an asset class and for the entrepreneurs whose businesses are funded by venture capital. A [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=157&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><div id="attachment_44" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><img class="size-full wp-image-44" title="Stuart Ellman" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Stuart Ellman" width="60" height="64" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Stuart Ellman</p></div>
<div id="attachment_45" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><img class="size-full wp-image-45" title="Eric Wiesen" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Eric Wiesen" width="60" height="64" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Eric Wiesen</p></div>
<p>In these last months, the drumbeat proclaiming the death of venture capital has grown louder, even becoming mainstream. Some of what&#8217;s appeared in the press sparked an interesting conversation amongst us about what all this means for venture capital as an asset class and for the entrepreneurs whose businesses are funded by venture capital. A number of perspectives were shared within <a href="http://www.rre.com">RRE</a>, and we collectively agreed that our industry faces some real challenges ahead, and that we want to be as thoughtful as we can about how we as investors face them, so that we can advise our portfolio companies and friends.</p>
<p>One analytical method that has been applied by some is to simply note that Venture Capital as an asset class has not had great returns in the eight-year period since the <a class="zem_slink" title="Dot-com bubble" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot-com_bubble">dot-com crash</a>, then connect the dots toward a conclusion that an asset class with limited liquidity and sub-par returns is doomed. With this model we should expect capital outflows until the industry is essentially gone. This strikes us as a lazy way to think about a complex problem. Had you applied this same method to publicly-traded stocks in 1940 or 1980 you could easily conclude that equities was an asset class whose best days were behind it, and would have then missed two of the greatest bull markets in history. In a more contemporary context, we&#8217;re likely to see a moribund real estate market, but that doesn&#8217;t mean real estate as an asset class is dead either. Assuming that because something has performed poorly in the past it will continue to perform poorly in the future has rarely proven an effective method of prediction.</p>
<p>One way to more accurately explain the last eight years is with basic economics: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Business_cycle">what goes up must come down</a>. Returns for venture capital from 1995-2000 were so phenomenally good that the asset class attracted massive amounts of new capital, new players and lots of me-too activity. As in all such episodes throughout history, this influx caused previously good returns to become concomitantly bad. Since the party ended, the VC industry has been slowly unwinding its way out of this overpopulation, but as our colleague <a href="http://www.rre.com/Our_Team#James_D._Robinson_IV">Jim Robinson IV</a> noted in a recent <a href="http://www.thedeal.com/techconfidential/behind-the-money/blog/behind-the-money/qa-we-have-always-been-way-too.php">interview</a>, the long cycle time of a VC firm (often 10 years) makes this unwinding a slow process. But it has been happening consistently and inexorably since 2001. When the case against Venture Capital is made, it is often mentioned that there are &#8220;several thousand&#8221; venture capital firms, and that it&#8217;s simply too many firms for what was a relatively small industry during its most profitable periods. And that is ultimately true. But there aren&#8217;t anywhere near that many venture firms who are genuinely active. If you define active as those firms that have made an investment in the past 12 months, that number is more like 500 than 2500 (Thompson claimed 1700 in 2007 while the National Venture Capital Association is more judicious, calling it 800 in 2006). And let&#8217;s be realistic - it&#8217;s still trending down and will likely continue to do so for the next couple of years. By the time the full 10 years have passed since the last of the bubble-era funds were raised, the industry will once again be relatively small.</p>
<p>But ultimately all of this is simply Monday-morning quarterbacking. Yes, too many firms were formed during the late 1990&#8217;s and too much money was raised. Too many companies were funded without real business models or that couldn&#8217;t justify the valuations investors accepted. And the price is still being paid for that excess. But the argument that venture capital is dead in 2009 seems, in our view, to oversimplify and confuse the two major economic collapses of the nascent 21st century: 2001 and 2008.</p>
<p>2001 was all about technology. Our ecosystem ballooned and then popped. Duly noted. But 2008 has nothing to do with technology or venture capital directly. 2008 was a collapse of historic proportions, largely driven by misguided government policy, leverage and a real estate bubble that dwarfed anything we saw in 2000. These factors have little to do with venture capital (which typically is 100% equity and has no leverage) or the companies in which we invest (which also typically use little to no leverage). We aren&#8217;t real estate investors and we as an investor group didn&#8217;t buy toxic assets. So then the question becomes - will venture capital and the world of technology startups be collateral damage in this collapse? And of course the answer is: yes and no. There&#8217;s no question that the broader economy affects startups and VCs alike. These effects have been widely discussed &#8212; here and elsewhere &#8212; from the slowdown in consumer spending to cutbacks in big company budgets to the challenges of raising VC money and that VCs face with their limited partners.</p>
<p>Some will single out sectors as unusually troublesome (usually <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_2.0">advertising-driven web startups</a> or cleantech companies that have high <a class="zem_slink" title="Capital expenditure" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capital_expenditure">CapEx</a>). In these sectors there are going to be winners and losers just like everywhere else. And sure, some VCs will have a hard time raising their next fund as LPs shy away from all &#8220;<a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/a/alternativeassets.asp">alternative</a>&#8221; assets, resulting from a &#8220;<a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/09/22/why-venture-firms-tighten-the-purse-strings-in-a-down-market/">Denominator Effect</a>&#8221; or other rationales. But while it&#8217;s fun to put &#8220;the death of Silicon Valley&#8221; on the cover or to write a story about how the lack of a robust IPO market will be the end of Venture Capital, in the final analysis the basic rationale for venture capital is as sound now as it has ever been.</p>
<p>There are only a few ways to grow the economy: more inputs (natural resources, labor) or higher productivity (which introduces a multiplier to the foregoing). And higher productivity typically comes from innovation. Venture capital is in the business of funding companies who will go after opportunities that established players can&#8217;t or won&#8217;t pursue. And in this day and age this rationale is more important than ever. Will capital be harder to come by to fund these companies, on both the startup and VC sides? Probably. A bad economy with damaged financial markets will do that. Will some startups manage to fund themselves to a quick exit without raising any money? Sure. It&#8217;s definitely cheaper to build a company now than it was ten years ago. Is there an argument to be made that we&#8217;re in the middle of a slow-rise period of incremental, rather than disruptive innovation? I think there is. But based on what we&#8217;re seeing, there are a lot of interesting companies being started, and most of them can use both capital and guidance. Ultimately those are the two commodities venture capital provides.</p>
<p>We know this is a challenging time, and it&#8217;s going to continue to be. But as things get better, innovation, new technology and new ideas will be a big part of it. We believe venture capital continues to be an important ingredient, and there&#8217;s no obvious substitute.</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><a class="zemanta-pixie-a" title="Zemified by Zemanta" href="http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/e2b3b7a2-205f-49fa-898a-040aeb8c8334/"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:medium none;float:right;" src="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=e2b3b7a2-205f-49fa-898a-040aeb8c8334" alt="Reblog this post [with Zemanta]" /></a></div>
Posted in Uncategorized&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/157/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=157&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2009/01/08/the-death-of-venture-capital-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stuart Ellman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Eric Wiesen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=e2b3b7a2-205f-49fa-898a-040aeb8c8334" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reblog this post [with Zemanta]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Go to War with the Army You Have</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/12/12/go-to-war-with-the-army-you-have/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/12/12/go-to-war-with-the-army-you-have/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 16:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[betaworks]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Fundraising]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[RRE Ventures]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Series A round]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=152</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We recently had the opportunity to talk about the current funding environment with a bunch of smart people at a brown bag lunch hosted by our friends at Betaworks. A lot if important angles were discussed, including best practices for entrepreneurs, the mindset at different VC funds and tactical suggestions for getting a funding done [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=152&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><div id="attachment_44" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><img class="size-full wp-image-44" title="Stuart Ellman" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Stuart Ellman" width="60" height="64" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Stuart Ellman</p></div>
<div id="attachment_45" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><img class="size-full wp-image-45" title="Eric Wiesen" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Eric Wiesen" width="60" height="64" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Eric Wiesen</p></div>
<p>We recently had the opportunity to talk about the current funding environment with a bunch of smart people at a brown bag lunch hosted by our friends at <a href="http://www.betaworks.com">Betaworks</a>. A lot if important angles were discussed, including best practices for entrepreneurs, the mindset at different VC funds and tactical suggestions for getting a funding done in the current climate.</p>
<p>One point that&#8217;s worth stressing was raised by several people (including us): When you raise money, make sure you have investors who are prepared to continue to support you the next time around.</p>
<p>Backing up somewhat, let&#8217;s acknowledge that when times are good, fundraising usually follows a fairly standard pattern. An investor or group of investors funds a company at the Series A level for a given amount. When the company has reached sufficient proof points in the business and when new capital is needed, the company will raise an additional round of financing. A new investor usually leads this round, with participation (on a pro-rata basis) from the existing investors. The new investor is brought in for a number of reasons:</p>
<p>•	This investor may be more oriented toward a later stage of the business and can add additional value;<br />
•	New investor may bring needed capital for future rounds of funding; but most importantly<br />
•	A new investor can set the price for the company. Prior investors may have conflicts relating to the prices of prior rounds.</p>
<p>When a new investor can&#8217;t be found, then the current investors face the choice of whether or not to do an &#8220;inside round&#8221;, meaning fund the company themselves. The point today is that many if not most follow-on financings are being done as inside rounds right now. The new investor who comes in and prices the company and puts in fresh capital is, in many instances, very hard to find. They are either trying to figure out how they are going to fund their own portfolio companies (and doing inside rounds for them) or they are struggling to raise their new fund and aren&#8217;t making investments in new companies.</p>
<p>All of this rolls up to the original point: when you build your syndicate for your Series A round, make sure you have a group of investors who will continue to support you when you need to raise more money. It&#8217;s fine to have an investor involved whose charter is solely to make Series A investments and then participate pro-rata down the road, but you should ALSO have an investor who is comfortable making Series B investments. Because as a lot of startups raising Series B and Series C rounds are learning, new investors are very hard to come by right now.</p>
<p>At <a href="http://www.rre.com">RRE </a>we are currently looking at funding two very promising early-stage deals. In both cases we could easily (given the amount of capital being raised) take the entire round ourselves, but we aren&#8217;t just thinking about today. Both of these companies are likely to raise more money later on, so in both cases we are bringing in partners who can both add value to the company, and who we believe will help us ensure that the company continues to be funded should the current climate last longer.</p>
<p>They say you go to war with the army you have, and the same is true for your venture syndicate. If at all possible, bring in investors you think can go the distance with you. It can make a big difference.</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><a class="zemanta-pixie-a" title="Zemified by Zemanta" href="http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/22086a34-2eb8-4885-8ece-46fab8d0d336/"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:medium none;float:right;" src="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=22086a34-2eb8-4885-8ece-46fab8d0d336" alt="Reblog this post [with Zemanta]" /></a></div>
Posted in venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Tagged: betaworks, Fundraising, RRE Ventures, Series A round, venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/152/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=152&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/12/12/go-to-war-with-the-army-you-have/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stuart Ellman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Eric Wiesen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=22086a34-2eb8-4885-8ece-46fab8d0d336" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reblog this post [with Zemanta]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Deep is too Deep?</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/how-deep-is-too-deep/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/how-deep-is-too-deep/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 22:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[downturn]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Board of directors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=150</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now that the markets have tanked and pensions and endowments are selling off their private equity holdings to rebalance their portfolios, many people have gotten religion.  VCs realize that the environment for raising new private equity funds is not great.  If they are near the beginning of their new funds, as RRE happens [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=150&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><div id="attachment_44" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-44" title="Stuart Ellman" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Stuart Ellman" width="60" height="64" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Stuart Ellman</p></div>
<p>Now that the markets have tanked and pensions and endowments are selling off their private equity holdings to rebalance their portfolios, many people have gotten religion.  VCs realize that the environment for raising new private equity funds is not great.  If they are near the beginning of their new funds, as <a href="http://www.rre.com">RRE</a> happens to be, it is a very fortunate position because they have plenty of fresh cash to put into companies at attractive prices.  If they are near the end of their most recent fund, it is not a pretty time.  With little fresh capital to put in their existing companies, the first word out of their mouths is to cut costs at their existing portfolio companies.  This makes sense, but only up to a point.</p>
<p>For some of our portfolio companies, especially web 2.0 companies that exist &#8220;in the cloud&#8221;, it&#8217;s realistic to burn very little money and grow virally. But, this model simply doesn&#8217;t work for companies in other sectors and with other cost structures.  I sit on the board of a terrific company in an extremely attractive space.  Given the current environment, some of their large contracts have been pushed out.  With valuations down and the company on a path to burn through its cash, it seems obvious to cut the expenses and make the cash last as long as it can. This company will only remain the leader in its space if it continues to have engineers crank out the hardware and software that constitute its solution.  It will only be a winner if it participates in most of the beta tests, trials and <a class="zem_slink" title="Request for Proposal" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Request_for_Proposal">RFP</a>&#8217;s that most of its large customers are demanding.  It needs to partner with many of the Fortune 500 companies and support these relationships.  These things are not cheap.  But we can only create value for the company if these things are done.  The key is spending enough to remain on the &#8220;leading edge&#8221; without going overboard and hurting ourselves on the &#8220;bleeding edge&#8221;.</p>
<p>The takeaway here is that the <a class="zem_slink" title="Board of directors" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Board_of_directors">board of directors</a> (and each individual director) has to set aside the desires of their specific class of shares and do what is best for all shareholders.  If, for example, my fund is out of fresh capital to put in a company but the company needs to spend money to retain or create value, I must vote to dilute myself in order to be doing my duty as a director.  This is not obvious to all board members, but reflects that Director&#8217;s duty to the company. Directors must work to maximize value to all shareholders, unless the company is in distress and worth less than the amount of debt.  Then, the duty of a board changes and the directors must work for the benefit of the debt holders.  This is tough medicine, but we have all lived through this before in 2001-2003.  Things will turn around but we must all do the right things now to let these companies survive and flourish in the future.</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><a class="zemanta-pixie-a" title="Zemified by Zemanta" href="http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/be84710e-156b-4de1-a805-86011dc41e59/"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:medium none;float:right;" src="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=be84710e-156b-4de1-a805-86011dc41e59" alt="Reblog this post [with Zemanta]" /></a></div>
Posted in downturn, venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Tagged: Board of directors, downturn, venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=150&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/12/02/how-deep-is-too-deep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stuart Ellman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=be84710e-156b-4de1-a805-86011dc41e59" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reblog this post [with Zemanta]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fundamental vs. Technical VC Investing</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/22/fundamental-vs-technical-vc-investing/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/22/fundamental-vs-technical-vc-investing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 19:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=148</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Public market equity investors typically fall into one of two camps: Fundamental or Technical Analysis. Sure, many combine both, but most are essentially one or the other.
At a high level, fundamental investors look at the underlying business to determine how well it will perform. They look at margin expansion or contraction, performance of suppliers and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=148&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><div id="attachment_45" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-45" title="Eric Wiesen" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Eric Wiesen" width="60" height="64" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Eric Wiesen</p></div>
<p>Public market equity investors typically fall into one of two camps: <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/university/fundamentalanalysis/">Fundamental</a> or <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/university/technical/">Technical Analysis</a>. Sure, many combine both, but most are essentially one or the other.</p>
<p>At a high level, fundamental investors look at the underlying business to determine how well it will perform. They look at margin expansion or contraction, performance of suppliers and customers and new market opportunities. They meet with management and assess their ability to execute the company&#8217;s strategy.</p>
<p>Technical investors, by contrast, are much more focused on the movement of securities within the market, and have developed a whole science around price movement, volatility, volume, etc&#8230; They look at &#8220;<a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/support.asp">support levels</a>&#8221; and patterns in time series charts. They are essentially trying to quantify the psychology of the liquid market to predict what the mass of other investors are likely to do.</p>
<p>Put in a simple way, fundamental investors buy the business. Technical investors buy (or <a class="zem_slink" title="Short (finance)" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Short_%28finance%29">sell short</a>) the stock.</p>
<p>So what does this have to do with VC investing? There are no liquid markets, so everyone is a fundamental investor, right? I would argue no - that there is a type of thinking among VCs that is analogous to technical analysis, and that some measure of a VC&#8217;s decision-making process is usually contingent on this process.</p>
<p>The basic evaluation model here at <a href="http://www.rre.com">RRE</a> (and I suspect at most VC firms) is often described on this blog: Market/People/Technology. It&#8217;s relatively straightforward - is a given company led by great entrepreneurs, targeting a big opportunity in a defensible way? This is the fundamental analysis we perform, and it generally drives our yay or nay decision on companies we see. Is this (or is it likely to be) a good business? But once we&#8217;ve gotten comfort on these first-order questions, we then ask another set of questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Who are the company&#8217;s comparables, be they startups or public companies?</li>
<li>How do the markets value those companies?</li>
<li>What success stories can we find of companies taking a similar approach to the one we&#8217;re looking at?</li>
<li>Who are the likely buyers for this company? What multiple of revenues or <a class="zem_slink" title="Earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earnings_before_interest%2C_taxes%2C_depreciation_and_amortization">EBITDA</a> do those companies enjoy in the market? How acquisitive have they historically been?</li>
</ul>
<p>These aren&#8217;t questions about the business itself. They don&#8217;t speak to whether the company has good leadership, whether its customers will want its product or whether its business model makes sense. These are market attitude and structure questions. They poll, to the extent that we can, the psychology and appetite in the market for this type of company.</p>
<p>Ultimately, this is the technical analysis piece of VC investing, and often is a part of the pitch process that entrepreneurs don&#8217;t expect. While there aren&#8217;t <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/h/head-shoulders.asp">head-and-shoulders</a> or <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/cupandhandle.asp">cup-and-handle</a> charts, it&#8217;s the part of the evaluation that gets done more on the position of the company as a tradable asset rather than as an underlying business. How will it be valued, and when, and by whom?</p>
<p>The approach to this piece of the analysis varies from investor to investor. Some will ask the entrepreneur straight out, &#8220;<em>Who buys this business</em>?&#8221; to see how the she thinks about the exit opportunities. Others don&#8217;t consider this a part of the process, but will think about it internally. Personally, I like to have this dialog with founders, to see if they are thinking early on about the exit trajectory the business could take, even though we usually agree we&#8217;ll have very limited visibility at an early stage. It&#8217;s more process and attitude than anything else.</p>
<p>Ultimately, you can see evidence of firms who prioritize the technical piece more than others. When you see VC &#8220;momentum investing&#8221; in a sector - consistent funding of a dozen or more ad networks, for example, it is at least partially the result of investors looking at the market, seeing the big exits and robust valuations and wanting to make a bet in a market that&#8217;s clearly in favor.  This is the VC flavor of technical analysis.</p>
<p>Generally speaking, this element is something we do at RRE, but it&#8217;s second-order for us. To put it another way, we will not make a bet purely on momentum and analogous big outcomes, but it will help inform a decision about a business we like. If the fundamental analysis comes back strong, but the technical piece looks very bad (public comps are valued very low, previous exits in the space have been at 1X revenues) it will admittedly give us pause. Because ultimately we need to see an opportunity to return a multiple of capital to our limited partners, and if the market isn&#8217;t interested in a deal we do, that is going to matter.</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><a class="zemanta-pixie-a" title="Zemified by Zemanta" href="http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/31961989-0983-4522-b07d-c1a0e6b313aa/"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:medium none;float:right;" src="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=31961989-0983-4522-b07d-c1a0e6b313aa" alt="Reblog this post [with Zemanta]" /></a></div>
Posted in Uncategorized&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Tagged: venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/148/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=148&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/22/fundamental-vs-technical-vc-investing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Eric Wiesen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=31961989-0983-4522-b07d-c1a0e6b313aa" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reblog this post [with Zemanta]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s in a Name?</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/20/whats-in-a-name/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/20/whats-in-a-name/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 23:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[aol]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Blogger]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Flickr]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[MySpace]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Photobucket]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[startup names]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Startups]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[YouTube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=146</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been on a few panels (and been in the audience for many more) that focus on starting up a company. A lot of the questions (unsurprisingly) are about starting up web companies and best practices around doing so. Inevitably, one question arises:
&#8220;How much does the name matter?&#8221;
What does surprise me is the answer I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=146&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><div id="attachment_45" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-45" title="Eric Wiesen" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Eric Wiesen" width="60" height="64" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Eric Wiesen</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;ve been on a few panels (and been in the audience for many more) that focus on starting up a company. A lot of the questions (unsurprisingly) are about starting up web companies and best practices around doing so. Inevitably, one question arises:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;How much does the name matter?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>What does surprise me is the answer I usually hear from VCs, successful entrepreneurs, and other luminaries:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;It doesn&#8217;t matter.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>They go on to say focus on your product, great customer experience, scalability and all the other important company-formation features. And I agree that those are all critical, first-order concerns. But I disagree that names don&#8217;t matter, at least where consumer-facing applications and services are concerned.</p>
<p>Businesses generally don&#8217;t care what things are called - they have the time and financial interest to due significant due diligence on various offerings (although truthfully it doesn&#8217;t always happen) and decisions are made around more metrics-oriented decision criteria. But consumers are a whole different ballgame. You need to grab a share of their increasingly overwhelmed and attention-deficit suffering consciousness. You need, to use a metaphor I like in many contexts, to be no or low-friction. And your name is the first thing they are going to see.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;d lay out three rules for naming a consumer-facing web product:</p>
<ol>
<li>Be easy to spell</li>
<li>Be 8 characters or less</li>
<li>Be in plain language</li>
</ol>
<p>You don&#8217;t need all three. But you need the first and one of the last two to have a good web name. Looking at some of the top (US) consumer-facing websites, let&#8217;s see how they stack up:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.yahoo.com">Yahoo</a> (Easy to spell, 5 characters, arguably plain language): 2.5/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.google.com">Google</a> (Easy to spell, 6 characters): 2/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.youtube.com">YouTube</a> (Easy to spell, 7 characters, plain language): 3/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.myspace.com">MySpace</a> (Easy to spell, 7 characters, plain language): 3/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.facebook.com">Facebook</a> (Easy to spell, 8 characters, plain language): 3/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.blogger.com">Blogger</a> (Easy to spell, 7 characters): 2/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.ebay.com">Ebay</a> (Easy to spell, 4 characters): 2/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.amazon.com">Amazon</a> (Easy to spell, 6 characters, plain language): 3/3 <strong>PASS</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.flickr.com">Flickr</a> (5 characters): 1/3 <span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>FAIL</strong></span></p>
<p>This is a somewhat cherry picked list, but most of remaining top sites by traffic are either abbreviations (<a href="http://www.msn.com">MSN</a>, <a href="http://www.aol.com">AOL</a>) or similarly compliant sites (<a href="http://www.live.com">live.com</a>, <a href="http://www.photobucket.com">photobucket</a>, etc&#8230;).  We find only one site - flickr - that doesn&#8217;t meet these criteria for consumer-facing name success.</p>
<p>We can speculate about why this is, but I would suggest that the obvious answer is likely the right one, as Occam would say. If consumers can&#8217;t remember, recognize or spell your name, they are unlikely to get to your site via direct, type-in traffic. That leaves you with SEO, SEM and other indirect methods for drawing in users, all of which are important, but without that initial primary funnel you may struggle. To pick on <a href="http://blog.iminlikewithyou.com/">Charles</a> (because I know he can take it), iminlikewithyou is not a good consumer-facing name. It&#8217;s 15 characters, is plain language, but includes a word with an apostrophe, so it only partially passes the spell test.  Really good product, bad name.</p>
<p>We can draw some conclusions from Flickr&#8217;s success, or we can just say it&#8217;s the exception that proves the rule. Flickr built its audience largely of &#8220;net natives&#8221; who quickly adopted the &#8220;missing e&#8221; as the next creative web naming convention (sort of like ____ster became earlier), and we&#8217;ve soon lots of similarly-spelled &#8220;Web 2.0&#8243; company names. In fairness, a lot of this is driven by domain squatters taking many of the plain language names. But in the absence of plain language, I would argue that your new company&#8217;s name should be short and easy to spell, even if it&#8217;s meaningless (worked pretty well for Google). Sure, the tech-saavy crowd may figure out del.icio.us but will your parents or your friends who aren&#8217;t &#8220;webheads&#8221;? If you are comfortable building a big, successful business out of just us (it can be done), by all means. But if you are going for mainstream&#8230;</p>
<p>Ultimately, if you are being thoughtful about your core site, service or application, you are carefully instrumenting your processes (registration, sign-on, setup, etc&#8230;) to minimize the waterfall of dropped users and are being diligent about removing friction to lower bounce rate and registration failure. Don&#8217;t start out on the wrong foot with a name that won&#8217;t stay with potential users. <a href="http://www.path101.com">Path101</a>? Good. <a href="http://www.xoopit.com">Xoopit</a>? Well&#8230;</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><a class="zemanta-pixie-a" title="Zemified by Zemanta" href="http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/f2ac4342-c65b-40a6-9063-2714dfa0c4c0/"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:medium none;float:right;" src="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=f2ac4342-c65b-40a6-9063-2714dfa0c4c0" alt="Reblog this post [with Zemanta]" /></a></div>
Posted in Uncategorized&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Tagged: aol, Blogger, facebook, Flickr, Google, MySpace, Photobucket, startup names, Startups, YouTube&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=146&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/20/whats-in-a-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/edw.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Eric Wiesen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=f2ac4342-c65b-40a6-9063-2714dfa0c4c0" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reblog this post [with Zemanta]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kashless</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/17/kashless/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/17/kashless/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 23:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[kashless]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[RRE Ventures]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=144</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We recently made a decision to invest in the Series A round of a new company called Kashless. This investment is one we&#8217;re very excited about, and reflects a lot of our investment philosophy here at RRE. The company is still essentially in stealth mode, although certain details leaked out via SEC filings we did [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=144&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><div id="attachment_44" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 70px"><a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-44" title="Stuart Ellman" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif?w=60&#038;h=64" alt="Stuart Ellman" width="60" height="64" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Stuart Ellman</p></div>
<p>We recently made a decision to invest in the Series A round of a new company called <a href="http://www.kashless.org">Kashless</a>. This investment is one we&#8217;re very excited about, and reflects a lot of our investment philosophy here at <a href="http://www.rre.com">RRE</a>. The company is still essentially in stealth mode, although certain details leaked out via SEC filings we did around the financing. Rather than go into a lot of detail about what Martin Tobias, the CEO of Kashless, is planning on doing with the company, we&#8217;ll talk a little bit here about our process and thinking that led to this investment.</p>
<p>As we&#8217;ve mentioned in this space before, at a highly abstract level, we (and most investors) look for excellence in three key areas: people, markets and technology (the order depends on which of us you ask). In certain sectors, technology will be the key differentiator (materials science-based cleantech or semiconductors), in others it will be the vision and execution capabilities of the management team that will primarily distinguish the big successes. In all cases you need a market that&#8217;s capable of supporting interestingly large businesses.</p>
<p>Two major positives intersected to make us very excited about the opportunity here. The first was the opportunity to back Martin Tobias again. As the writers of this blog discussed offline the other day, Martin is a winner. We don&#8217;t just know him in a business relationship, we know him as a friend as well. Stuart stays with Martin when he travels to Seattle.  They ride the 200 mile Seattle to Portland bike ride each year.  Stuart and Martin have spend a great deal of time trying to figure out what business to start.  Kashless is the culmination of this strategizing, much of it done during bike rides.   Martin has demonstrated a great nose for the very beginning of trends, and that&#8217;s a terrific quality in an entrepreneur. He&#8217;s also extremely good at building organizations and getting them to scale. We know Martin&#8217;s strengths and weaknesses.  We know that we can work with Martin and we know that there is mutual respect.  We also know that he has lived through bubbles and busts before and we have a shared history on the appropriate ways to react to new market information.</p>
<p>The second is that (true to form for Martin), we think Kashless is poised to catch a big wave. Often times when we evaluate companies that seem good, but don&#8217;t quite feel right, one question we ask internally is, &#8220;what wave is this company riding?&#8221;, which helps focus the conversation around large, meta-trends that can propel a company and its target market into a high growth trajectory. Kashless is riding a big wave - call it &#8220;green&#8221;, &#8220;sustainability&#8221; or what you like, but economic, cultural and social forces are all moving us toward a world where issues of sustainability are more important than ever. Kashless looks to enable people to live more efficient, sustainable lives, and that&#8217;s an objective of which we are both supportive and optimistic.  Also very important for RRE, as we mentioned in previous posts, Kashless can achieve these objectives in a capital efficient manner.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more from Kashless, but we think big things are coming.</p>
Posted in venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Tagged: kashless, RRE Ventures&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=144&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/17/kashless/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/stu.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stuart Ellman</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The more things change, the more they stay the same&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/15/the-more-things-change-the-more-they-stay-the-same/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/15/the-more-things-change-the-more-they-stay-the-same/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 13:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[downturn]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=135</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another guest post from a member of the RRE Team - here Jim Robinson IV shares a few thoughts and anecdotes about a lot of the discussion flying around the web about the VC model being broken. - EDW

As this discussion gets underway - again - I pulled together a bit of perspective. I call [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=135&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><p><em>Another guest post from a member of the RRE Team - here <a href="http://www.rre.com/Our_Team#James_D._Robinson_IV">Jim Robinson IV </a>shares a few thoughts and anecdotes about a lot of the <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/guest1c3ad/thefunded-canarie-presentation?type=powerpoint">discussion</a> <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2008/11/12/the-vc-model-is-broken/">flying</a> <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/11/12/a-scary-line-has-been-crossed-for-vcs/">around</a> <a href="http://www.avc.com/a_vc/2008/11/a-slightly-diff.html">the web</a> <a href="http://jeffnolan.com/wp/2008/11/12/the-vc-model-is-broken-again/">about</a> <a href="http://www.altgate.com/blog/2008/11/venture-capital-is-broken.html">the</a> <a href="http://yallaguy.wordpress.com/2008/11/13/is-venture-capital-broken/">VC model</a> <a href="http://gigaom.com/2008/11/14/is-the-vc-model-broken-far-from-it/">being</a> <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/the-pyramid-principle-a-new-approach-to-venture-investment.html">broken</a>. - EDW<br />
</em></p>
<div id="attachment_136" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 98px"><a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/jamesiv.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-136" title="James D. Robinson IV" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/jamesiv.jpg?w=88&#038;h=95" alt="James D. Robinson IV" width="88" height="95" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">James D. Robinson IV</p></div>
<p>As this discussion gets underway - again - I pulled together a bit of perspective. I call it, “<span style="text-decoration:underline;">Things I heard when I first joined the world of venture capital as an intern in 1991</span>”.  For those more recent to this industry, during that period the business was down and out after the ‘88-90 debacle. Many funds had stopped investing, there were few IPOs, older guys were retiring, cents-on-the-dollar returns, etc… I remember thinking maybe I should have my head examined for coming into VC just as it was dying.  My boss at the time, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Hambrecht">Bill Hambrecht</a>, wondered the same thing…</p>
<p>So here are a few of the things people were saying in 1991:</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;The VC model is broken&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;There is too much money chasing too few deals&#8221;</li>
<li> &#8220;VC&#8217;s are too arrogant and the pitching process is too inefficient&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Superfunds with $100 million or more are in trouble and will fail&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Software companies are much more capital-efficient and this requires a new way of thinking about VC&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Software is over as a category.  Just like disc drives, there are too many me-too companies.  Only the big ones will survive&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;LP&#8217;s are moving away from VC as an asset class given the return profile and future prospects&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;The number of firms will decline dramatically&#8221; (was about 600 then, depending on what you count)</li>
<li>&#8220;IPO&#8217;s are much tougher and will stay that way; exits - and returns - will suffer for a decade or more&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Future opportunities are in biotech and &#8217;specialty materials&#8217;, not IT.</li>
</ul>
<p>The above were <strong>not</strong> just random comments, but in fact the &#8216;prevailing wisdom&#8217; of the day held by many, including lots of VCs, entrepreneurs, LP&#8217;s, etc.</p>
<p>By contrast, here is what I hear today&#8230;.</p>
<ul>
<li>&#8220;The VC model is broken&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;There is too much money chasing too few deals&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;VC&#8217;s are too arrogant and the pitching process is too inefficient&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Superfunds with $200 million or more are in trouble and will fail&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Internet companies are much more capital-efficient and this requires a new way of thinking about VC&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;IT is over as a category.  Just like web 2.0 companies, there are too many me-too companies.  Only the big ones will survive&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;LP&#8217;s are moving away from VC as an asset class given the return profile and future prospects&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;The number of firms will decline dramatically&#8221; (is about 1200 now, depending on what you count)</li>
<li>&#8220;IPO&#8217;s are much tougher and will stay that way; exits - and returns - will suffer for a decade or more&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;Future opportunities are in ET and Nanotech, not IT&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>I actually agree with a number of the sentiments above. Of course, I did back then, too. Yeah, I know. This time it’s different. Right? I wonder, in 15 years, what we will say.</p>
<p>Whenever I read these kinds of discussions, it always gets me to a more humble place, where I realize history tends to repeat far more often than not, no matter how much we wish it were not so.  It also reminds me of a bunch of my favorite famous quotes from the past&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;640K (of conventional memory) ought to be enough for anybody.&#8221; </em>&#8211; Bill Gates, CEO and founder of Microsoft, <strong>1981</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;There is no reason anyone would want a computer in their home.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Ken Olson, president, chairman and founder of Digital Equipment Corp. (DEC), maker of big business mainframe computers, arguing against the PC, <strong>1977</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;We don&#8217;t like their sound, and guitar music is on the way out anyway.&#8221;</em> &#8212; President of Decca Records, rejecting The Beatles after an audition, <strong>1962</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Transmission of documents via telephone wires is possible in principle, but the apparatus required is so expensive that it will never become a practical proposition.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Dennis Gabor, British physicist and author of Inventing the Future, <strong>1962</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;There is practically no chance communications space satellites will be used to provide better telephone, telegraph, television, or radio service inside the United States.&#8221;</em> &#8212; T. Craven, FCC Commissioner, <strong>1961</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;The world potential market for copying machines is 5000 at most.&#8221;</em> &#8212; IBM , to the eventual founders of Xerox, saying the photocopier had no market large enough to justify production, <strong>1959</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;I have traveled the length and breadth of this country and talked with the best people, and I can assure you that data processing is a fad that won&#8217;t last out the year.&#8221;</em> &#8212; The editor in charge of business books for Prentice Hall, <strong>1957</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Computers in the future may weigh no more than 1.5 tons.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Popular Mechanics, &#8220;predicting&#8221; the relentless march of technology, <strong>1949</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Television won&#8217;t last because people will soon get tired of staring at<br />
a plywood box every night.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Darryl Zanuck, movie producer, 20th Century Fox, <strong>1946</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;I think there is a world market for maybe five computers.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Thomas Watson, chairman of IBM, <strong>1943</strong><br />
<em></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Who the hell wants to hear actors talk?&#8221;</em> &#8212; H.M. Warner, Warner Brothers, maker of silent movies, <strong>1927</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;The radio craze will die out in time.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Thomas Edison, American inventor, <strong>1922</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;That the automobile has practically reached the limit of its development is suggested by the fact that during the past year no improvements of a radical nature have been introduced.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Scientific American, Jan. 2 edition, <strong>1909</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Heavier-than-air flying machines are impossible.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Lord Kelvin, British mathematician and physicist, president of the British Royal Society, <strong>1895</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;X-rays will prove to be a hoax.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Lord Kelvin, British mathematician and physicist, president of the British Royal Society, <strong>1895</strong>(?)</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;The phonograph has no commercial value at all.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Thomas Edison, American inventor, <strong>1880s </strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Everyone acquainted with the subject will recognize it as a conspicuous failure.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Henry Morton, president of the Stevens Institute of Technology, on Edison&#8217;s light bulb, <strong>1880</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Drill for oil? You mean drill into the ground to try and find oil? You&#8217;re crazy.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Drillers whom Edwin L. Drake tried to enlist to his project to drill for oil, <strong>1859</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Rail travel at high speeds is not possible because passengers, unable to breathe, would die of asphyxia.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Dionysius Lardner, Professor of Natural Philosophy and Astronomy at University College, London, and author of The Steam Engine Explained and Illustrated, <strong>1830s</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;&#8230;so many centuries after the &#8216;Creation&#8217; it is unlikely that anyone could find hitherto unknown lands of any value.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Committee advising King Ferdinand and Queen Isabella of Spain regarding a proposal to provide venture capital to Christopher Columbus, <strong>1486</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Stock prices have reached what looks like a permanently high plateau.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Irving Fisher, Yale University Professor of Economics, <strong>1929</strong> (two weeks later, the stock market crashed and the Great Depression started)</p>
<p>And finally, as it relates to predicting the future:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>There are many methods for predicting the future. For example, you can read horoscopes, tea leaves, tarot cards, or crystal balls. Collectively, these methods are known as &#8220;nutty methods.&#8221;  Or you can put well-researched facts into sophisticated computer models, more commonly referred to as &#8220;a complete waste of time.</em> &#8212; <a href="http://thinkexist.com/quotation/there_are_many_methods_for_predicting_the_future/11983.htm">Adams, Scott</a></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>Predicting the future is easy. It&#8217;s trying to figure out what&#8217;s going on now that&#8217;s hard.</em> &#8212; <a href="http://quotationsbook.com/quote/16492/">Dressler, Fritz</a></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>The more unpredictable the world is the more we rely on predictions. </em>&#8211; <a href="http://quotingthomas.com/Famous_quotes_by_SteveRivkin.html">Rivkin, Steve</a></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>It&#8217;s tough to make predictions, especially about the future.</em> &#8212; <a href="http://quotingthomas.com/Famous_quotes_by_YogiBerra.html">Berra, Yogi</a> <strong><br />
</strong></p>
Posted in downturn, venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Tagged: venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/135/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=135&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/15/the-more-things-change-the-more-they-stay-the-same/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/jamesiv.jpg?w=88" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">James D. Robinson IV</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flipswap</title>
		<link>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/14/flipswap/</link>
		<comments>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/14/flipswap/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 15:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fiveyearstoolate</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[adaptive blue]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[flipswap]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[greentech]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[recyclebank]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[RRE Ventures]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[tendril]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[venture capital]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/?p=130</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are happy to have our partner Harsh Patel here guest posting about our recently-announced investment in Flipswap. - EDW

It&#8217;s probably safe to say the current climate for startup venture financing has been thoroughly documented over the last few weeks, both here and elsewhere.  I think you get it.  But as my partner [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=130&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class='snap_preview'><br /><p><em>We are happy to have our partner <a href="http://www.rre.com/Our_Team#Harsh_P._Patel">Harsh Patel</a> here guest posting about our recently-announced investment in Flipswap. - EDW<br />
</em></p>
<div id="attachment_131" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 98px"><a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/harsh.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-131" title="Harsh Patel" src="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/harsh.jpg?w=88&#038;h=95" alt="Harsh Patel" width="88" height="95" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Harsh Patel</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s probably safe to say the current climate for startup venture financing has been thoroughly documented over the last few weeks, both <a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/10/24/flat-is-the-new-40-markup">here</a> and elsewhere.  I think you get it.  But as my partner <a href="http://www.rre.com/Our_Team#Stuart_J._Ellman">Stuart</a> mentioned in a recent post, despite this climate we still see opportunity and we are still doing deals.  We recently <a href="http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/10/28/adaptive-blue">announced</a> our investment in <a href="http://www.adaptiveblue.com/index.html">Adaptive Blue</a> and now I&#8217;m happy to announce another new investment in <a href="http://www.flipswap.com/">Flipswap</a>, a Series B financing co-led by <a href="http://www.rre.com">RRE</a> and <a href="http://www.ngenpartners.com/">NGEN Partners</a>.</p>
<p>This investment reflects an evolving thesis we have in Fund IV around &#8220;Green Technology&#8221;, where traditional information technologies and associated business models intersect with a new set of global challenges. <a href="http://www.recyclebank.com/"> Recyclebank</a> and <a href="http://www.flipswap.com">Flipswap</a> developed unique business models that generate real economic incentives that allow consumers, businesses and governments to act more sustainably while still acting in their own self-interest. <a href="http://www.tendrilinc.com/"> Tendril</a> is attacking the demand side of the energy problem by directly linking energy consumers to utilities, enabling both sides to proactively manage energy usage and reduce cost.  So while financial markets may be busy painfully remaking themselves in the near term, they will not affect this macro thesis (or many other macro trends which underpin our investment decisions).</p>
<p>But of course macro alone is never enough.  Underlying trends and investment theses are only academic unless embodied by entrepreneurs who can execute.  Sohrob Farudi and his team at Flipswap did exactly that.  Even as we all consult our tea leaves and crystal balls to see where the markets are headed, the best entrepreneurs know they don&#8217;t have that luxury.  So instead they control what they can and react quickly when they have to.  One of the simplest but most compelling points of evidence I look for as a VC is that an entrepreneur continues to perform throughout the fundraising process the way they said they would at your first meeting.  Even in the best of times fundraising can be a lengthy process, and your ability to accurately forecast your business and execute against it is critical.  So while any investment decision can be complex and the diligence process long, it very often comes down to this - do we believe in the market and do we believe in the team?  We said yes on both counts and we&#8217;re delighted to welcome Flipswap to the portfolio.</p>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><a class="zemanta-pixie-a" title="Zemified by Zemanta" href="http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/d188d6c4-6237-45bc-8d40-f79460c9d5d8/"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:medium none;float:right;" src="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=d188d6c4-6237-45bc-8d40-f79460c9d5d8" alt="Reblog this post [with Zemanta]" /></a></div>
Posted in Uncategorized&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Tagged: adaptive blue, flipswap, greentech, recyclebank, RRE Ventures, tendril, venture capital&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/130/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com&blog=4778179&post=130&subd=fiveyearstoolate&ref=&feed=1" /></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fiveyearstoolate.wordpress.com/2008/11/14/flipswap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiveyearstoolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fiveyearstoolate.files.wordpress.com/2008/11/harsh.jpg?w=88" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Harsh Patel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=d188d6c4-6237-45bc-8d40-f79460c9d5d8" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reblog this post [with Zemanta]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>