<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://www.blogger.com/styles/atom.css" type="text/css"?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xmlns:openSearch='http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/'><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483</id><updated>2009-01-21T11:35:54.960-08:00</updated><title type='text'>Giles Bowkett</title><subtitle type='html'>&lt;a href="http://github.com/gilesbowkett/archaeopteryx/wikis/home"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/arx_101508/sideways.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://secure.eff.org/site/SPageServer?pagename=DON_splash"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/eff_011109/EFF_animated.gif"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</subtitle><link rel='http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#feed' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/'/><link rel='next' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default?start-index=26&amp;max-results=25'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author><generator version='7.00' uri='http://www.blogger.com'>Blogger</generator><openSearch:totalResults>1141</openSearch:totalResults><openSearch:startIndex>1</openSearch:startIndex><openSearch:itemsPerPage>25</openSearch:itemsPerPage><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-2997704644094105567</id><published>2009-01-21T11:35:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-21T11:35:54.984-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-21T11:35:54.984-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Speaking At CUSEC In Montréal</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://2009.cusec.net/schedule/"&gt;In two days&lt;/a&gt;!</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/2997704644094105567?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2997704644094105567'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/speaking-at-cusec-in-montral.html' title='Speaking At CUSEC In Montréal'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-699798327526360142</id><published>2009-01-21T11:13:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-21T11:15:02.683-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-21T11:15:02.683-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>ftw</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://www.boston.com/bigpicture/2009/01/the_inauguration_of_president.html"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/inaug_012109/inaug.jpg" border=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/699798327526360142?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/699798327526360142'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/ftw.html' title='ftw'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-9010637983534183913</id><published>2009-01-20T00:05:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-20T00:07:11.412-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-20T00:07:11.412-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>The Business Case For Expensive iPhone Apps</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://www.mobileorchard.com/price-and-popularity-the-iphone-app-stores-data-shows-whos-making-the-big-money/"&gt;Some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.mobileorchard.com/99-cent-iphone-apps-not-significantly-more-popular/"&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/dcgrigsby"&gt;Dan Grigsby&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/9010637983534183913?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/9010637983534183913'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/business-case-for-expensive-iphone-apps.html' title='The Business Case For Expensive iPhone Apps'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-2656449499823779634</id><published>2009-01-19T15:02:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-19T22:19:06.145-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-19T22:19:06.145-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>HAML Brings Seaside Awesome To Ruby</title><content type='html'>Seaside packs a lot of ideas into one framework. One innovation: you don't write HTML. You tell Seaside what HTML you want, and it does all the dirty work.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's a Seaside object with a method that creates a simple form. It's for a mini-app that takes your address, tells you who your senators and representative are, and gives you their phone numbers. It currently has no graphic design.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/seaside_form.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Seaside version of this app is unfinished, because I'm much more competent with Ruby. But it's a nice, simple example. Take a look at the code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/seaside_code.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This code is easy to read. You're creating an HTML form, with text, a text input, and a submit button. You know that whether you can read Smalltalk or not.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In Seaside, you have web app components (&lt;code&gt;WAComponent&lt;/code&gt; subclasses) with &lt;code&gt;renderContentOn&lt;/code&gt; methods (actually messages) that generate HTML for you. This structure, combined with Smalltalk's syntax, gives you clear and simple code. The clarity and simplicity make Seaside fun to work in.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There's a lot of frustration as well, since Seaside generally happens outside of Unix, making me a stranger in a strange land. But the code is, afterwards, just easy as hell to read. I often come back to code and scratch my head wondering what I was thinking when I wrote it. That doesn't happen with Seaside, as far as I can tell. You always know what you meant to do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The downside, however, is that this code just uses the word &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt; too much. It's kind of ridiculous to type &lt;code&gt;html space.&lt;/code&gt; when you could just type " ". In Seaside, you're not going to type a whole lot of HTML, but you are going to type &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt; a whole lot. Any time I see code like this I look for a refactor. If you're calling the same object with every line of code, then the method belongs in that object.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's code from a Seaside tutorial:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/tutorial.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don't think this is any real serious of criticism of Seaside, however, although I do think it's a valid criticism of the Seaside &lt;i&gt;community&lt;/i&gt;. It's an obvious need for refactoring, and it comes from the language that invented refactoring. What's up with that? I think Seaside programmers should be subclassing the renderer at least as often as &lt;code&gt;WAComponent&lt;/code&gt; - but that's a tangent.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I bring this all up for the sake of comparison. Like I say, I didn't actually write this app in Seaside. I wrote it in Sinatra with HAML.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/sinatra_form.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Take a look at the code for this view.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/haml.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It isn't as pretty as the Seaside code, but it's almost as clear, and it's terser. With HAML, you don't have to type a whole lot of HTML, and you might not type a whole lot of &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt;. And just like the Seaside code, it's easy enough to figure out what this code is doing. There's HTML; there's a form; there's a text input and a submit input, which is to say, a submit &lt;i&gt;button&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That could be more readable. In the best of both worlds, HAML wouldn't just abbreviate the process of writing HTML; it would also replace nonsense like &lt;code&gt;input{:type =&gt; "submit"}&lt;/code&gt; with Rails-y helpers with logical names like, for example, &lt;code&gt;button&lt;/code&gt;. It always worries me, when somebody thinks I'm smart because I'm a programmer, that they're going to find out that one of the reasons programmers think DHH is a genius is because he figured out that we should use the word &lt;code&gt;button&lt;/code&gt; when we want to say "button."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/zomg.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;At the same time, however, HAML annoys a lot of people. I praised it on Twitter and everybody I work with started laughing at me, even people who can't write code. Hampton Caitlin took the Python feature that annoys people the most, namely semantic indentation, and combined it with the Perl feature that annoys people the most, namely gratuitous punctuation. It should be no surprise that combining the most annoying feature of Perl with the most annoying feature of Python would result in a language that annoys many people very much. It's like a eugenics program to breed a hybrid super-annoyance. I don't know if Hampton's next language is going to take a lot of the busywork out of JavaScript, or simply fart in public while forcing you to hear &lt;i&gt;Battlestar Galactica&lt;/i&gt; spoilers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/cylon.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I like it anyway, though. HAML kind of gives you the inverse of Seaside's advantage. The readability isn't perfect, but the writing is &lt;i&gt;fast&lt;/i&gt;. Like Smalltalk, HAML uses incredibly simple rules. You can learn them in a few minutes, and afterwards, it pretty much just works out the box. And most people don't compare HAML to Smalltalk; they compare it to HTML.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's HAML generating your list of representatives:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/legislators.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's the HTML:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/html.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here's what that would look like in ERb:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/erb.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The HAML makes the ERb look messy. But look closer and you'll see a much more interesting difference. The HAML is almost entirely &lt;i&gt;programming&lt;/i&gt;. There's very little markup involved. That means that when you're writing HAML, you're &lt;i&gt;programming&lt;/i&gt; more and marking up less. This is the same advantage Seaside gives you. If you like programming and you don't like writing markup, then the advantage is you &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;have more fun&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/fun.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I enjoy programming in Seaside because when I'm programming in Seaside, I'm programming. I'm not wrestling with markup; that's for computers to do. I get the same pleasure out of using HAML. At the same time, when I'm in Seaside, I trip over my own feet a lot, because there's a lot about Smalltalk's idiosyncratic environment that doesn't make sense to me. HAML doesn't have that issue.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;HAML also takes a more even-handed approach to the balance of programming and markup than ERb. ERb requires bulky special delimiters for programming, and treats markup as plain text. The implication is that markup code is normal, and programming code is unusual. In many cases you don't notice, because delimiters are built into the markup, so you're adding them to both markup and programming either way. However, in a mostly-programming view like the above example, the delimiters just look stupid.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;ERb favors a type of application where you have less dynamic content and more static content. Where ERb requires bulky special delimiters for programming but treats markup as text, HAML requires &lt;i&gt;svelte&lt;/i&gt; special delimiters for both markup &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; programming, and only treats &lt;i&gt;text&lt;/i&gt; as text. This works equally well whether static markup code predominates, or dynamic programming code. Balance is good.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/balance.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I think HAML is awesome. I get a major Seaside advantage without the stumbling. I have to take annoyances from Perl and Python, but in exchange I get to skip the HTML. I've written a lot of Perl, a little Python, and an unholy fuckton of HTML. I remember what I enjoyed; I know what I like. The tradeoff's worth it, to me. I'm more than happy to take Perl and Python aggravation if it means I don't have to write HTML.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I've heard that HAML doesn't have unit tests, but &lt;a href="http://github.com/nex3/haml/tree/master"&gt;it does on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. The project started with Hampton Caitlin and Nathan Weizenbaum took it over. It could be that an early version lacked tests, and Nathan added them. I haven't taken a look at the tests in detail but there are plenty of them, for what that's worth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;: Brett Morgan clued me in to Smalltalk &lt;a href="http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/node/2606"&gt;cascades&lt;/a&gt;, which allow you to skip typing &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt; 100 times without having to subclass anything; and a heckler on Twitter came close to making a good point, that Rails uses &lt;code&gt;submit_tag&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;button&lt;/code&gt;. He didn't actually say that, he said &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;input type="submit"&amp;gt; != &amp;lt;button&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, which was kind of my point, but if he had managed to think of a better criticism, he would have brought up the &lt;code&gt;submit_tag&lt;/code&gt; thing. But Rails does use &lt;code&gt;link_to&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;a href&lt;/code&gt;, and it does have &lt;code&gt;button_for&lt;/code&gt;, so, close enough.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/campfire.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And: the app, which looks up your legislators by your address, took 20 lines of code. I wrote it while watching &lt;i&gt;The Silence Of The Lambs&lt;/i&gt; and debugging work code on a client's staging server. I used full addresses because you need the full address; searching only by zip code will sometimes return inaccurate results, due to pervasive gerrymandering. I never got around to deploying, but here's the code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/sinatra.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just for the hell of it, here's an 8-line version:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/haml_011909/eight_lines.gif"&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/2656449499823779634?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2656449499823779634'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/haml-brings-seaside-awesome-to-ruby.html' title='HAML Brings Seaside Awesome To Ruby'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-5415750432410464205</id><published>2009-01-19T00:19:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-19T00:19:24.779-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-19T00:19:24.779-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Cute Video Summarizes Cluetrain Manifesto</title><content type='html'>&lt;object width="300" height="225"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2753002&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&amp;amp;fullscreen=1" /&gt;&lt;embed src="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2753002&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&amp;amp;fullscreen=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" width="300" height="225"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/5415750432410464205?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5415750432410464205'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/cute-video-summarizes-cluetrain.html' title='Cute Video Summarizes Cluetrain Manifesto'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-3328311761914635730</id><published>2009-01-18T03:40:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-18T03:47:38.503-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-18T03:47:38.503-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>User Interface: Remember The Ecosystem</title><content type='html'>Go to a video on YouTube; it starts right away. Go to a musician's page on Myspace; the music starts right away. Everyone knows how annoying this is. What I've just figured out is the common principle in the annoyance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is an entire environment on your computer, and both these errors - and all the many variations - come from a single failure in planning user experience. &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Nobody's app or site will ever be the only thing running on anyone's machine under normal circumstances.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can avoid this entire category of errors by remembering this simple fact.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/3328311761914635730?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3328311761914635730'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/user-interface-remember-ecosystem.html' title='User Interface: Remember The Ecosystem'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-2000943172491809334</id><published>2009-01-18T03:23:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-18T03:28:55.610-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-18T03:28:55.610-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Animation: Hand-Drawn Hand</title><content type='html'>I took a bunch of art classes a few years back. Most of my video work from that time &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/174841"&gt;makes me cringe&lt;/a&gt;, but this I'm still pretty happy with.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="334"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=174840&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1" /&gt;&lt;embed src="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=174840&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" width="500" height="334"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's a technical study. I drew maybe thirty pictures of my hand, moving very slowly from one gesture to another, scanned them, and then traced over I think 17 of them in Flash. I tried to do it with &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tweening"&gt;tweens&lt;/a&gt;, but it didn't work. I did it in After Effects just fading quickly from each hand-drawn original to the next, but the differences in the scans, differences of lighting and paper texture mainly, borked the result. I wanted consistency. So I hand-drew every frame on top of the scans of the original drawings.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After this I did some research on animation, and it seems the workflow in most Hollywood cartoons is to draw keyframes in the States and outsource the hand-drawn tweening to Asia. This leads me to believe that in about ten years (very roughly) we'll see an explosion in home-grown animation. Flash is almost good enough to do the in-between drawing automagically, but not quite. The AI necessary to automate that grunt work is definitely achieveable, however.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/2000943172491809334?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2000943172491809334'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/animation-hand-drawn-hand.html' title='Animation: Hand-Drawn Hand'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-7714053724966740609</id><published>2009-01-18T02:29:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-18T02:34:35.319-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-18T02:34:35.319-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>OS X: Get Rid Of Weak Icons</title><content type='html'>&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/icon_011809/broken.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/icon_011809/question.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.discoapp.com/"&gt;&lt;img border=0 src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/icon_011809/disco_icon.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/icon_011809/thief.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width="349" height="197"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2868059&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1" /&gt;&lt;embed src="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2868059&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" width="349" height="197"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/icon_011809/fixed.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/icon_011809/the-end.jpg"&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/7714053724966740609?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/7714053724966740609'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/os-x-get-rid-of-weak-icons.html' title='OS X: Get Rid Of Weak Icons'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-6714461023104696918</id><published>2009-01-18T01:45:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-18T01:47:03.772-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-18T01:47:03.772-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Nyeah Nyeah Atwood: I Win</title><content type='html'>This might not make sense to you. I'm just posting it so I can e-mail Jeff Atwood the link and annoy him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2007/10/7-youtube-use-cases-unrelated-to-viacom.html"&gt;Giles Bowkett, 2007&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/01/18/business/media/18ping.html?_r=1&amp;ref=technology"&gt;NY Times, 2008&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/6714461023104696918?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/6714461023104696918'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/nyeah-nyeah-atwood-i-win.html' title='Nyeah Nyeah Atwood: I Win'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-3990407299688120368</id><published>2009-01-18T01:12:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-18T01:17:50.475-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-18T01:17:50.475-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>What's Hot On GitHub: ENTP</title><content type='html'>For &lt;a href="http://hoth.entp.com/2008/10/31/what-s-hot-on-github-entp"&gt;three&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://hoth.entp.com/2008/12/3/what-s-hot-on-github-entp-again"&gt;months&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.rubyinside.com/whats-hot-on-github-january-2009-1450.html"&gt;in a row&lt;/a&gt;, ENTP projects and projects by ENTP programmers have shown up on &lt;a href="http://www.rubyinside.com/whats-hot-on-github-january-2009-1450.html"&gt;Ruby Inside's monthly "What's Hot On GitHub" feature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don't know if anyone else in the company has even noticed, but personally, I'm hoping for four. &lt;a href="http://calendaraboutnothing.com/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Don't break the chain&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/3990407299688120368?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3990407299688120368'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/whats-hot-on-github-entp.html' title='What&apos;s Hot On GitHub: ENTP'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-4816610068705179589</id><published>2009-01-18T01:03:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-18T01:09:33.692-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-18T01:09:33.692-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Coding Apps For National Service On Jan. 19th</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://sunlightlabs.com/appsforamerica/"&gt;Do it!&lt;/a&gt; Hop on the bandwagon. &lt;a href="http://hoth.entp.com/2009/1/17/keeping-tabs-on-our-congress"&gt;Justin from ENTP created one&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://blog.obiefernandez.com/content/2009/01/getting-our-national-service-groove-on-with-apps-for-america.html"&gt;Hashrocket are creating one&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/4816610068705179589?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4816610068705179589'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/coding-apps-for-national-service-on-jan.html' title='Coding Apps For National Service On Jan. 19th'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-2572139183528846242</id><published>2009-01-18T00:24:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-18T00:30:15.589-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-18T00:30:15.589-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Return Of The Tumble-Log</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://giles.tumblr.com/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;once again back it's the incredible&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/2572139183528846242?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2572139183528846242'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/return-of-tumble-log.html' title='Return Of The Tumble-Log'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-878658592900819631</id><published>2009-01-17T17:36:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-17T17:43:08.528-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-17T17:43:08.528-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Why Hacker News Thinks PHP Won Something</title><content type='html'>This happened yesterday:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/php_011609/hacker_news.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I found these headlines strange.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/php_011609/omgwtf.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The obvious question, of course, is &lt;i&gt;what&lt;/i&gt; PHP allegedly won. And I mean that in both senses: what was the contest, and what was the prize?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next question is: &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; PHP really win?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The third question could be: why did PHP win? It could also be: why does Hacker News &lt;i&gt;think&lt;/i&gt; it won?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Both blog posts say PHP won by becoming the dominant programming language on the Web. This means that the contest was to see which language would obtain the most users, and the prize was having more users than anybody else. Whether this means they &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; won or not depends on whether or not this idea has any validity.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of course, the answer's no. If you program in the most popular programming language, your skill in that particular language is a commodity. If you program &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; in the most popular programming language, you have made &lt;i&gt;yourself&lt;/i&gt; a commodity. A commodity can only compete on location and price, and location doesn't really get you much on the Internet. This means that only people with a poor understanding of economics program in PHP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For years I hid the PHP experience on my resume and even lied in job interviews, saying I didn't know the language. In reality, I've used every version. I remember it well. Back then we all used Perl. I was writing CGI scripts in Perl before there were HTTP libraries. Back then we hand-coded our headers, and we liked it. We walked twelve miles uphill through the snow both ways, and we opened database connections with backticks, and we liked it. Why? Because we were primitives and we didn't know any better, that's why.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://flickr.com/photos/mfakheri/2986166090/"&gt;&lt;img border=0 src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/php_011609/old_guy.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'd like to call this a Hacker News smackdown, but it isn't. First, top of the list of links for one day is just a blip on the radar. Second, if I really couldn't stand Hacker News, I wouldn't read it. Third, it's not a smackdown because it's not a decisive defeat. It's a tie. PHP didn't win, because what it was (allegedly) aiming for was something bad to have. But PHP also &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; win, because it &lt;i&gt;got&lt;/i&gt; what it was (allegedly) aiming for.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The blog posts Hacker News links to - which, honestly, would be &lt;a href="http://startuplessonslearned.blogspot.com/2009/01/why-php-won.html"&gt;unusually&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://alan.dipert.org/post/70990749/why-php-really-won"&gt;moronic&lt;/a&gt; even if this was not Hacker News but Reddit or Digg - ascribe PHP's "success" to either its community or its features. In fact, PHP's "success" came from a combination of lucky timing, and two design decsions: embedding code in a web page, and imitating Perl.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Compare Microsoft's market dominance in the early days of GUI desktop PCs with PHP's dominance in the early days of Web scripting. In either case, an inferior technology overcame a similar, superior technology, within an emerging category. When PHP emerged, everybody was already writing CGI scripts in Perl. PHP was similar enough to Perl that a Perl hacker could be up and running in 15 minutes, and it was easier to use, in one simple, important way: it was embedded in the Web page. You didn't need to code up headers; you didn't need separate files.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This was a tiny win, but it occurred in the context of an epochal, unprecedented, world-changing paradigm shift that created thousands of jobs and destroyed &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travel_agency"&gt;entire&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newspaper"&gt;industries&lt;/a&gt;. These extraordinary historical conditions magnified PHP's advantage. If you could create Web scripts faster than the next company, in the period from 1994 to 1999, it meant the difference between driving a Honda and piloting a yacht.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://flickr.com/photos/bremnerj/22897819/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/php_011609/yacht.jpg" border=0&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People who wrote a ton of PHP in those years invested a great deal of their time in PHP. They now have PHP skills, and they've given the world frameworks and libraries. These silly blog posts, which everyone on Hacker News voted up, both claim that PHP is the language most used on the Web, and although I have no evidence confirming or refuting it, I'm willing to believe them. But the blogs go on to say that PHP's "advantage" comes from its language features or its community.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;First of all, PHP &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;has&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; no advantage. I once got an e-mail from a recruiter where the recruiter had mistakenly forwarded private comments from his boss. It said they were looking for a Perl hacker who would work for less money because they would get to choose Perl. That's how these people think.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Market forces are not about Care Bears and hugs. If you clone a programmer, two programmers with the same brain, and you send one out to hack PHP, and you have the other one use a language where you can charge a reasonable amount of money, the PHP programmer will make less money with the exact same brain. If you love PHP, for some insane reason, you're making less money than you could make, because of your poor taste in languages and your naive assumptions about market forces. &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is not an advantage.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; PHP could not have lost harder.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/php_011609/will_code_for_food.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Second, PHP's advantage came from a tiny ease-of-use boost, in an era where A) Web programmers did &lt;i&gt;everything&lt;/i&gt; by hand, and B) the world changed overnight. &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;There are no lessons for language designers here.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; You might as well be reading tea leaves. World-changing paradigm shifts &lt;i&gt;by definition&lt;/i&gt; do not occur in the same category twice. Before PHP vs. Perl, it was Microsoft vs. Apple. A hundred years ago it was Railroad A vs. Railroad B. It's not going to be languages twice, for the same reason it's never going to be railroads again. There's no point making any language-design decisions based on PHP's success story. The gains PHP got from these design decisions do not correlate to the wisdom of the decisions but to the epochal circumstances of the moment when the decisions happened.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The secret strategy behind PHP's "success" is to already be standing in the right place when the big ball of money falls out of the sky.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; That strategy &lt;i&gt;works&lt;/i&gt;, but it's not scaleable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So you have two blog posts, at number 1 and number 2, debating &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; irrelevant cargo-cult strategy will net you a historic, unrepeatable "advantage" and enable you to "achieve" a &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/03/nothing-will-ever-reign-supreme-ever.html"&gt;"goal"&lt;/a&gt; which would decrease your earnings &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; have you writing painful, ugly code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hacker News used to be too good for this kind of thing. So the question here is: what on earth is wrong with Hacker News? Why is its quality declining? Is the decline inevitable?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/05/summon-monsters-open-door-heal-or-die.html"&gt;But I've already answered that&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/878658592900819631?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/878658592900819631'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/why-hacker-news-thinks-php-won.html' title='Why Hacker News Thinks PHP Won Something'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-4490863385668110625</id><published>2009-01-15T23:21:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-15T23:30:25.950-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-15T23:30:25.950-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Made-Up Thomas Edison Quote</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=vision+without+execution+is+hallucination"&gt;Lots of people attribute "Vision without execution is hallucination" to Thomas Edison&lt;/a&gt;. But &lt;a href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Thomas_Edison"&gt;you won't find it on Wikiquote&lt;/a&gt;, and none of these people provide details on where or when he allegedly said it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don't think he did. I think people used the words "vision" and "execution" differently back then, compared to the way we do today, especially the word "vision," which in those days would have been (in my opinion) reserved for religious contexts. The idea that execution has anything to do with vision, in those days, just didn't exist. If you told somebody back then that you were going to execute on a vision, they'd wonder what the hell you were talking about. Visions were religious phenomena and executions happened during revolutions or the administration of the death sentence. And I'm absolutely positive that the word "hallucination" became a businessman's expression of contempt during the 1960s. Before then, it was too exotic; I believe texts from Edison's day use "phantasm" heavily, and would have gone to "phantom" before they got anywhere near "hallucination."&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It sticks out like a sore thumb to me. It's like if somebody told me that "Cowabunga, dude!" was a quote from George Washington. I can't even figure out why anybody believes it for a second.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/4490863385668110625?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/4490863385668110625'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/made-up-thomas-edison-quote.html' title='Made-Up Thomas Edison Quote'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-749906071187462043</id><published>2009-01-15T19:41:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-15T19:41:52.392-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-15T19:41:52.392-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Ableton Live Will Host Max/MSP</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://www.ableton.com/extend"&gt;Very powerful new feature coming&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/749906071187462043?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/749906071187462043'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/ableton-live-will-host-maxmsp.html' title='Ableton Live Will Host Max/MSP'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-2685869521295608654</id><published>2009-01-14T13:26:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-14T13:27:13.105-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-14T13:27:13.105-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>MIT Blackjack Team Perspective On Financial Crisis</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://www.semyon.com/crisis.html"&gt;The reason that  societies ban pyramid schemes outright, instead of relying on the market to make them unprofitable, is that most people trust their intuition, and their intuition leads them astray. If you were to wait for the market to run its course on a pyramid scheme, the losses could devastate a whole country, as Albanians found out a few years ago.&lt;/a&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/2685869521295608654?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/2685869521295608654'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/mit-blackjack-team-perspective-on.html' title='MIT Blackjack Team Perspective On Financial Crisis'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-5091694726640377980</id><published>2009-01-13T23:17:00.001-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-13T23:31:13.459-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-13T23:31:13.459-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Why Twitter Should Buy Hashtags</title><content type='html'>A lot of people find &lt;a href="http://hashtags.org/"&gt;hashtags&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter annoying. However, they exist because nature abhors a void. They provide something Twitter lacks: categorization. If hashtags also carried with them enforceable privacy restrictions, they would become very powerful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Clay Shirky loves LiveJournal because LiveJournal's flexible, user-defined privacy restrictions allow you to express the simple, unavoidable reality that you often do not want all the same people to see all the same things. In real life you share some information with some friends and other information with others. &lt;a href="http://majikthise.typepad.com/majikthise_/2008/12/facebook-pic-shows-obama-speechwriter-groping-clinton-in-effigy.html"&gt;The things you publish on the Internet should not be readable to all possible people who might find you there&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Twitter's &lt;i&gt;already&lt;/i&gt; essential to tons of people. Imagine if you could tweet at varying levels of publicity. If Twitter had this additional expressive capacity, it would become &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;more&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; essential to &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;more&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Likewise, think how useful it would be if you could tune into only &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; information emanating from a given user. My mom follows me on Twitter. She doesn't give a damn what I think about &lt;a href="http://rspec.info/"&gt;RSpec&lt;/a&gt;, but if I'm thinking of getting a puppy, she'll want to know every possible detail. Someone like &lt;a href="http://blog.davidchelimsky.net/"&gt;David Chelimsky&lt;/a&gt; might take the opposite point of view. Dave should be able to say yes to #rspec and no to #puppy, and my mom should be able to do the inverse.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(I'm sure Dave loves puppies too, of course. Everybody loves puppies. It's just an example.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/puppies_011309/aww.jpg"&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/5091694726640377980?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/5091694726640377980'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/why-twitter-should-buy-hashtags.html' title='Why Twitter Should Buy Hashtags'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-8301885859053348990</id><published>2009-01-13T14:26:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-13T14:27:53.129-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-13T14:27:53.129-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Browser Wars Redux</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://www.urbanhonking.com/ideasfordozens/2009/01/facebook_digs_deeper_into_the.html"&gt;Facebook custom markup: opportunity and trap&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/8301885859053348990?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/8301885859053348990'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/browser-wars-redux.html' title='Browser Wars Redux'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-3654536087660985120</id><published>2009-01-12T13:17:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-12T16:29:39.989-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-12T16:29:39.989-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Never Build A Concept Car</title><content type='html'>&lt;a href="http://counternotions.com/2008/08/12/concept-products/"&gt;This blog post is right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=3oGFogwcx-E"&gt;Exhibit A&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://rjdj.me/what/"&gt;Exhibit B&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://music.metafilter.com/2943/Runnin-With-The-Songsmith"&gt;Exhibit C&lt;/a&gt;.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/3654536087660985120?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3654536087660985120'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/never-build-concept-car.html' title='Never Build A Concept Car'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-3093334742358394248</id><published>2009-01-10T13:53:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-10T14:03:11.057-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-10T14:03:11.057-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Libertarianism Attempts To Divide By Zero</title><content type='html'>When I wrote &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/fundamental-problem-with-libertarianism.html"&gt;my blog post about Libertarianism&lt;/a&gt; the other day, I forgot to mention the biggest problem that Libertarianism has. Libertarianism assumes the presence of many cultural conditions that cannot exist without pervasive free education. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reductio_ad_absurdum"&gt;A Libertarian society would therefore lack the necessary pre-conditions of a Libertarian society.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Consider for example the distinction between self-interest and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enlightened_self-interest"&gt;enlightened self-interest&lt;/a&gt;. Where does the enlightenment come from?</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/3093334742358394248?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3093334742358394248'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/libertarianism-attempts-to-divide-by.html' title='Libertarianism Attempts To Divide By Zero'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-6314835260538826658</id><published>2009-01-08T22:31:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-08T22:46:05.594-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-08T22:46:05.594-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>MS Paint Dead Space</title><content type='html'>BoingBoing &lt;a href="http://www.offworld.com/2009/01/ms-paint-the-games-of-2008.html"&gt;linked&lt;/a&gt; to a gamers forum thread: &lt;a href="http://www.neogaf.com/forum/showthread.php?t=347856"&gt;2008 games in MS Paint&lt;/a&gt;. I'm on OS X, so I used &lt;a href="http://www.flyingmeat.com/acorn/"&gt;Acorn&lt;/a&gt; instead. I couldn't register at the forum; first it denied me based on my Gmail address, then once I relented and used another address, it fed me a series of indecipherable captchas until I gave up. So here it is:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/ms_paint_010809/dead_space.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And it's based on this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/ms_paint_010809/reak.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not exactly a masterpiece, but certainly a fun challenge. The rules allow you to use a tablet, but I didn't see that til too late.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/6314835260538826658?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/6314835260538826658'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/ms-paint-dead-space.html' title='MS Paint Dead Space'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-3528676671923857501</id><published>2009-01-08T11:04:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-08T11:04:55.114-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-08T11:04:55.114-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>My Balls Are Fuzzy Today</title><content type='html'>I blog about whatever I want to blog about. Some people like that; &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/ruby/comments/7mno0/top_ruby_presenter_of_2008_giles_bowkett/7nzg"&gt;some people don't&lt;/a&gt;. That's fine with me. I don't care what people who don't like my blog think about my blog. I figure they shouldn't read it, and I think my logic is sound, although I know for a fact - from comments on sites like Hacker News and Reddit, and occasional inappropriate aggressive tweets - that many people who don't like my blog read it anyway. That's cool too, more pageviews to me, but at the cost of stating the obvious, if you don't like my blog, but you read it anyway, I don't want to hear your complaining. People need to realize that their time-management fail is not my concern.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/funny-pictures-squirrels-have-discovered-coffee.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.8em;"&gt;This image has nothing to do with anything.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don't really care what people who &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; like my blog think about my blog, either. I don't even care what &lt;i&gt;I&lt;/i&gt; think of my blog. It's not supposed to be Gospel. My blog exists partly to channel my &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/09/blogger-claims-they-can-prove-i-am-bot.html"&gt;hypergraphia&lt;/a&gt; to some productive effect and partly because as a programmer my blog is one of several things which drive my &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2007/05/geek-marketing-key-to-making-money-as.html"&gt;personal brand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/obama_miagi.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.8em;"&gt;This image has nothing to do with anything either.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blogs are a &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2007/11/why-reddit-just-doesnt-mean-shit.html"&gt;long tail medium&lt;/a&gt;. Here's a page from Google Analytics. I got Reddit-ed a little one day and saw a little spike in readership. &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The page that got Reddit-ed accounted for only 42% of the readership spike.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/goog-anal.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My rule, derived &lt;i&gt;entirely&lt;/i&gt; from experience, with no opinion or personal investment one way or the other: "&lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2007/11/long-tail-backwards-in-blog-readership.html"&gt;post a lot, even if it seems random&lt;/a&gt;." In a long tail medium, a top ten on Reddit or Hacker News will drive traffic to your blog, but once that traffic gets to your blog, it can go in any direction, so you want to have a lot of things on your blog that people might also want to read. Sometimes people want to read &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/02/wtf-is-this-solar-powered-rotating.html"&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2007/11/crazy-science-shit.html"&gt;crazy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/12/crazy-rspec-one-spec-per-file.html"&gt;shit&lt;/a&gt;. Why not. That's cool with me. I like crazy shit too.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For instance, &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/06/darth-giles.html"&gt;this shit is crazy&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/weird_06308/darth_bowkett.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But I like it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you're one of the people who comes to my blog, reads it, and then gets angry at &lt;i&gt;me&lt;/i&gt; for wasting your time, I have good news and bad news. The good news is, you're right, somebody is wasting your time, and you're right to be mad at them. The bad news is, it's &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;you&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, not me, so fuck off and die. Go kick your own ass and leave me out of the equation. Better yet, just &lt;i&gt;read something you like&lt;/i&gt;. That way we'll &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt; be happier.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One unfortunate byproduct of the personal brand phenomenon - that it helps your career if other programmers know who you are - is that other programmers end up with opinions about you. Some of these opinions are passionate; some of them are accurate; many of them are neither. I know one entire company that worked themselves into a furious delusion of having some kind of feud with me, and I still have no idea what we were ever even supposed to be fighting &lt;i&gt;about&lt;/i&gt;. The set of passionate opinions and accurate opinions did not intersect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It's kind of the same problem a very successful actor faces, and given that I would love to be a very successful actor, or even a working one, I have some ambivalence about it. It's annoying, but it means that what I'm doing is working. Brad Pitt doesn't &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; all these legions of emotionally frustrated housewives to be so fascinated with him, it's just an unfortunate side effect of a very successful acting career. And I'm not even saying that I'm Brad Pitt, and all these Reddit muppets are emotionally frustrated housewives. DHH is Brad Pitt, maybe. I'm like &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=atD3F5NhLww"&gt;Jesus Jones&lt;/a&gt; or "Whoomp! There It Is." Some people just care too much about shit that doesn't matter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width="560" height="345"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/u3ZLW3VPHME&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/u3ZLW3VPHME&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="560" height="345"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;However, I hope you made it all the way down here, because after all the troll-baiting and finger-flipping, there is something worth thinking about. A &lt;a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/ruby/comments/7mno0/top_ruby_presenter_of_2008_giles_bowkett/7nzg"&gt;Reddit thread&lt;/a&gt; voices an idea I've considered: splitting my blog into multiple blogs, one for programming, one for music, one for politics. I mentioned this on Twitter and most people who replied recommended against it. I only got one vote in favor, in this very informal election.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As I see it, there are three reasons not to. First, I'm lazy. Second, my rule is post any random thing, because people might like it. Third, people who read my blog but don't want to have a &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/05/summon-monsters-open-door-heal-or-die.html"&gt;filtering problem&lt;/a&gt;, and I really believe this is something we should solve with &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/12/work-in-progress-boingboing-minus.html"&gt;technology&lt;/a&gt;. In fact I'm working on a Web app which solves it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/just-dont.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The idea behind I Just Don't Give A Shit is simple: prevent you from seeing the shit you just don't give a shit about. Development is stalled right now, but it'll launch in microapp form some time this year. The FAQ is fun to read. The answer to every question is, "I just don't give a shit." For instance, it's going to be a for-pay app; if that &lt;a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2007/08/13/37signals-drives-another-company-to-the-deadpool/"&gt;bothers you&lt;/a&gt;, well, I just don't give a shit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/give-money.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The counter-argument to the technological argument is strong, however. The counter-argument goes like this: good branding is consistent and simple. By separating my blog into multiple blogs, I would make the branding better for each sub-blog. All the things that comprise the complicated brand Giles Bowkett could become simpler brands, and thereby brands which would also be easier to sell. The analogy breaks down a little there, because I'm not really doing any selling per se, but the analog would be readers. Simplify your blog, make it more consistent, and you get more readers. Certainly there are a lot of Ruby-only blogs out there with many more readers than mine. The same is true for music-only blogs and politics-only blogs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What complicates things here is that because my blog has a lot of different topics, the more somebody reads it, the more likely they are to get along with me in person, since somebody who digs Obama and Ruby and dubstep is going to have more in common with me than somebody who loves Obama but hates Ruby (for example). Also, the person who loves Obama but hates Ruby might know me from my blog. If they knew me from a Ruby-only blog, meeting them in person wouldn't be fun. If they know me from a blog where they saw we had some common interests and some differences, then we have something to talk about.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blogs aren't just about marketing. They're also about communication. A lot of things on the Web blur the lines between marketing and conversation, which is inevitable given the &lt;a href="http://www.cluetrain.com/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cluetrain Manifesto&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; idea that markets &lt;i&gt;are&lt;/i&gt; conversations. Sometimes the results are awesome and sometimes &lt;a href="http://www.howtousetwitterformarketingandpr.com/"&gt;not&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/suits.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So far, by keeping my numerous subtopics all under one roof, I'm emphasizing the conversational aspect. It's mostly personal preference. I like to make money, and I like to have fun. These interests often align, but when faced with a choice, I &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2007/11/why-i-program-in-ruby-and-maybe-why-you.html"&gt;choose fun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/bubbles.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There's another question as well. If I'm right, and the blog-filtering problem is a technological problem, then &lt;a href="http://friendfeed.com/"&gt;FriendFeed&lt;/a&gt; is doing it wrong. And not just wrong - &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;exactly&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; wrong. The FriendFeed idea is that you want to know every damn thing your friends are doing on every damn site they use. My idea is that you only want to discuss your common interests with people.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/tao.png"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I'm basically a Taoist, so I believe the real answer here is to seek balance. For some of your friends, if they only use Twitter and Flickr and Facebook, and you're just considering the idea of keeping in touch with real-life people who don't blog about anything boring to you, FriendFeed makes a lot of sense. But for my Internet friends who blog about interesting things, and also Java, or interesting things, and also their pets, I just don't give a shit, so I Just Don't Give A Shit is going to be the way to go.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I hate to say this because in some cases my Internet friends cross over into real-life friends, and some of these pets whose pictures I don't give a shit about, I've actually met, but I don't think their feelings are going to be hurt, because they're animals, and they don't know what Flickr is. Their only opinion on the subject is probably "meow," and they say that no matter what you ask them. They probably just don't give a shit either.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/balls_010809/funny-pictures-cognitive-disonance.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the time being, I'm keeping my blog consolidated, but I really don't know what my final answer will be. Now excuse me. I've got to go shave my balls.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/3528676671923857501?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3528676671923857501'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/my-balls-are-fuzzy-today.html' title='My Balls Are Fuzzy Today'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-7223265905385009461</id><published>2009-01-07T23:12:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-08T12:45:18.192-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-08T12:45:18.192-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>The Fundamental Problem With Libertarianism</title><content type='html'>I was once a Libertarian. I'm not any more.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Libertarian ideas are revolutionary. I've been told that &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leon_Trotsky"&gt;Trotsky&lt;/a&gt; once said "Every revolutionary should &lt;a href="http://alchessmist.blogspot.com/2008/11/political-chess-alekhine-vrs-trostsky.html"&gt;study chess&lt;/a&gt;." Few Libertarians would consider Trotsky's opinion on anything, but Trotsky overthrew a powerful government, so I figure his opinions on revolution are informed opinions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/chess_010709/trotsky.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The best book on chess that Libertarians should read is &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/libertarian-i-can-fix-that.html"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Wrecking Crew&lt;/i&gt; by Thomas Frank&lt;/a&gt;, which left me certain after many years that I was absolutely no Libertarian, and more than that, embarrassed to have ever been one. The book doesn't address Libertarianism directly, and in fact doesn't even do it the courtesy of taking it seriously at all. It's a book about how American conservatives have followed a deliberate strategy of destroying, undermining, and sabotaging the Federal government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They've done so with the support of Libertarian think tanks all over Washington. Republican Presidents and legislators use Libertarian arguments to advance policy decisions which benefit business, then conveniently forget those same arguments when it comes to issues of government debt or unnecessary military spending. They even conveniently forget the arguments when &lt;a href="http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2008/11/libertarian-argument-against-bailout.html"&gt;advancing business interests in ways which contradict every last iota of Libertarian political theory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They forget the arguments because they have no real interest in them; they serve only as justifications. The hypocrisy of politicians is no surprise, but the Libertarian think tanks themselves are complicit in this scam. Frank quotes one of their policy wonks freely confessing that he constructs his reasoning with no concern for intellectual integrity or even internal consistency. The arguments are only a means to an end.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The end, of course, is policy decisions which benefit business. If you think it through, this should be enough to destroy Libertarianism for you. That one domino can crash the whole set.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/5_tXcRYOYZ0&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/5_tXcRYOYZ0&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="480" height="385"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It takes work to achieve political change. You achieve it through violence, volunteerism, and/or money. I'm going to leave out violence, because I think it's pretty obvious that &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/josh-horwitz/is-sarah-palin-mainstream_b_124098.html"&gt;anyone looking for violent revolution to succeed in the United States is just insane&lt;/a&gt;. If you seek a peaceful, non-violent revolution in American politics, your only options are money and volunteerism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There's already a lot of money in Libertarian think tanks; it comes from business. The explosion of dedicated Libertarian volunteerism necessary to transform the United States has yet to materialize, even though &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Whats-Matter-Kansas-Conservatives-America/dp/0805073396"&gt;the Republican Party &lt;i&gt;has&lt;/i&gt; harnessed an explosion of socially conservative volunteerism in the service of the same business interests that benefit from Washington's "Libertarian" bullshit factories&lt;/a&gt;. Money from business interests provides the only real political pressure pushing policy in a Libertarian direction.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This means that if you want to achieve a Libertarian transformation of the United States, your only possible winning strategy is to get as much money from business as possible. But that means that &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;the only way to get government out of business is to get business into government&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. In order to affect this revolutionary change, you would need to leverage a great deal of political momentum from campaign contributions originating with business interests. Then, once you had achieved a Libertarian transformation, you would need all the people with strong ties to business interests, who would owe their political careers to these strong ties, to turn their backs on their business allies. You would need to empower business interests in the political arena, and then prevent them from exercising their power.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If politics were chess, Libertarians would be trying to win by holding up the pawn, saying "my pawn has a machine gun!", and making little pew-pew noises. It just doesn't work that way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/chess_010709/pew_pew_pew.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Update&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;: Couple tweets accused me of knocking over a straw man here.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/straw_010809/lazy.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The fact that some Libertarians don't like the GOP doesn't make a difference. I didn't bother going into detail about that, &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;even though I do acknowledge it in the links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, because it's &lt;i&gt;irrelevant&lt;/i&gt;. If you're going to accuse me setting up straw men, click the links first, please, because you're accusing me of not knowing things I mention; and consider the possibility that you just didn't get the argument in the first place. Seriously, I've got stuff to do today.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/7223265905385009461?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/7223265905385009461'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/fundamental-problem-with-libertarianism.html' title='The Fundamental Problem With Libertarianism'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-7657999129212706280</id><published>2009-01-07T19:02:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-07T19:03:00.800-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-07T19:03:00.800-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Propane: Custom CSS Feature/Hack</title><content type='html'>ENTP developer Trevor Squires released his side project &lt;a href="http://propaneapp.com/"&gt;Propane&lt;/a&gt; today. In addition to its other features, you can hack it to give you custom CSS.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/propane_010709/afro.gif"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I just changed the fonts. I alternate between Gill Sans and Futura. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/mattly/status/1102756612"&gt;Matt Lyon&lt;/a&gt; went a little further.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/propane_010709/mattly.jpg"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There's maybe a proper UI coming for this soon; for now you just edit a CSS file in &lt;code&gt;Application Support&lt;/code&gt;. Both &lt;a href="http://github.com/mattly/helvetichat/tree/master"&gt;Matt's CSS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://github.com/gilesbowkett/propane-theme/tree/master"&gt;mine&lt;/a&gt; are on GitHub. The README in my repo tells you where to put the CSS file.</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/7657999129212706280?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/7657999129212706280'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/propane-custom-css-featurehack.html' title='Propane: Custom CSS Feature/Hack'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry><entry><id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-7602886877359920483.post-3130713595554945449</id><published>2009-01-06T19:56:00.000-08:00</published><updated>2009-01-06T19:57:04.057-08:00</updated><app:edited xmlns:app='http://purl.org/atom/app#'>2009-01-06T19:57:04.057-08:00</app:edited><title type='text'>Truth In Advertizing</title><content type='html'>&lt;img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/giles/advertizing_010609/truth.gif"&gt;</content><link rel='edit' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://www.blogger.com/feeds/7602886877359920483/posts/default/3130713595554945449?v=2'/><link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/feeds/posts/default/3130713595554945449'/><link rel='alternate' type='text/html' href='http://gilesbowkett.blogspot.com/2009/01/truth-in-advertizing.html' title='Truth In Advertizing'/><author><name>Giles Bowkett</name><email>noreply@blogger.com</email></author></entry></feed>