<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
    xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">

    <channel>
    
    <title>Ian Landsman&apos;s Weblog v2.0</title>
    <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/index/</link>
    <description>Starting from Scratch</description>
    <dc:language>en</dc:language>
    <dc:creator>Ian</dc:creator>
    <dc:rights>Copyright 2009</dc:rights>
    <dc:date>2009-01-15T14:02:00-05:00</dc:date>
    <admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://www.pmachine.com/" />
    

    <item>
      <title>.NET and Java Logging</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/net_and_java_logging/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/net_and_java_logging/#When:14:02:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>The Gurock brothers have <a href="http://blog.gurock.com/postings/microisvs-and-microsites-an-experiment/357/">started up</a> two new micro sites about logging, <a href="http://www.dotnetlogging.com/">.NET Logging</a> and <a href="http://www.java-logging.com/">Java Logging</a> in the style of my open source help desk list. Hopefully they&#8217;ll have as much success as I&#8217;ve had with <a href="http://www.opensourcehelpdesklist.com">open source help desk list</a>. If you have a blog go ahead and give them a link and help support our fellow MicroISV&#8217;s.
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2009-01-15T14:02:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Winter Pictures</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/winter_pictures/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/winter_pictures/#When:21:24:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s a few nice winter pictures from the past few days just to change it up. Actually I didn&#8217;t spend a lot of time framing the pictures nicely, but still I think they&#8217;re nice. I could do without that house being there, but I&#8217;d need a bulldozer for that.
</p>
<p>
<p><b>Ice on the Hudson</b>:<br />
<br />
<img src="http://www.userscape.com/blog/images/uploads/DSC_1746.jpg" border="0" alt="image" name="image" width="700" height="465" />
<br />
</p>

<p><b>Sunset</b>:<br />
<br />
<img src="http://www.userscape.com/blog/images/uploads/DSC_1743.jpg" border="0" alt="image" name="image" width="700" height="465" />
<br />
</p>

<p><b>Poughkeepsie at Night</b>:<br />
<br />
<img src="http://www.userscape.com/blog/images/uploads/DSC_0303_2.jpg" border="0" alt="image" name="image" width="700" height="394" />
<br />

</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2009-01-12T21:24:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to Start a MicroISV</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/how_to_start_a_microisv/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/how_to_start_a_microisv/#When:15:26:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Andy with a great quick start guide to <a href="http://successfulsoftware.net/2009/01/05/running-a-microisv/">starting a MicroISV</a>. This covers all that boring stuff nobody covers in their starting a business articles. Well, maybe not <a href="http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/comments/what_they_never_told_you_about_handling_b2b_transactions/">nobody</a>.
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2009-01-05T15:26:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to Compete When All You Do is Solve Problems</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/how_to_compete_when_all_you_do_is_solve_problems/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/how_to_compete_when_all_you_do_is_solve_problems/#When:15:31:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://scobleizer.com/2008/12/28/twitter-idiot-land/">Scoble</a> has an interesting post today. In many ways I think it sums up or represents some of the frustration I&#8217;ve felt working in the tech software world. Getting publicity, links, mentions, any type of reasonable attention when all your product does is solve real world problems is very hard, bordering on impossible. There&#8217;s simple no market any longer for reporting on hard working, profitable companies. 
</p>
<p>
I&#8217;ve thought about this a lot and I don&#8217;t have a really good solution for how to bring the conversation back to our side. Short of building in features or even entire products devoted to just getting attention (and not solving real problems) I&#8217;m not sure what to do. My current thinking though is to try and ride it out. This environment can&#8217;t last forever, hopefully when it changes companies that have kept having good results and making real customers happy will be popular again.
</p>
<p>
On the up side, the impending downturn in 09 could help shake some of this up as there will likely be less ego companies around which should be good news for the rest of us.
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2008-12-28T15:31:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Help Desk Priority Structure</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/help_desk_priority_structure/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/help_desk_priority_structure/#When:17:00:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Over on HelpSpotted: <a href="http://helpspotted.userscape.com/2008/12/15/creating-a-help-desk-priority-structure/">Creating a Help Desk Priority Structure</a>
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2008-12-15T17:00:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>HelpSpot 2.6 Sneak Peek</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/helpspot_26_sneak_peek/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/helpspot_26_sneak_peek/#When:01:18:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re interested in seeing some of the new features in the next HelpSpot release we have a post about it on HelpSpotted. <a href="http://helpspotted.userscape.com/2008/12/10/version-26-sneak-peek/">http://helpspotted.userscape.com/2008/12/10/version-26-sneak-peek/</a>
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2008-12-11T01:18:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>HelpSpotted: The HelpSpot Blog</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/helpspotted_the_helpspot_blog/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/helpspotted_the_helpspot_blog/#When:19:21:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick post to let you know that we&#8217;ve launched <a href="http://helpspotted.userscape.com">HelpSpotted</a>. The official HelpSpot blog. We&#8217;re going to be posting tips, tricks, sneak peeks and more there. We already have a lot of good stuff up so take a look.
</p>
<p>
I&#8217;m also trying to setup a blogroll of HelpSpot customer blogs on the site so if you&#8217;re a customer and have a blog please post your URL on this post: <a href="http://helpspotted.userscape.com/2008/12/10/customer-blogroll/">http://helpspotted.userscape.com/2008/12/10/customer-blogroll/</a>
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2008-12-10T19:21:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Blog Blazers Book Giveaway!</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/blog_blazers_book_giveaway/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/blog_blazers_book_giveaway/#When:16:43:01Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.userscape.com/products/helpspot/">HelpSpot</a> customer and fellow MicroISV <a href="http://www.followsteph.com/">Stephane Grenier</a> just released his work of love, <a href="http://www.blogblazers.com/">Blog Blazers</a>. The book is a series of interviews Stephane conducted with 40 popular bloggers. I&#8217;m honored to be one of the bloggers, though there&#8217;s a lot more talented bloggers than myself in the book including the likes of Seth Godin, Eric Sink, Jeff Atwood, etc.
</p>
<p>
One of the keys to my success if not the primary key has been this blog. While I don&#8217;t write as much as I used to, the early years of UserScape and it&#8217;s success were almost completely dependent on this blog and the traffic it generated. Without this blog I&#8217;d almost certainly be working &#8220;For the Man&#8221;, filed away in some cubical farm. 
</p>
<p>
While blogs are no longer &#8220;new&#8221; as they were when I started, I still think they&#8217;re a key component to any startups business, especially a MicroISV. Now, one problem with blogs is that it&#8217;s often hard to find concise advice on how to blog well. Even just figuring out where to start looking for advice is difficult. Sure there&#8217;s lots of &#8220;how to blog&#8221; links in Google, but few get into the subtle details that make a truly successful blogger. Blog Blazers does just that. If you&#8217;re starting out in blogging or want to grow your blogging presence this book is where to start.
</p>
<p>
Now, Stephane has been kind enough to offer my readers an amazing opportunity. He&#8217;s given me <strong>10</strong> copies of Blog Blazers to give away free on this here blog. I&#8217;ve thought a lot about how I might give these away. I don&#8217;t want to do anything cheesy nor do I have time for a very complicated give away. So here&#8217;s what I&#8217;ve decided:
</p>
<p>
To receive a free copy of Blog Blazers be one of the first 10 people to agree to write up a complete review of Blog Blazers on their own blog. That&#8217;s it. <strong>This is on the honor system</strong>. If you&#8217;re not going to write up a review about it then please don&#8217;t ask for a copy and let someone else have it. You must have a blog to be eligible.
</p>
<p>
If you&#8217;re ready to commit to doing a review then just do the following:
</p>
<p>
* Post a comment below stating you&#8217;d like to review Blog Blazers and include your blog URL
<br />
* Include your real email in the email field
</p>
<p>
I&#8217;ll email the 10 people to get their address information and ship off the books, probably next week.
</p>
<p>
If you have a blog and think your readers might be interested in this giveaway please link them over.
</p>
<p>
Thanks!
</p>
<p>
<strong>Update:</strong> We&#8217;re at 10. Thanks everyone!
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2008-11-19T16:43:01-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Advice for Peldi</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/advice_for_peldi/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/advice_for_peldi/#When:15:38:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>One of the few blogs I create time to read regularly these days is the <a href="http://www.balsamiq.com/blog">Balsamiq Blog</a> by Peldi Guilizzoni. He&#8217;s a MicroISV, his first product is the really cool <a href="http://www.balsamiq.com/">Balsamiq Mockups</a> application which lets you build software mockups quick, easy, and in a fanciful fashion that keeps the focus on UI. So instead of deciding between Aquamarine and Bondi Blue for that button you can figure out if the button should be there at all.
</p>
<p>
Today Peldi had a post every MicroISV dreams of, <a href="http://www.balsamiq.com/blog/?p=424">reaching $100,000 in sales</a>. It&#8217;s a good read and I suggest you read it before you read the rest of my post.
</p>
<p>
So in his post he has a few questions and observations. Since his experience seems to mirror mine very very closely (leaving his job, revenue growth, B2B, fantastic wife that&#8217;s a key part of the company) I thought I&#8217;d post my perspective on some of his questions/comments being 3 years farther down the road than him. So Peldi here&#8217;s some notes, they may or may not be very helpful <img src="http://www.userscape.com/blog/images/smileys/grin.gif" width="19" height="19" alt="grin" style="border:0;" />
</p>
<p>
<strong>Congrats on the success! </strong>
</p>
<p>
<strong>Product Versions</strong>
<br />
I think you&#8217;ve made a great move having the Jira and Confluence versions. I bet they pay off handsomely over time as those customers are likely to upgrade at a high percentage in the future and are also more rich sales initially. My advice here is not to spend too much time on Balsamiq for open source. There&#8217;s very little upside there, especially if the market tightens. It&#8217;s also another version to support long term. Everything you add increases support, don&#8217;t underestimate that. I&#8217;d stick with building versions which are add-ons to existing server products people already pay for. That&#8217;s a great angle, run with it!
</p>
<p>
<strong>Adding Staff</strong>
<br />
No no no. I think it&#8217;s a really bad move to add anyone. $100,000 isn&#8217;t that much money. You can spend that money in much better ways. Before you hire anyone you should do the following (note to self:I need to write this up into a bigger post)
<br />
<ul>
<li>Payoff ALL credit cards</li>
<li>Payoff any student loans</li>
<li>Payoff any personal loans</li>
<li>Buy a house (if you don&#8217;t already own one)</li>
<li>Payoff your cars if possible</li>
<li>Save at least $50,000 in savings, more if possible. Not stock, not an IRA/401K, straight cash in an account.</li>
</ul>
<br />
The point here is you should be improving your personal financial situation. This is not greed, this is good business. Since it costs so little to run a MicroISV your first priority should be making sure you are personally in a very good financial situation. This will ensure that your business will survive should you hit a downturn. If you have no debt you could probably live on just a few thousand dollars a month, you want to make sure that&#8217;s possible.
</p>
<p>
Other benefits of waiting are that you&#8217;ll be very clear about what areas you need to add staff in. It&#8217;s so early for you that you don&#8217;t want to make a bad hire. Also hiring someone greatly increases headaches on multiple fronts. Trust me just dealing with getting health insurance is a multi-week process. These are distractions you don&#8217;t need. 
</p>
<p>
<strong>The &#8220;Oh Crap&#8221; Question (what if you&#8217;re hit by a bus)</strong>
<br />
This question is not a concern. It feels scary, but it really isn&#8217;t a problem. It wasn&#8217;t a problem for me and my application is the type where companies depend completely on it, staff live in it 10 hours a day, all day, all week. Many companies LIKE dealing with a smaller company. This is an advantage, you can provide support on a level larger competitors can only dream about. 
</p>
<p>
Here&#8217;s a few tips:
<br />
<ul>
<li>Emphasize your size as a strength</li>
<li>Superior support (Question, when was the last time a vendor replied to you within an hour?)</li>
<li>Faster release cycles</li>
<li>Direct developer contact means customer feature requests are often implemented and implemented fast</li>
<li>Emphasize the money back guarantee (I assume you have one), this IS the best product of it&#8217;s type on the market and you stand behind it in a way others don&#8217;t.</li>
<li>Your product is successful. If you disappear there will be no shortage of companies looking to purchase the source and continue development</li>
</ul>
<p>
I&#8217;ve found these to be enough, but if you wanted to take it one step further you could also provide an agreement that you&#8217;ll be releasing the source code in full should you be hit by a bus. You&#8217;d want a lawyer to do this since you wouldn&#8217;t want it to apply once you reached a certain size, etc.
</p>
<p>
You said everything you need to know about this in your post: &#8220;I don’t really feel like I have reached my limits in terms of how much I can do by myself&#8221;. Until you are there&#8217;s nothing more to discuss. You shouldn&#8217;t add staff until you are working crazy hours, until you are going crazy, until you are in a great financial position to ensure the survival of the company. This is the best way to support your customers. 90% of small business go out of business. You&#8217;re much more likely to leave them high and dry because you go out of business than because you get hit by a bus. That needs to be your primary concern.
</p>
<p>
<strong>Investors</strong>
<br />
Under no circumstances should you take money!! I&#8217;m glad to hear you don&#8217;t want to. You&#8217;ve proved the concept and now make enough to live comfortably. That&#8217;s it, there&#8217;s no reason you need one penny at this point. You&#8217;ve taken all the risk and it&#8217;s paid off. No need to let someone else in now that you&#8217;ve proven the product.
</p>
<p>
That&#8217;s my 2 cents. Hopefully it&#8217;s been useful. Keep up the great work and interesting blog!
</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2008-11-14T15:38:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Are you Hiring? I&#8217;ve Got Your Man</title>
      <link>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/are_you_hiring_ive_got_your_man/</link>
      <guid>http://www.userscape.com/blog/index.php/site/are_you_hiring_ive_got_your_man/#When:19:22:00Z</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>My friend Kevin Dangoor recently lost his position at a technology company in Michigan. He&#8217;s looking for new opportunities that can make use of both his project management and development skills. If you&#8217;re in the Python community you might already know Kevin from the popular <a href="http://www.turbogears.org/">TurboGears</a> framework he created. If you or someone you know is hiring please look him up. You can get more details on his background and his contact information here:
</p>
<p>
<a href="http://www.blueskyonmars.com/2008/10/29/in-the-market-for-a-job/">http://www.blueskyonmars.com/2008/10/29/in-the-market-for-a-job/</a>
<br />

</p>]]></description>
      <dc:subject>General</dc:subject>
      <dc:date>2008-10-29T19:22:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>

    
    </channel></rss>