<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl" type="text/xsl" media="screen"?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css" type="text/css" media="screen"?><rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>Information Arbitrage</title><link>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/</link><description>A Wall Streeter's Ride into the Wild, Wild Web
by Roger Ehrenberg</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 09:50:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><generator>TypePad http://www.typepad.com/</generator><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/InformationArbitrage" type="application/rss+xml" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>428659</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://www.feedburner.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item><title>Nationalization Isn't a Dirty Word</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/519929575/the-us-banking-sector-needs-a-restart.html</link><category>Current Affairs</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 09:50:35 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61751060</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The time has come to acknowledge the depths of our problems. It has already been demonstrated that propping up failing institutions does nothing but delay the inevitable. It consumes staggering sums, it wastes time, and it prolongs what will invariably prove to be one of the sharpest economic downturns in generations. A downturn that originated not in the real economy, but in the financial economy. The credit bubble fueled the housing bubble, shortly after the stock market bubble had been pricked. Easy money plus poor regulatory constructs with a touch of fraud was just what was needed to bring down the system. Sadly, many companies and industries have been effected that had nothing to do with and extracted little benefit from the financial bubble. So while our financial institutions are getting their comeuppance, the rest of the economy is being dragged down with them. It is just wrong, simply not fair, but it highlights the importance and interconnectedness of our financial institutions with the other engines of our economy. Without a healthy financial sector, the real economy simply cannot flourish. </p><p>Today we are lost. Our leaders are wandering around, trying to address the problems in a patchwork manner. Pork abounds. None other than Barney Frank, head of the House Financial Services Committee, <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123258284337504295.html">used his position</a> to extract funds for a small institution in his home state.  As long as the rescue plan is administered in this manner more money will be wasted, confidence will be destroyed and little progress will be made in helping get our financial sector - and, therefore, the rest of our economy - back on its feet. The time has come for a change.</p><p>The answer lies in the complete takeover of sick institutions. Call it nationalization, call it what you will, but it is the most expedient, most cost efficient and ultimately least disruptive way to accomplish what needs to be done. The goal is not to have huge swaths of the US financial sector owned and controlled by the Government. They are particularly bad operators and skew market forces, and should be viewed as a catalyst, as a stop-gap to address the current crisis. Fact is, they are the only institution with a large enough balance sheet and the power to jump-start the healing process, which means segregating illiquid assets (Bad Bank) from performing, liquid assets (Good Bank), warehousing and working out the Bad while selling off or spinning out the Good. While this would wipe out the common equity and much of the debt of sick institutions, it would end the charade that there is any real equity and debt value left in many of them, save for the largesse bestowed upon them by Treasury via TARP. Time to end the largesse and the pork and to get on with the hard work of really solving the financial sector's problems.</p><p>The newly-created Good banks will have clean balance sheets, rational capital structures and be open for business. They will be able to lend money without fear that they'd be better off saving it, and will make rational lending decisions without Government intervention. A group of healthy banks in a sick economy does not mean that lending will all of a sudden take off. The prudent banker will only invest when risk-adjusted returns are sufficiently attractive. But those healthy companies that have been squeezed by the credit crisis will now have access to better-priced capital, and will have a range of institutions offering competitive rates from which to choose. This condition does not exist today because of the fear across the banking sector. Unfortunately, only the Government can take away this fear by using its balance sheet as a bridge to clean things up. But rather than squandering taxpayer dollars by "insuring" the walking-dead banks of today against portfolio losses, the money would be better spent marking bad assets down, letting the US taxpayer pay a depressed price, creating optionality by warehousing them on the Fed's balance sheet and selling them after the credit market dislocation has abated.</p><p>What this really amounts to is a virtual restart of the US banking sector. Mistakes have been made on a scale too massive to imagine, and it is up to us to deal with these mistakes thorugh a combination of decisive action and sensible regulatory changes. But let's not get too hung up on terminology; there is work to be done.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=hTRDcR.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=hTRDcR.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=YFqjuV.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=YFqjuV.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=tfIVOA.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=tfIVOA.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=npEaLo.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=npEaLo.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=JvNF9W.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=JvNF9W.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/519929575" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The time has come to acknowledge the depths of our problems. It has already been demonstrated that propping up failing institutions does nothing but delay the inevitable. It consumes staggering sums, it wastes time, and it prolongs what will invariably...</description><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/the-us-banking-sector-needs-a-restart.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>It's Not About Hope</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/518762572/its-not-about-hope.html</link><category>Current Affairs</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 09:00:08 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61702824</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>Like most, I watched yesterday's Inaugural festivities with interest, less in the pomp and pageantry and more in the messaging from our new President. While I don't think it will go down as among the most memorable and quotable of addresses, it was blunt, honest and grounded. But let's be clear; notwithstanding the positive sentiment around Obama's taking the reins, and the hope associated with his plans, his achievements will be based on policy decisions and <strong>not</strong> on hope. And while sentiment will play a role in our recovery, it will not be the driver of a rebound. Changes in sentiment that impact people's financial behaviors will come from real changes in our Federal Government, the economy, and the health of our financial institutions and local governments. And these changes will only happen if Obama is willing and able to make the hard decisions necessary, such as:</p><ol>
<li>Aggressively taking over failing banks, recapitalizing the healthy parts with public and private capital and working out the rest over time;</li>
<li>Providing a mix of tax incentives and public funds for upgrading our technology infrastructure;</li>
<li>Using tax policy and access to our National labs and Universities to unlock trapped intellectual property that can be used for innovation;</li>
<li>Developing a durable solution to the morass that is Social Security;</li>
<li>Constructing a plan for re-invigorating public education, using market-based methods and vouchers to create a culture of high achievement that is accessible to all; and</li>
<li>Investing in re-training displaced workers from dying industries to make them productive, fulfilled and able to secure a healthy future for themselves and their families.</li>
</ol>
<p>None of these things are easy and require broad-based, bipartisan support for passage. But for the Obama Administration to be truly successful, he will have to take on these massive, mutli-generational problems. While it is easy to say that the hand he's been dealt is not fair, and that bar for what constitutes success has been set too high, he has been handed an historic opportunity to restructure key elements of a badly broken system. </p><p>As is my wont to use derivative metaphors, the Obama Administration is not unlike a very valuable at-the-money option. The question is, will he reward the call buyers or the put buyers? Because my hunch is that option sellers will be the losers here; something explosive will happen. The question is in which direction.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=27CG32.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=27CG32.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=oYiLid.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=oYiLid.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=biYsKc.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=biYsKc.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=cwvoaP.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=cwvoaP.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=RP0Agv.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=RP0Agv.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/518762572" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Like most, I watched yesterday's Inaugural festivities with interest, less in the pomp and pageantry and more in the messaging from our new President. While I don't think it will go down as among the most memorable and quotable of...</description><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/its-not-about-hope.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Obama's Big Chance</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/513635823/obamas-big-chance.html</link><category>Current Affairs</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 08:42:55 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61431862</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Albeit reluctantly, <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=20601087&amp;sid=aoqgF6jqDIPI&amp;refer=home">the Senate gave the go-ahead</a> to release the additional $350 billion in TARP funding contemplated by the original plan. A 52-42 vote isn't exactly a resounding vote of confidence, but who can blame the Senators for their cynicism given the manner in which the first $350 billion was disbursed and the utter lack of tracking and accountability? The representative case for support was articulated by Senator Richard Durbin:</p> <blockquote><p>“It’s money that can be spent, may be spent, by the new president, Barack Obama&nbsp;,” Illinois Democrat Richard Durbin&nbsp;&nbsp;said before the vote. “I want to give President Obama the tools he needs to breathe life back into this economy.”</p></blockquote>
<p>To his credit, President-elect Obama acknowledged that this vote was a struggle because of the widespread displeasure over the handling of TARP I:<blockquote><p>“I know this wasn’t an easy vote because of the frustration so many of us share about how the first half of this plan was implemented,” Obama said in a statement. He promised to set strict pay limits on executives at companies receiving funds, provide more loans to small businesses and ensure “taxpayers can see where their money is spent.”</p></blockquote><p> The question is, will Obama yield to populist rhetoric and Congressional photo-ops or will he do the ugly work that needs to be done? What worries me are <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123205759811587287.html?mod=testMod">intentions such as these</a>:</p><blockquote><p>To overcome political objections, the incoming Obama administration
pledged to spend $50 billion to $100 billion on a "sweeping"
foreclosure-prevention effort. It also said it would impose tougher
restrictions on banks that receive government aid, including
requirements on banks to lend money, increased restrictions on
executive compensation and curtailed dividend payments for some firms.</p></blockquote><p>I'm not sure what a "sweeping foreclosure-prevention effort" is, but it worries me. Requirements for banks to lend money? A really, really bad idea. While some of the badness that happened over the past 5-7 years led to distorted markets, e.g., abnormally cheap credit, instruments that received high ratings inconsistent with their risks, fraudulent loan origination practices, etc., coming in and distorting them further is not a recipe for a healthy recovery. Plenty of people directly and indirectly hold mortgages that were originated in an honest manner but whose payers either can't or don't want to service their debt. Should they be penalized because the servicer wants to foreclose and/or the payer no longer wants to fulfill an obligation on a house with no remaining equity? The incentives are perverse, and the ripple effects of a wholesale mortgage restructuring project would be far-reaching and re-distribute wealth in potentially unfair and inappropriate ways. </p><p>Forcing banks to lend couldn' be a more intellectually bankrupt idea. The business of commercial banks is to lend money when the risk-adjusted returns exceed its cost of capital. Just lend money, because we said so? We've seen this movie before - it's called <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/07/banking-sector.html">Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac</a> - and it doesn't end well. The right way to approach the problem is to create truly healthy banks, either out of currently sick institutions or de novo, and to let them make rational lending decisions. If the Government sees a particular constituency that requires funding, don't force a bank to do it if it doesn't make economic sense. Either create a discrete program or use tax incentives to generate the necessary resources. The worst possible outcome of TARP is to create another generation of sick institutions by forcing them to make irrational loans to satisfy the moral (or public relations) objectives of our Government representatives. Obama needs to fight this urge with a vengance.</p><p>Then there is the issue of using TARP for non-financial sector problems - like the auto industry. In order to ensure support from the Senate, Larry Summers, the future head of the National Economic Council, made the following remarks:</p> <blockquote><p>In a nod to concerns about how the bailout has expanded beyond
financial firms to include the U.S. car business, Mr. Summers said the
second half of the funds would be used to help prevent "systemic
consequences in the financial and housing markets," not to implement an
"industrial policy" that would aid various troubled industries. To
assuage Republican concerns, the Obama team also agreed to provide
additional support to the auto industry only "in the context of a
comprehensive restructuring."</p></blockquote><p>This is good news. There is TARP and there is industrial policy, and there is good industrial policy and bad. <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/some-thoughts-on-the-markets-and-politics.html">Lobbing cash into a sick auto industry</a> without a comprehensive approach to the problem is bad policy. Bad like TARP has been bad, providing sick institutions with cash without fundamental changes in their businesses, management, or the promise of an appropriate risk-adjusted return. Fortunately Mr. Summers is smart enough to know this, and he will hopefully keep Obama from veering off course. </p><p>How Obama handles the financial crisis over the next 180 days will set the tone for his entire Administration. He needs to be a strong, pragmatic, independent thinker who refuses to be swayed by headlines or popularity contests. He needs to earn the respect - not the love - of the US citizenry. This means making decisions for the long-term good of the country, even if it means incurring excruciating short-term pain. Palliatives are the easy way out; set rates to zero, pump additional trillions of liquidity into the economy, restructure all non-performing mortgages of people below a certain income threshold, bail out dying industries that employ hundreds of thousands of workers, support local public-works projects, and watch our country slide by on his watch and then absolutely crater after he leaves office. Many would choose this course because, well, it doesn't require much imagination or tolerance for pain. But it is the wrong thing to do. </p><p>Obama has the potential to be the most impactful President in generations if only he has the intestinal fortitude to do the hard work and to make the hard decisions required. Forces will conspire to push him off this path. He must resist them. </p>
</div>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=HWAmA4.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=HWAmA4.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=dweH93.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=dweH93.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=3vwB8n.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=3vwB8n.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=K0SC47.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=K0SC47.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=2HUbB0.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=2HUbB0.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/513635823" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>Albeit reluctantly, the Senate gave the go-ahead to release the additional $350 billion in TARP funding contemplated by the original plan. A 52-42 vote isn't exactly a resounding vote of confidence, but who can blame the Senators for their cynicism...</description><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/obamas-big-chance.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>SOC or Bust</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/512456868/soc-or-bust.html</link><category>Current Affairs</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2009 19:55:53 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61335418</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>With the implosion of Citigroup and the depth of losses across the
banking sector, including today's announcement that Bank of America is seeking additional bailout funding, the time has come to create and empower the
<a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/12/fresh-voices-needed-fixing-the-financial-system.html">Stabilization Oversight Council (SOC)</a>. The Treasury, positioned as the
only game in town with respect to policy-making to deal with the
financial crisis, has come up way, way short. While they need to have a
seat at the table, other voices need to be heard as well. And not in a
one-off, haphazard way, as has been done since the beginning of the crisis, e.g., the Treasury administers TARP, the FDIC
drives the mortgage-restructuring strategy, the White House intervenes on behalf of the automakers, the Fed wrings their hands
in public but to little effect, etc.. The SOC will take a holistic approach
to the problem, working to develop solutions that fit together, are
sequenced properly, and are both clearly communicated and transparent
in their elements and their monitoring. A clean slate is needed, and
I'd recommend that it be created <strong>before</strong> the next $350 billion
is pushed out the door. Because if this $350 billion is used in a
manner similar to the previous $350 billion, the taxpayer rip-off and
policy failures will place an unacceptable and unnecessary burden on
<a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/12/the-us-is-at-a-strategic-inflection-point-with-the-opportunity-to-re-assume-global-leadership-on-both-diplomatic-and-e.html">subsequent generations</a>.<br>
</p><p>While it is seductive to spend stimulus dollars on
infrastructure, the auto industry, and every other constituency that
has come out of the woodwork with their hands out, <strong>priority number one</strong>
has to be a plan for <strong>fixing the financial services sector</strong>.This extends well beyond fixing balance sheets, thought this certainly needs to happen (via takeover and <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/we-the-people-good-bank-bad-bank-our-bank.html">Good Bank/Bad Bank</a> restructuring of failing institutions), and includes items such as:</p><ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Simplified and clarified accounting standards</span>: Mark-to-market accounting treatment on all trading portfolios not supported by term financing. Tightening of consolidation rules to prevent the shunting of risk into off-balance sheet vehicles with opaque disclosures. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Key themes</span>: transparency and full disclosure. </li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Revised regulatory standards</span>: Revised capital requirements that are detached from Value at Risk (VaR) and calibrated to the business cycle, e.g. higher capital/larger reserves in good times, lower capital/smaller reserves in bad times. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Key themes</span>: capital requirements that take into account asymmetrical risk distributions, built-in shock absorbers to force capital accumulation while it is plentiful to prepare for inevitable turns in the business cycle.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: bold;">Restructuring of the ratings industry</span>: Eliminate the inherent conflicts in issuer-funded ratings. Create an independent and impartial body to issue and maintain ratings, partially funded by the deal. Key themes: independence, transparency, free from bias, paid for as an implicit due diligence expense by investors.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is not about bailing out undeserving bankers; they will be fired, their stock wiped out. This isn't about creating another real estate bubble; it will take years for existing inventory to be worked through, partially-built homes to be finished and sold and current sellers to find buyers at anything other than distressed prices. This is about getting the US to face into its problems, to swallow an expensive, bitter pill and to move on. But we can't move on with a financial system in shambles. We can't restructure the auto industry, make necessary investments in technology infrastructure and enact effective tax policy in the absence of healthy, functioning credit markets.</p><p>Another key element of the plan is creating a culture of transparency, honesty and responsibility, three items sorely lacking as evidenced by reasons for and magnitude of the credit crisis. While cynics may scoff, I don't see the presence of these things as being anathema to making money or supporting the free markets. To the contrary, I believe they can usher in a healthier, more sustainable investment climate, one where investors and individuals alike will have more realistic expectations of returns and reduced volatility due to fewer unpleasant surprises.</p><p>The time has come for a change. TARP hasn't worked. The banking crisis has only deepened. We need the best minds from relevant disciplines to build a comprehensive plan for stabilizing the financial system. Perhaps <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/07/an-open-letter.html">President Elect Obama</a> can use his energy and fresh perspective to taken an unconventional approach to solving our problems. He can be the catalyst; he is not the answer. The SOC is the answer. </p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=vv0f7M.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=vv0f7M.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=sIzME1.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=sIzME1.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=IVbMaf.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=IVbMaf.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=U44Io9.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=U44Io9.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=b0eGa8.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=b0eGa8.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/512456868" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>With the implosion of Citigroup and the depth of losses across the banking sector, including today's announcement that Bank of America is seeking additional bailout funding, the time has come to create and empower the Stabilization Oversight Council (SOC). The...</description><category domain="http://rss.financialcontent.com/stocksymbol">SOC</category><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/soc-or-bust.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Citigroup - Somebody Please Say "Game Over"</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/511271676/citigroup-somebody-please-say-game-over.html</link><category>Wall Street</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 16:57:30 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61294536</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>From the <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123185686674677225.html?mod=djemTEW">Wall Street Journal Online</a>:</p><p style="margin-left: 40px;">Until recently, Citigroup Chief Executive Vikram Pandit had
repeatedly backed the company's "universal bank" model. But with
directors and executives now bracing for a fourth-quarter operating
loss of at least $10 billion and federal officials worried about
previous turnaround efforts, Citigroup has decided that more dramatic
action is needed, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>
<p style="margin-left: 40px;">Shrinking Citigroup won't be quick or easy. The company is assigning
management teams to handle the gradual disposal of units and other
assets, but a person familiar with the matter emphasized that Citigroup
doesn't plan to engage in a "fire sale." Efforts to find buyers also
will be complicated by rocky market conditions and the recession.</p>
<p style="margin-left: 40px;">Citigroup already has pursued some pieces of its downsizing push.
For example, executives have been trying for months to reduce its
exposure to Japan, where rising defaults are hurting profits. Citigroup
also has been searching for about a year to find a buyer for Primerica,
which sells mutual funds, insurance and other financial products.</p>
<p style="margin-left: 40px;">That auction hasn't resulted in a sale because of a scarcity of
buyers willing to pay what Citigroup regards as a reasonable price,
according to people familiar with the matter.  </p>
<p style="margin-left: 40px;">As part of the new plan, Citigroup executives are considering the
possibility of creating what is known as a "good bank-bad bank"
structure, these people said. Under that structure, Citigroup would
create a new corporate entity to house what it regards as its core
businesses.</p>
<p style="margin-left: 40px;">The "bad bank" would hold around $700 billion in assets, with the
remaining $1.1 trillion considered core. The entity would face
accounting-related complications, and Citigroup hasn't settled on the
approach, people familiar with the discussions said.</p><p>It is hard to articulate the contempt I have for the Treasury surrounding their handling of the Citigroup situation. Is it any surprise we (the US Taxpayer, that is) now find ourselves in this position? You can't blame Vikram, Win and the stellar board for sitting back and letting the Government throw money at them in a panic without addressing the core issues at hand: namely, erosion of both on- and off-balance sheet asset values together with difficulty in funding these assets. </p><p>What if, just what if, Treasury (together with the SEC) had said four months ago - game over, guys. Employ FAS 157 across your asset portfolios, show us exactly how broke you are, hand us the keys, we'll settle accounts with those who are owed money and say too bad to those who aren't (common stockholders and unsecured debtholders), sell of the good assets and warehouse the bad at marked-down levels. The Government could have worked out illiquid derivatives positions over time without causing a market cataclysm. Oh, and Management and the Board, don't let the doorknob hit you in the butt on your way out. You'll be hearing from a few lawyers any day now. These decisive actions would have saved taxpayers tens if not hundreds of billions of dollars, yet we still have the good ol' Citi management at the helm steering the ship. It's almost like the Madoff situation; he's dead, yet somehow he's still sending millions jewelry to his friends and family. He should be in the clink. And Citigroup Management should be on the street. </p><p>Why is legacy Management getting to decide how and when to dispose of assets on our dime? The firm is bankruput save for Treasury's largesse. Someone needs to say game over - now - that has the best interests of the US Taxpayers and the financial markets in mind. Because up to this point, it is not clear that anyone has been looking out for these two key constituencies.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=yepgBX.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=yepgBX.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=HqOPvQ.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=HqOPvQ.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=A1guEW.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=A1guEW.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=YeD7bu.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=YeD7bu.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=p3Q5kg.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=p3Q5kg.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/511271676" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>From the Wall Street Journal Online:Until recently, Citigroup Chief Executive Vikram Pandit had repeatedly backed the company's "universal bank" model. But with directors and executives now bracing for a fourth-quarter operating loss of at least $10 billion and federal officials...</description><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/citigroup-somebody-please-say-game-over.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The Citi Never Sleeps - Only its Board, Risk Managers and Regulators</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/509991958/the-citi-never-sleeps-only-its-board-risk-managers-and-regulators.html</link><category>Wall Street</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 11:30:00 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61230416</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The Citigroup of the past decade is THE shining example of an array of costly failures: accounting policies; business strategies; management compensation schemes; risk management practices; and Government policies. And now we see that <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123172133334572421.html?mod=djemITP">Citigroup is doing badly</a>; more badly, in fact, than many thought likely. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/01/10/business/10rubin.html?_r=1&amp;dlbk">Rubin is out</a>. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/aponline/2009/01/11/business/AP-Banks-Outlook.html?dlbk">Smith Barney is being jettisoned</a> for a little cash and some accounting profits. Desperation is taking hold. Will more bailout funds be required, notwithstanding the egregious deal the second-time around? You can bet on it. We are now seeing the sequel to the original Citigroup drama, <em>As the Stomach Turns</em>.</p><p><strong>Accounting Policies</strong></p><p>First, there was the Sandy Weill empire-building phase. In short, accounting standards gone awry. Because of the "pooling method" of accounting for mergers, Sandy was able to bolt on enterprise after enterprise by doing stock deals that met the necessary criteria. This resulted in effectively slapping together two sets of historical financial statements without showing the "goodwill" (premium paid over tangible book value) paid for in the deal. And because there were no charges to earnings for the amortization of goodwill, Citigroup could defer the time when it needed to come clean that it had paid too much for acquisitions and that the goodwill didn't really exist. Happy for Sandy, his largest deals (Primerica/Travelers and Travelers/Citicorp) were
done prior to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Purchase_price_allocation">the end of the pooling method</a> pursuant to FAS 141
and 142. Surprise, common shareholders! We paid tens of billions too much for the businesses we bought. But the joke is on you. To even greater effect, Citigroup availed itself of a juicy 21st century accounting fiction, Special Purpose Vehicle (SPV) accounting, that laid the foundation for its cataclysmic collapse over the past 18 months.</p><p><strong>Business Strategies</strong></p><p>Sandy figured out something truly brilliant: by growing so large he created a firm that was <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/playing-chicken-with-citigroup.html">"too big to fail,"</a> but just big enough to get paid outsized sums for facilitating its growth-by-acquisition strategy. Get paid on the upside and bailed out on the downside. Whether it was simple greed or an amalgam of greed and market prescience, his strategy worked beautifully. He got paid princely sums while the firm was in rapid growth mode and got out near the top, his minions - and the US taxpayer - were left to deal with the detritus after-the-fact. This may have been his most brilliant business deal of all; working with his Board to get paid for high-risk, ultimtely transient earnings and bailing out at just the right time. Has anybody showed such skill at market timing? Nice work, Sandy. Further, his approach was also <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/04/breaking-up-is.html">deeply flawed from a corporate finance perspective</a>. With few realizable synergies among his portfolio of businesses, it would have been more efficient and created greater shareholder value by having these businesses as stand-alone entities. They would be been more focused, properly financed, received the necessary managerial oversight and attracted the best investors for their particular business activity. Asset allocation is always done best at the investor level; corporate managers only have an incentive to get big, and the friction and distraction associated with managing a disparate array of businesses is costly for both shareholders and the businesses alike.</p><p><strong>Compensation Practices</strong></p><p>Grow the numerator (revenues), avoid charges to the denominator (goodwill), take more risk and back up the compensation truck at year-end. It really wasn't that complicated. Conglomerators for decades have played a similar game and made away with monstrous rewards for their era. It is only that so much had been written about pooling and its being an accounting fiction that Boards and HR departments should have been hip to the game by the late 1990s. This, together for paying for short-term results, particularly in its trading businesses, contributed to a compensation culture that was skewed towards all the wrong things - top line growth without an approriate discount for risk and persistence. Not smart, guys.</p><p><strong>Risk Management Practices</strong></p><p>When the intellectual purity of Jamie Dimon was still at hand, he sharply reduced Citigroup's exposure to Russia - and fast. He closed down the Risk Arbitrage group at Salomon. He was laser-focused on the risk side of the equation. Once he left, <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/02/citigroups-mode.html">nobody stepped in to fill the void</a> (except that LTCM guy). It decided to crank up the securitization machine and to play accounting gimmickry, circa 2004: the SPV game. It pushed hundreds of billions of dollars of CDO exposure off-balance sheet, meeting the accounting critieria for de-consolidation while retaining enough risk to have the assets come flying back onto its books if certain "unlikely" things happened. Well, they did and they did, and these SPVs, which enabled Citigroup to present financial statements and footnotes that drastically understated its real exposure, were the key contributor to its undoing. While this was certainly an accounting game, it was also a severe breakdown in risk controls because regardless of where these assets were housed, Citigroup retained real economic exposure to their performance. And Citigroups risk management team, without question, fell down when it came to taking these SPV risks into account. </p><p><strong>Government Policies</strong></p><p>While Sandy set the table, Hank and Friends have been trying to clean it up, without much success. First a $25 billion injection, no strings attached. Then a massive backstop deal whose cost is currently unknown, but is many multiples of the original staggeringly large cash injection. Yet the problems still remain. Why? Because the Treasury has been reluctant, for some reason, to get tough with Citigroup's management and to clean house once and for all. <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/we-the-people-good-bank-bad-bank-our-bank.html">Take over the firm. Employ a good bank/bad bank strategy. </a>Force <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/10/building-a-solid-foundation-for-free-markets-let-the-healing-begin.html">mark-to-market accounting</a> across the banking sector and see exactly which institutions are the walking dead, which are broken but can be repaired and which are a.o.k. Develop a consistent plan. Execute the plan. Stop with the one-off, band-aid solutions. <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/some-thoughts-on-the-markets-and-politics.html">Citigroup needs a redo, just like the auto industry.</a> And just like Social Security. Wipe out common and junior debt holders. Sell off good assets to the private sector or spin them off. Warehouse bad assets and work them out over time. But Sandy was right; shareholders and the Government permitted Citigroup to become too big to fail. Well, it needs to fail. Just not in the haphazard, destructive way that Lehman failed. It can be done much, much better.</p><p>Someone needs to take Citigroup out behind the barn and shoot it. Because if we don't, it just may kill us in the process.  </p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=SHNagE.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=SHNagE.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=hvd6Cm.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=hvd6Cm.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=2H9JNt.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=2H9JNt.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=SWb56p.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=SWb56p.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=fQU27P.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=fQU27P.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/509991958" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The Citigroup of the past decade is THE shining example of an array of costly failures: accounting policies; business strategies; management compensation schemes; risk management practices; and Government policies. And now we see that Citigroup is doing badly; more badly,...</description><category domain="http://rss.financialcontent.com/stocksymbol">SPV</category><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/the-citi-never-sleeps-only-its-board-risk-managers-and-regulators.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Wall Street, Circa 2010: Disaggregation and Specialization</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/508141804/wall-street-circa-2010.html</link><category>Wall Street</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2009 09:25:58 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61139738</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>The Wall Street of today is almost unrecognizable from that at which I worked for almost two decades. The rise of the trading culture, first brought into the mainstream by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Gutfreund">John Gutfreund</a> and Salomon Brothers in the 1980s and which lasted for more than 20 years, is now a vestige of the past. Huge trading losses have been posted. Risk limits have been taken down. "Structured Product" is now a dirty word. Securitization? Don't want to hear about it. Asset-backed what? Sell - sell now! What started as a way to manage risk and to parse it out to those best positioned to bear it - the mortgage-backed security - evolved into something that lost its raison d'etre. The course of increasing complexity and distance from its intended goal, risk management, was a key contributor to the financial crisis we are encountering today. Much has been written about the "why" of Wall Street's demise, but I'd like to consider a slightly different question: <span style="font-weight: bold;">What now?</span> What does a functional Wall Street of tomorrow look like? What businesses does it choose to be in? Where and how can it bring value to clients, both issuers and investors, in ways that are logical, straightforward, transparent, and consistent with its objective to increase its own shareholder value?</p><div><span style="font-weight: bold;">Industry structure: Disaggregation and Specialization<br></span></div><br><div>What used to be the bulge bracket Wall Street firms and their international peers had become financial supermarkets. Securities trading and issuance. Corporate advisory services. Asset management. Retail brokerage. Even insurance. In essence, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sandy_Weill">Sandy Weill</a> model of the one-stop financial enterprise. This model was doomed from the get-go and the financial crisis will only hasten its demise. The concept of internally diversifying cash flows by seeking to operate a pile of loosely-related businesses under one roof never made sense, theoretically or otherwise. And yesterday's announcement that <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123152743795268785.html?mod=testMod">Citigroup is looking to unload Smith Barney</a> only reinforces the point - although Morgan Stanley clearly has a different view of things. <strong><br></strong></div><br><div><span style="font-weight: bold;">Disaggregation of Securities Dealers and Equity Research</span></div><br><div><strong>Securities Dealers</strong>, those that help companies issue capital and to make markets in those and other securities, will continue do this. One related businesses will be bundled with securities dealers: Investment Banking. Issuers need advice on how and when to issue, and may also want M&amp;A advice: Investment Bankers will continue to provide this service. The difference between how it used to work and how it will work in the future is the <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/03/some-updated-th.html">disaggregation of Equity Research</a>. The major securities houses will have global distribution platforms for connecting issuers and investors, and to provide markets on a worldwide basis. There will be relatively few of these players as the cost of maintaining a global distribution platform is huge and, in my opinion, <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/09/investing-20.html">a natural oligopoly</a>. But research will be "open sourced," as the charade sometimes called "Wall Street single-stock research" is finally exposed. </div><br><div>Having the securities underwriter issue a "puff piece" as part of the IPO selling process is a waste of time, money and is fraught with conflicts. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Settlement">Global Settlement</a> was just that - a settlement. It wasn't a solution. There only reason for bulge bracket firms to pay for costly research operations is if they help Investment Banking land deals. Bulge bracket research budgets in the early 2000s were in the $500 million to $1 billion+ range. If one were to disaggregate commissions into payment for research and execution, it is safe to say that investors attributed little value to Wall Street research. So how did the gap get filled? Investment banking mandates, together with outsized commissions on "hot" IPO deals that precipitated the Global Settlement in the first place. Transparency will enter the research venue, where investors buy research from the best providers at a known cost. There is no reason why a securities dealer should have better research than anyone else, and given that this is not their area of specialization it isn't clear that they should be in this business at all. Added complexity is almost always a bad thing, and securities dealers have enough to manage without operating a separate research arm. </div><br><div><span style="font-weight: bold;">Disaggregation of Securities Dealers and Commercial Banking</span></div><br><div>A solid idea in concept, but fraught with conflict and potential magnification of risks. Seems logical from the Wall Street perspective; let's simply migrate up the right hand side of the balance sheet, providing everything from bank loans to term debt to mezzanine, convertibles to preferreds to common stock. The problem is, however, that bank debt and bridge loans were used as levers to secure other, higher margin pieces of business such as IPOs, M&amp;A, junk bonds and derivatives. So what you'd get are a bunch of very smart, very aggressive, very crafty, super-money motivated product specialists pressuring the commercial bankers to make loans whether they liked them or not. "It's for the good of the (firm) relationship" was the siren's song. What they really meant to say was "It's for the good of my P&amp;L (and the basis for my year-end bonus)". This is clearly not the best way to manage risk or allocate capital.<br><br>The risks borne by securities dealers - market risks - are fundamentally different than those absorbed by commercial bankers - credit risks. This is why large financial firms have two discrete risk hierarchies governing these distinct exposures. However, if one takes the evolution of the markets to the limit, then market risk and credit risk effectively intersect, e.g., a company's debt is as liquid as its stock and every slice of the right hand side of the balance sheet is listed and tradable. In this case a company's credit risk would be priced, in real time, by the market, and one could assess the appropriateness of the risk/reward trade-offs embedded in each security. Arbitrage would keep the relationships efficient. This is what capital arbitrage trading strategies seek to do today, but by using a mix of liquid (listed equities) and less liquid (credit derivatives, bonds and bank loans) assets. But the time when credit and market risks intersect is a ways off, and building integrated platforms predicated upon this condition that are laden with conflicts results in a flawed business model.<br><br><strong>Disaggreation of Securities Dealers and Retail Brokerage</strong><br>
<br>
The bundling of retail brokerage and securities was a mistake of both
scale and conflicts of interests: scale because the entities are simply
too big and the cultures to different to manage, and there are few
natural synergies between the two businesses; and conflicts because
retail brokers are more heavily compensated to push proprietary
in-house products than third-party products, resulting in advice to
clients that is biased, at odds with the fiduciary responsibility
brokers have to their clients. How can Morgan Stanely resolve this
conflict? They can't. A combined Smith Barney/Morgan Stanley retail
brokerage operation will be a prime candidate for spin-off when the IPO
market recovers. The integrated financial enterprise resulted in a
broken system; the crisis will provide the impetus to fix it. <br><br><strong>Disaggregation of Securities Dealers and Proprietary Trading</strong><br><br>Wall Street firms generally have several pools of trading risk, some of which are customer-related and others which are purely proprietary. Being in the securities business means taking market risk. Firms will underwrite deals, buy positions from customers without having the other side of the trade, shape its book to best position it to make money from customer flow, etc. However, this is very different than taking non-customer driven, proprietary positions in the market. Given the need for separation between the customer-serving flow traders and the proprietary traders, it is not clear that securities deals need these proprietary trading operations at all. Since they can't benefit from information about customer flow, there are no true synergies between this operation and the rest of the securities business. In good times these businesses can mint money and help bolster the bottom line. But in bad times these businesses are a distraction and can cause management to lose focus on what really matters - firm clients. Morgan Stanley's decision to pare back its proprietary trading is no surprise; if the goal is to create a less volatile, more customer-focused, sustainable franchise, then it stands to reason that this is yet another business that need not be part of the legacy Wall Street mix.<br><br><strong>Disaggregation of Securities Dealers and Illiquid Assets</strong><br><br>OTC derivatives - CDS, swaps, etc. - were the engine of growth and profitability at many Wall Street firms. Part of the appeal was opaqueness, e.g., I can hide how much I'm making. Part of the appeal was capital efficiency. These businesses consumed tremendous resources to function effectively - credit, documentation, legal, operations, etc. However, this opaqueness has also contributed to its downfall, as the need to unwind and/or settle mind-bending numbers of transactions and the collateral impacts has highlighted a fundamental flaw in the OTC derivative market's evolution. These weaknesses can be addressed by shifting a large number of these transactions to exchanges, substantially increasingly liquidity, transparency, simplicity and collateral management. The securities dealer of 2010 will have an active and profitable derivatives business; it will just look more like stock trading circa 1990 than what it has for the past 20 years. Will there be some "exotic," hard-to-price risks that will reside on the Securities Dealers' balance sheet? Certainly. But it will be a small number that is aggressively managed to ensure that it stays small and doesn't get out of hand.<br><br><strong>Conclusions</strong><br><br>The Securities Dealer circa 2010 will be laser-focused on client business: raising capital, distributing risk, and trading within the scope of customer flows. This is the culture and this is what they do best. Equity research will become an industry unto itself, moving beyond the "independent research" moniker it wears today. <strong>In tomorrow's world all research will be independent</strong>. Who wants biased research? The jig is up. Corporate lending will be done by commercial banks. Glass-Steagall separated Investment Banking and Commercial Banking for a reason. While I don't think that these regulations are necessary, as an investor I'd prefer to put my money into a pure-play Securities Dealer and a pure play Commercial Bank than a combined entity any day. Better managed. Fewer conflicts. More profitable. Retail brokers will become independent enterprises, offering their clients an open-source platform of the best products and service available, without the incentive to push a single house's product line. They will compete on client service, financial planning, portfolio design and after-fee performance. This would be an attractive business for investment, as it will possess stable cashflows and a strong brand free from conflicts. Proprietary trading will likely be done outside the province of the Securities Dealers, in a healthy hedge fund and institutional asset management framework (more on that in another post). And the illiquid asset business - OTC derivatives, etc. - will move towards exchanges, looking more and more like a stock trading business under the Securities Dealer's umbrella. <br><br>2010 will be a better world on Wall Street. Greater focus. Fewer conflicts. More profitable. Less risky. It is now up to Mr. Market to make this happen.<br></div><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=oikSDc.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=oikSDc.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=YrDM7O.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=YrDM7O.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=U8DC5q.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=U8DC5q.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=6yW0nf.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=6yW0nf.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=dbpgUb.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=dbpgUb.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/508141804" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>The Wall Street of today is almost unrecognizable from that at which I worked for almost two decades. The rise of the trading culture, first brought into the mainstream by John Gutfreund and Salomon Brothers in the 1980s and which...</description><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/wall-street-circa-2010.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Early Stage vs. Later Stage Investing: Risks and Rewards</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/506292974/early-stage-vs-later-stage-investing-risks-and-rewards.html</link><category>Investing</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 09:41:41 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61047470</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>This has been a topic du jour. Seed stage investing is too risky, with valuations coming down the risk/reward is better in later stage companies, etc. Part of this is due to more seasoned companies - those that have done A and B rounds and are generating revenues - either seeking additional runway to achieve profitability or profitable companies seeking a "rainy day" cushion. But another impetus for this are VCs who have capital to deploy but want to do so in less risky enterprises. Clearly there is a big question mark around exits - few M&amp;A exits are happening and the IPO market is closed indefinitely, raising concerns about funding seed stage companies with little track record and even fewer revenues.</p><p>So I am trying to separate out the risk/reward decision from the "I don't want to take much more risk" decision. Given the sharp decline in seed stage valuations (at least that's what I'm seeing), the risk/reward calculus for great companies looks pretty compelling. As long as they are funded with, say, two years of capital, and that this capital is designed to help them get to breakeven and hopefully beyond, AND the deal is done at an attractive valuation, how does this stack up with an A or B round supplement done flat to the last round? I'd say pretty well. While certainly the risks of the seed stage investments are higher, I'd argue that the potential returns more than compensate given the valuations currently available, even for great start-ups. But hey, this is only one man's view.</p><p>One thing is for sure - there is a dearth of start-up capital out there. The pendulum has swung far in the other direction relative to 2006-2007, when start-ups were often getting crazy valuations based on a powerpoint and some good ideas. And it will continue swinging even farther away from rationality, IMHO. This is why I believe true venture investing will be one of the top performing assets classes over the next 36 months - Vintage 2009-2011 deals. Time will tell, but I'm putting my money where my mouth is.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=xbXU0J.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=xbXU0J.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=6uXTRf.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=6uXTRf.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=VO6v1W.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=VO6v1W.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=Z3MgdK.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=Z3MgdK.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=xdW9qb.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=xdW9qb.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/506292974" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>This has been a topic du jour. Seed stage investing is too risky, with valuations coming down the risk/reward is better in later stage companies, etc. Part of this is due to more seasoned companies - those that have done...</description><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/early-stage-vs-later-stage-investing-risks-and-rewards.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Companies In the News</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/506288625/quick-portfolio-company-update.html</link><category>Investing</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 09:24:29 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-61026218</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>In recent days some of my companies have done some pretty cool stuff. Given the general malaise I wanted to share a few rays of sunshine:</p><p><strong><a href="http://www.buddymedia.com/">Buddy Media</a></strong>: Buddy Media has been on a tear, both in terms of performance (read: closing deals) and contributing to the social media ecosystem. First, Mike Lazerow and team came out with a <a href="http://www.buddymedia.com/our-approach/what-advertisers-need-to-know-about-branded-social-media-apps">white paper</a> concerning what advertisers needs to know about social apps. Then they announced a <a href="http://www.buddymedia.com/buddyblog/VivaKi-Goes-Social-Enters-into-Strategic-Relationship-With-Buddy-Media.html">strategic relationship with VivaKi</a> that got great coverage in Adweek and other industry venues. Finally, <a href="http://www.alleyinsider.com/2009/1/facebook-widgetmaker-buddy-media-claims-138-revenue-growth">SAI came out with a piece</a> referencing Buddy Media's rapid growth during Q4 2008, which wasn't exactly the greatest time to be selling to agencies and the big brands. Bottom line, while times are tough and getting tougher, the the upside in helping advertisers deliver value to customers via the social nets is a greenfield opportunity. Advertisers are looking to spend scarce ad dollars more efficiently, and Buddy Media is one of the companies helping to show them the way.</p><p><strong><a href="http://www.blogtalkradio.com/">BlogTalkRadio</a></strong>: BTR recently came out with a <a href="http://blog.blogtalkradio.com/2009/01/05/introducing-the-new-blogtalkradio/">new site design</a> and added a host of new features to enhance hte experience for both content creators and listeners. Alan Levy and team also published a <a href="http://blog.blogtalkradio.com/2009/01/05/the-new-blogtalkradio-all-you-need-to-know/">detailed road map of new features and functionality</a> to help make sure users get the most out of the BTR platform. Usage stats are skyrocketing, as new hosts are finding BTR an easy, effective means for communicating with their followers, getting a message out or promoting a product or service. In its short life BTR has moved beyond the podcast to faciliate real-time, streaming dialogue from any phone line; it has altered the paradigm for Internet radio and spoken communication online.</p><p><strong><a href="http://www.stocktwits.com/streams/all">Stocktwits</a></strong>: Howard Lindzon presented at <a href="http://www.alleyinsider.com/2009/1/westheimer-takes-ny-tech-meetup-oath-of-office-on-a-macbook-photo">this week's NY Tech Meetup</a> in front of a packed house at IAC. I'd say that his presentation - in essence, letting the application run live while talking about the company's strategy and plans - was a success. It is hard not to be excited about the company's progress. We will shortly be coming out with added functionality to make the user experience even better, and a variety of value-added services as well. There will be much more to say soon, but it was exciting to see the response at the Meetup dedicated to "Built on top of Twitter" applications from an often-cynical crowd.</p><p>There are other things going in the portfolio - financings that are closing, new product releases, etc. - that I can't comment on now. But I think it is safe to say that the early-stage business is still alive and kicking, with perhaps some of the best investment opportunities over the past several years. So as I'm watching the public markets plunge on awful economic news, fraud and global violence, I am thankful that our little corner of the world is still doing ok.</p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=HrGocu.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=HrGocu.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=HjaRxg.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=HjaRxg.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=9pin0y.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=9pin0y.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=kuCYU5.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=kuCYU5.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=RwSgNB.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=RwSgNB.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/506288625" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>In recent days some of my companies have done some pretty cool stuff. Given the general malaise I wanted to share a few rays of sunshine:Buddy Media: Buddy Media has been on a tear, both in terms of performance (read:...</description><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/quick-portfolio-company-update.html</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on 2009</title><link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~3/503784647/some-thoughts-on-2009.html</link><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roger Ehrenberg</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 16:51:16 -0600</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:typepad.com,2003:post-60778594</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>So much promise, so many risks. This is how 2009 is shaping up. While euphoria surrounding the Obama Administration's fiscal stimulus plans will drive the markets early in the year, I believe this rally will lose steam as massive deficit spending begins to shine a light on the greatest risk facing the US: debasement of the currency. The power we will be handing our creditors is stunning, and in an unstable and highly politicized environment it may well be wielded to the detriment of the US economy. Can you imagine the prospect of China and Japan balking at buying more dollar-denominated assets? While some might say "Well, it wouldn't be in their (US creditors') own self-interest to precipitate a massive decline in the dollar," depending on the political stakes at hand I wouldn't put it past them. This is a very unstable manner in which to run a country and an economy, where we've lost control of our balance sheet and, potentially, our political standing.</p><p>Michael Lewis and David Einhorn penned <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/01/04/opinion/04lewiseinhorn.html">an insightful Op-Ed</a> in yesterday's <em>New York Times</em>. In effect, they raise several reasons for why the financial crisis happened and what can be done to address the problems. Interestingly, many of their root causes (mis-aligned, <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2007/11/asymmetric-ince.html">short-term Wall Street incentives</a>, rating agencies' <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2007/10/rating-agencies.html">conflicts of interest</a>, regulators' personal self-interests, etc.) and prescriptives (consistent, <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/why-did-tarp-change-course.html">well-communicated Treasury policies</a>, creation of healthy institutions through Government takeovers, sale of healthy assets and the <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/09/paying-for-the.html">long-term workout of bad assets</a>, <a href="http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2008/11/the-plague-of-short-termism.html">long-term emphasis</a> separate from stock market impacts, etc.) are in line with the thinking I've put forth on this blog over the past 18 months. One part of the article really got my back up. The Madoff meltdown and the existence of a whistleblower, Harry Markopolos, who had notified the SEC years before of his concerns is reminiscent of Einhorn's indictments of both Lehman Brothers and Allied Capital Corp (ALD). Like Markopolos, Einhorn spent years seeking to educate the SEC about the wide-ranging fraud taking place at ALD but to no avail. </p><p>This kind of regulatory breakdown is absolutely stunning, but not when one considers the mis-aligned motives of those doing the regulating. It is no different than the prevalence of short-termism on Wall Street, Corporate America and in our Government. While it is maddening, it only highlights the enormity of our task; to restructure the essence of how incentives are set in order to calibrate human nature with the good of society. This doesn't mean that what is good for you can't be good for society and vice versa. To the contrary, I believe we can balance self-interest with overall good. But when self-interest pays off in short-term ways, how are people going to act? You got it. This is among the biggest and most important challenges facing our Government, our companies and our citizens in 2009 and beyond.</p><p>So, here are a few trends that I think should - and will - prevail during 2009:</p><ul>
<li><strong>Increased financial statement transparency</strong>. The "fair value" crowd will win the day. Investors are sick of surprises, and the only way these can be mitigated is through disclosure. Notwithstanding their poor performance over the past several years, the SEC recently supported the continued application of the fair value framework.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>The "exchanging" of credit derivatives and interest rates swaps</strong>. Keeping with the theme of transparency and adding a dose of simplicity, the trillions of dollars of exposure require far better tracking, disclosure and collateral management than has been in place up to now. Standardization is something that could and should have been addressed five years ago, but here we are. The time is now to liquify and demystify these opaque instruments.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>An explosion in illiquid asset trading</strong>. Given the magnitude of the stranded venture investments, private equity and hedge fund LP interests seeking to be offloaded and hundreds of billions of illiquid and "side pocketed" hedge fund assets, new venues will emerge for trading these risks. Venture capitalists and other early investors will want liquidity well before the IPO market comes back, and markets will spring up to handle these deals. And fund-of-funds, pensions and endowments in desperate need of liquidity will want as many options as possible for selling their LP interests and other illiquid holdings. This is a boom area for 2009 and 2010.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>A wholesale re-thinking of the role of rating agencies</strong>. If it wasn't before, it is now abundantly clear that rating agencies did neither a good job nor were free of bias while serving in a quasi-fiduciary capacity. Their work, an essential element in the due diligence process covering trillions of dollars of paper, was found to be wholly inadequate at precisely the time it was most needed. Given that ratings put forth by the major agencies are suspect, might not a new system be called for? Or perhaps a scrapping of the role of rating agencies entirely? At this point why would issuers pay rating agencies for their imprimatur when it has been shown not to be worth much? I don't know.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Good Bank/Bad Bank (or a variant) will prevail as the financial services bailout tool of choice</strong>. The Treasury's hundreds of billions of capital injections into sick institutions with sick managements made absolutely no sense then and it makes no sense now. There are two ways to help the system and minimize moral hazard: (1) engineer a wholesale takeover of failing firms, wipe out common shareholders and unsecured creditors, kick out management, sell good assets to the highest bidder and warehouse bad assets for an organized liquidation over time; and (2) replace management at failing firms, wipe out the common and unsecured debtholders, isolate the illiquid, "bad" assets and sell them at market value to a Government-sponsored liquidating trust, recapitalize the "good" assets with either private (preferred) or public funds and let it go forth and prosper. Either way the outcome is both logical and far superior to that which has been engineered by the current Administration. Let's get a move on.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>The US stock market's return profile will look like a parabola, rising early and then falling late</strong>. Excitement over Obama and his stimulus package will drive prices higher, bringing money off the sidelines that is afraid to miss the recovery. Problem is, the combination of a plunging real economy and tax receipts coupled with trillions in Treasury issuance to cover the bailout, fiscal stimulus, war operations and refinancing of existing debt will crush the dollar. If the emerging markets begin to recover and the US "flight to quality" trade falters, US stocks could be a laggard for quite some time. Dollar assets simply won't look that attractive relative to developing nations with far more attractive growth prospects and with demographics to sustain this growth well into the middle of this century.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Early-stage investing will be in its Renaissance</strong>. First is was private equity. Then it was hedge funds. Now I believe early-stage investing will create untold fortunes in this next cycle. Enabling technologies have made it so cheap to pursue new ideas that it is unleashing a wave of brainpower this world has never seen. Have an idea? Code it up. Processing power is cheap. Storage is cheap. And accessing customers has never been cheaper. There is a vibrancy across the early stage community - entrepreneurs, investors and customers - that simply doesn't exist at other points along the investment spectrum. Investor fear notwithstanding, good ideas are getting funded, and those that get funding and survive in today's hostile climate will emerge strong, game-tested, and ready to rock it when the economy recovers.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>The hedge fund industry "barbell" will only become more pronounced</strong>. I started writing about this in mid-2006, where I posited that the middle of the hedge fund industry would be squeezed. This has been borne out over the past few years, and represents a trend that will continue unabated in 2009. Institutions are redeeming out of funds large and small, but the largest funds will survive. Between sheer mass, long-term investor relationships and lock-ups the largest brand name funds will continue. Those funds that once populated the middle will not. Small funds will always exist, either as launch-pads for managers with grand visions or for investors content to run small, tightly-knit shops without the ever-present need to focus on marketing and customer relations. Bottom line, I think the fund with several hundred million under management will go the way of the dinosaurs.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market regulation will be revisited in spades</strong>. The key question is, are the changes incremental or wholesale? I'd argue that the current system combines the worst of many worlds, and headline-grabbing Congresspeople who think they look good by saying "increase regulation" without really understanding what that means could make things materially worse. We need to take a big step back, look at the tangle of regulations and regulatory bodies, pull out a piece of clean paper and say "What would a prudent regulatory framework look like?" It would likely emphasize transparency and disclosure, and be in sync with the accounting rule-makers at FASB. This is a huge undertaking, but one that needs to begin in earnest in 2009.</li>
</ul>
<p>We'll see how it goes. Regardless, 2009 should prove to be a very, very interesting year.</p><p></p><p></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=Y0ktZx.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=Y0ktZx.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=jVX0Vy.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=jVX0Vy.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=HICKYS.P"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=HICKYS.P" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=Ho9veQ.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=Ho9veQ.p" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?a=XXUr35.p"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/InformationArbitrage?i=XXUr35.p" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/InformationArbitrage/~4/503784647" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded><description>So much promise, so many risks. This is how 2009 is shaping up. While euphoria surrounding the Obama Administration's fiscal stimulus plans will drive the markets early in the year, I believe this rally will lose steam as massive deficit...</description><category domain="http://rss.financialcontent.com/stocksymbol">ALD</category><feedburner:origLink>http://www.informationarbitrage.com/2009/01/some-thoughts-on-2009.html</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
