<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com">
    <title>InfoQ Personalized Feed for Unregistered User - Register to upgrade!</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com</link>
    <description>This RSS feed is a personalized feed, unique to your account (registered or unregistered) on InfoQ.com.  On InfoQ you can select which communities you are interested in using the 'Your Communities' box on the left side bar, and you can even turn off any content matching sub-topics or tags. The results of those selections will reflect in what news you see in this RSS feed - it should match whatever you see in the 'news' center panel on InfoQ. If you are NOT seeing this correlation then you may not be using a feed URL associated with your InfoQ account. For best accuracy, register to InfoQ and then grab a new RSS feed url from the 'Personal Feed' link on the left side menu. Enjoy!</description>
    <items>
      <rdf:Seq>
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/engine-yard-solo" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/rtmp-to-open" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/vertebra-released" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Textual-DSL-Markus-Voelter" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Architect-Qualities" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Spring-Integration-Joshua-Long" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/jquery-1.3" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Sun-JES-Server-Open-Source" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/migrations_dotnet" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/SOAPatternsBook" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/ruby-191-coming-up" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/phillips-adhearsion" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/francl-testing-overrated" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/AWS-Management-Console-Security" />
        <rdf:li resource="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/debgem" />
      </rdf:Seq>
    </items>
  </channel>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/engine-yard-solo">
    <title>Solo: Engine Yard on Amazon EC2</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/engine-yard-solo</link>
    <description>Solo is a new offering from Engine Yard to run their software stack on Amazon EC2. We talked to Engine Yard's founder and architect Jayson Vantuyl to learn the differences between Solo and their present hosting services and what their target audience is. &lt;i&gt;By Mirko Stocker&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Mirko Stocker</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-22T21:00:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/engine-yard-solo</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/rtmp-to-open">
    <title>Abobe to publish the Real-Time Messaging Protocol (RTMP) specification used in Flash Platform</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/rtmp-to-open</link>
    <description>Adobe has announced plans to publish the Real-Time Messaging Protocol (RTMP) specification, which is designed for high-performance transmission of audio, video, and data between Adobe Flash Platform technologies. This move that has followed the opening of the AMF spec has been received with varying degrees of enthusiasm from the RIA community. &lt;i&gt;By Dionysios G. Synodinos&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Dionysios G. Synodinos</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-22T18:15:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/rtmp-to-open</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/vertebra-released">
    <title>Engine Yard Releases Cloud Management Framework Vertebra</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/vertebra-released</link>
    <description>Vertebra, announced at RailsConf 2008, has finally been released. Vertebra is a platform to develop and manage cloud applications. We talked to Engine Yard founder and architect Jayson Vantuyl about what Vertebra and its use of XMPP bring to the table. &lt;i&gt;By Mirko Stocker&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Mirko Stocker</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-21T22:07:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/vertebra-released</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Textual-DSL-Markus-Voelter">
    <title>Presentation: Textual DSLs Made Simple</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Textual-DSL-Markus-Voelter</link>
    <description>In this presentation filmed during QCon London 2008, Markus Voelter tried to convince the audience that writing a textual external DSL is fairly straightforward and simple. He took them through the steps needed to create a textual DSL from defining the grammar to processing a domain model. &lt;i&gt;By Abel Avram&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Abel Avram</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-21T15:49:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/Textual-DSL-Markus-Voelter</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Architect-Qualities">
    <title>The Qualities of a Software Architect</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Architect-Qualities</link>
    <description>The software/enterprise architect job is an important one. The duties of an architect are numerous and require specific leadership, communication and technical skills to be fulfilled.  &lt;i&gt;By Abel Avram&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Abel Avram</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-21T08:58:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/Architect-Qualities</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Spring-Integration-Joshua-Long">
    <title>Article: Getting Started With Spring Integration</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Spring-Integration-Joshua-Long</link>
    <description>In this article, Joshua Long introduces the readers to Spring Integration, an extension of the Spring framework supporting the Enterprise Integration Patterns. After a short introduction into Enterprise Application Integration (EAI), the article presents an example of the integration between an email application and a blogger one. &lt;i&gt;By Abel Avram&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Abel Avram</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-20T13:23:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/Spring-Integration-Joshua-Long</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/jquery-1.3">
    <title>jQuery 1.3 Released with New High Performance CSS Selector Engine</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/jquery-1.3</link>
    <description>Version 1.3 of the JavaScript library jQuery has been released featuring Sizzle, a brand new CSS selector engine which offers significant performance gains for the most frequently used selectors. Along with the release, a new API browser was presented which is available online or as an Adobe AIR application and can accommodate live running examples with which the developers can experiment. &lt;i&gt;By Dionysios G. Synodinos&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Dionysios G. Synodinos</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-19T19:32:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/jquery-1.3</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Sun-JES-Server-Open-Source">
    <title>Sun Opens Netscape Server Source</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/Sun-JES-Server-Open-Source</link>
    <description>Sun's OpenSolaris project has released the Java Enterprise Server as open source under the BSD license.  The is largely the same as their commerical product, which descends from the Netscape Enterprise Server of the 90's.   &lt;i&gt;By Charlie Martin&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Charlie Martin</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-19T07:04:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/Sun-JES-Server-Open-Source</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/migrations_dotnet">
    <title>Rails Style Database Migrations in .NET</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/migrations_dotnet</link>
    <description>Versioning database schema along with your .NET code is essential for managing volatile codebases especially when employing continuous integration. Ruby on Rails accomplishes this with a popular solution of abstracting DDL SQL into Ruby commands. Similar solutions are available in .NET with third party libraries. &lt;i&gt;By Al Tenhundfeld&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Al Tenhundfeld</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-18T05:19:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/migrations_dotnet</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/SOAPatternsBook">
    <title>The “SOA Design Patterns” Book Is Available</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/SOAPatternsBook</link>
    <description>Prentice Hall has just announced the release of Thomas Erl’s latest book -  SOA Design Patterns -  the industry’s most comprehensive catalog of design patterns for SOA. &lt;i&gt;By Boris Lublinsky&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Boris Lublinsky</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-18T03:02:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/SOAPatternsBook</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/ruby-191-coming-up">
    <title>Ruby 1.9.1 Is Close - Time To Switch From 1.8.x?</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/ruby-191-coming-up</link>
    <description>Ruby 1.9.1, the first stable version of Ruby 1.9 is around the corner, with the RC2 expected any day. 1.9.x hasn't seen much adoption or support in it's first year - although a closer look shows that it might be time to consider 1.9.1.&#xD;
 &lt;i&gt;By Werner Schuster&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Werner Schuster</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-18T00:56:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/ruby-191-coming-up</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/phillips-adhearsion">
    <title>Interview: Jay Phillips on Adhearsion and VoIP</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/phillips-adhearsion</link>
    <description>In this interview recorded at RubyFringe, Jay Phillips talks about VoIP, Asterisk and how his framework Adhearsion makes it easy to write voice applications. &lt;i&gt;By Werner Schuster&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Werner Schuster</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-17T20:22:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/phillips-adhearsion</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/francl-testing-overrated">
    <title>Presentation: Testing is Overrated</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/francl-testing-overrated</link>
    <description>In this talk from RubyFringe, Luke Francl asks: is developer-driven testing really the best way to find software defects? Or is the emphasis on testing and test coverage barking up the wrong tree? &lt;i&gt;By Werner Schuster&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Werner Schuster</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-17T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/francl-testing-overrated</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/AWS-Management-Console-Security">
    <title>The AWS Management Console Raises Security Concerns</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/AWS-Management-Console-Security</link>
    <description>There has been an ongoing debate over how secure cloud computing is. Some argue that clouds are more secure than many private networks, while others consider that cloud computing may open more security holes. Some consider that Amazon’s - Web based – AWS Management Console is creating more opportunities to hackers. &lt;i&gt;By Abel Avram&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Abel Avram</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-14T13:17:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/AWS-Management-Console-Security</dc:identifier>
  </item>
  <item rdf:about="http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/debgem">
    <title>DebGem: Ruby Gems for Debian</title>
    <link>http://www.infoq.com/news/2009/01/debgem</link>
    <description>DebGem is a new service from Phusion that properly integrates Ruby Gems into Debian-based Linux distributions. We talked to Hongli Lai and Ninh Bui from Phusion to learn more about the project. &lt;i&gt;By Mirko Stocker&lt;/i&gt;</description>
    <dc:creator>Mirko Stocker</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2009-01-13T22:10:00Z</dc:date>
    <dc:identifier>/news/2009/01/debgem</dc:identifier>
  </item>
</rdf:RDF>

