<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl" type="text/xsl" media="screen"?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css" type="text/css" media="screen"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
  <title>James Britt - Code, Content, Caffiene</title>
  <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2009:mephisto/</id>
  <generator version="0.7.3" uri="http://mephistoblog.com">Mephisto Noh-Varr</generator>
  
  <link href="http://www.jamesbritt.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2009-01-16T18:35:24Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/JamesBritt-Home" type="application/atom+xml" /><entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2009-01-16:934</id>
    <published>2009-01-16T18:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2009-01-16T18:35:24Z</updated>
    <category term="2008 MWRC" />
    <category term="RubyConf" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/514197036/mt-west-rubyconf-2009-registration-is-open" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Mt. West RubyConf 2009 registration is open</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;MountainWest RubyConf is on March 13-14, 2009 in Salt Lake City, UT and costs just $100.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;That’s right, perhaps the most kick-ass RubyConf of the year cost only one.  Hundred. Dollars.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mtnwestrubyconf.org/'&gt;Go now.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='caps'&gt;BTW&lt;/span&gt;, I’ll be speaking at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;See the list of speakers &lt;a href='http://mtnwestrubyconf.org/2009/speakers'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2009/1/16/mt-west-rubyconf-2009-registration-is-open</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2009-01-14:930</id>
    <published>2009-01-14T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2009-01-16T00:28:05Z</updated>
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/512226116/the-braithwaite-effect" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>The Braithwaite Effect</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;I’m amazed that &lt;a href='http://www.google.com/search?q=raganwald&amp;amp;#38;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;#38;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;#38;aq=t&amp;amp;#38;rls=com.ubuntu:en-US:official&amp;amp;#38;client=firefox-a'&gt;Raganwald&lt;/a&gt; would have any &lt;a href='http://github.com/raganwald/homoiconic/blob/f6b0ffa05615fd507cd7ebb912e639078e4e4309/2009-01-14/advertisement.md'&gt;trouble scoring work&lt;/a&gt;.  Or the kind of work he would enjoy (since, in the broad view, its easy to get &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; job, less easy to get a job you enjoy)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Seriously, what are people thinking?  “Oh, he seems smart, but he doesn’t have the .Net chops with BizTalk experience we need.”&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fortunate the work with many smart people.  Most of them were good at what they did, i.e., their “real” job, but some also had a knack for helping others get better at their job, too.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t just a matter of straight-up mentoring; these people were able to offer a different point of view, ask the odd question, get people thinking about new things in new ways.  It kept things fresh, made the work more fun.  It’s one thing to tell people stuff, it’s another to get people to want to know and understand more stuff.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.ecotopia.com/webpress/futures.htm'&gt;Alan Kay said&lt;/a&gt;, “At &lt;span class='caps'&gt;PARC&lt;/span&gt; we had a slogan: ‘Point of view is worth 80 IQ points.’ “&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Smart, interesting people like Reg should be hired  simply to go wander around a company, strike up conversations, and ease people into a different point of view.   It would make the whole company smarter.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2009/1/14/the-braithwaite-effect</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2009-01-10:929</id>
    <published>2009-01-10T23:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2009-01-10T23:18:39Z</updated>
    <category term="JRuby" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/508395532/gems-in-a-jar-jruby-continues-to-rock" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Gems in a Jar.  JRuby continues to rock</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Big props to Nick Sieger.  His latest bit of super cool awesomeness is &lt;a href='http://blog.nicksieger.com/articles/2009/01/10/jruby-1-1-6-gems-in-a-jar'&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote cite='true'&gt;
As a result of some fruitful hacking at RubyConf 2008, I was able to modify JRuby so that gems can be loaded and used without having to unpack them. The feature became generally available with the 1.1.6 release last month. Gems in a jar!
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2009/1/10/gems-in-a-jar-jruby-continues-to-rock</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2009-01-07:925</id>
    <published>2009-01-07T19:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2009-01-07T19:25:49Z</updated>
    <category term="Ignite" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/505471235/proposals-begin-accepted-for-ignite-phoenix-iii" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Proposals begin accepted for Ignite Phoenix III</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Got something to? Something you’re passionate about?   Can you you say it with 20 slides, 5 seconds a slide?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.ignitephoenix.com'&gt;Ignite Phoenix&lt;/a&gt; III is coming up, and &lt;a href='http://www.ignite-phoenix.org/2009/01/01/submissions-now-open-for-ignite-phoenix-3/'&gt;presentation proposals are now being accepted.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2009/1/7/proposals-begin-accepted-for-ignite-phoenix-iii</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-12-30:924</id>
    <published>2008-12-30T19:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-30T19:27:01Z</updated>
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/498799255/on-merb-rails" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>On Merb+Rails</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Pat Eyler has been asking some folks for their thoughts on the Merb/Rails merge.  Basically, he’s putting the  same three questions to a number of people, with interesting results.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;He asked me, and has published &lt;a href='http://on-ruby.blogspot.com/2008/12/rails-and-merb-why-merge-at-all.html'&gt;my response.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='caps'&gt;BTW&lt;/span&gt;, the observation that adding Merb into Rails could mean that people will get to use Merb (or some form of it)  while claiming to be doing Rails (and so avoiding the dread “but why use  @foo? Why not Rails?” challenge) was copped from a post by David Koontz to the Phoenix Ruby User Group mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/12/30/on-merb-rails</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-12-30:923</id>
    <published>2008-12-30T04:09:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-30T04:10:13Z</updated>
    <category term="HackerNews" />
    <category term="JotBot" />
    <category term="JRuby" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/498262611/getting-feedback-for-your-product-jotbot-on-hacker-news" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Getting feedback for your product: JotBot on Hacker News</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Now that &lt;a href='http://www.getjotbot.com'&gt;JotBot&lt;/a&gt; has been released, I wanted to get more feedback for the application.  I posted to &lt;a href='http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=413327'&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and solicited comments.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I have to say that  I’m really pleased with the results.  I’ve seen a jump in the number of people requesting trial keys; I can’t be sure (maybe Google Analytics can help me here) but I’m assuming the post prompted folks to try it out.  So that’s good.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;But the comments have been really useful.  Not everyone is falling all over the app, of course.  But there have been some good observations, some good questions about how JotBot works and how it effects the user.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I really appreciate the comments from &lt;a href='http://news.ycombinator.com/user?id=webwright'&gt;Tony Wright&lt;/a&gt;  of &lt;a href='http://www.rescuetime.com'&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt;.  RescueTime was a &lt;a href='http://www.ycombinator.com/faq.html'&gt;Y Combinator&lt;/a&gt; startup, and I’ve been hearing good things about it ever since they launched.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Among other things, Tony’s comments made me realize that some may think of JotBot in terms of a &lt;em&gt;productivity&lt;/em&gt; app, while others see it as a pro-active &lt;em&gt;record-keeping&lt;/em&gt;  tool.  Hence, what works for some does not work for others, or work so well.  (I, of course, secretly want it to be all things to all people.  More realistically, I do not want to downplay its value as a productivity enhancer, but I do see how it differs from RescueTime and other “stealth” behavior tracking tools, and JotBot was born of a need to track activity details.  Yes, it can make you more productive, but its “pull” model may be the wrong kind of disruption for some people.  I just hope people try it before passing judgment)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Aside from Tony’s points, one comment really got me thinking: To use JotBot, you need a key, even for the free trial.  For some, this is too much of an annoyance.  Indeed, it would be much nicer if people could just download and run the app, while the time-limit still held. More thought needs to be given to that.  I want it to be as painless as possible for people to see if JotBot works for them.  On the other hand, I’m not a fan of crippleware or nagware.  Suggestions welcome!&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, thanks again to the HN community.  I’d love it if everyone who commented went and tried JotBot and then decided to buy it. But, no matter what, I’m really grateful that people take the time to offer their observations.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/12/30/getting-feedback-for-your-product-jotbot-on-hacker-news</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-12-22:920</id>
    <published>2008-12-22T22:54:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-22T22:54:49Z</updated>
    <category term="JRuby" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <category term="Time-tracking" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/492591488/jotbot-is-now-for-sale" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>JotBot is now for sale</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://happycamperstudios.com'&gt;Happy Camper Studios&lt;/a&gt; has released what is, as best I can tell, the first commercial desktop application written in JRuby.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.getjotbot.com'&gt;JotBot&lt;/a&gt; is time tracking done right.   It aims to be minimally disruptive, but it uses a “pull” approach so that  you don’t have to  remember to go log your time. Instead, you get reminded at a configurable interval to record what you’ve been doing.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;There’s a quick tour video on the &lt;a href='http://www.getjotbot.com'&gt;JotBot home page&lt;/a&gt; that shows off most of the features and give you a feel for how it behaves.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I’m super proud of this release and the amazing work put in by my fellow campers, David Koontz and Logan Barnett.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;You can read the back-story on the development process at &lt;a href='http://dkoontz.wordpress.com/2008/12/22/jotbot-post-mortem-2/'&gt;David’s blog.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;You can try JotBot for 30 days free, so &lt;a href='http://www.getjotbot.com/download/'&gt;give it a whirl.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/12/22/jotbot-is-now-for-sale</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-12-17:913</id>
    <published>2008-12-17T16:34:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-17T16:35:58Z</updated>
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/487738073/hire-reg-braithwaite" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Hire Reg Braithwaite</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://reginald.braythwayt.com/RegBraithwaiteGH1208_en_US.pdf'&gt;His CV.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/12/17/hire-reg-braithwaite</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-12-08:914</id>
    <published>2008-12-08T05:34:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-08T05:59:41Z</updated>
    <category term="JRuby" />
    <category term="Monkeybars" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/478132485/monkeybars-with-inline-ruby-swing-code-and-gee-whizz-generator" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Monkeybars with inline-Ruby Swing code and Gee Whiz! generator</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;I forked the &lt;a href='http://gitorious.org/projects/monkeybars'&gt;Monkeybars repo&lt;/a&gt; so I could safely experiment with some things.  My repo is &lt;a href='http://gitorious.org/projects/monkeybars/repos/monkeybars-with-inline-ruby-swing'&gt;monkeybars-with-inline-ruby-swing&lt;/a&gt; and that’s pretty much it in  a nutshell.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Often, when people talk about Monkeybars, they compare it to some other similar tool that uses inline  code (often using a “builder”-style syntax)  to define the UI.  The typical Monkeybars demo, in contrast, shows the use of &lt;span class='caps'&gt;WYSIWYG UI&lt;/span&gt; editor to create a binary Java Swing class; this file is then used in the Monkeybars app.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, showing how this is done can take some time, even for a basic Hello, World! demo app.  The sad truth of conference talks and demos is that you can get screwed from both ends in trying to properly explain anything non-trivial.  You want to point out the details (because your tool is powerful), but that eats up the limited time available.  You also want to actually show something, ideally something complete, so you end up with something simplistic.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;If done well, then everyone gets the point: robust, sophisticated tool presented in overly-simplistic app for demonstration purposes.  However, you can often end up with people seeing it the other way: lots of detailed steps needed to get to skimpy results.  What’s then not grasped (or not well explained) is that the details are there to convey the breadth of possibilities; the skimpy app is there to simply demonstrate that this is something &lt;strong&gt;real&lt;/strong&gt;.  You still have to apply some imagination to understand the implications for larger, far more complex applications by extrapolation.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Demos using hand-written code to define a &lt;span class='caps'&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; have a real edge here because the speaker never has to leave the code editor, never has to switch views or tools, never has to explain much more than “here’s some more Ruby.”  What’s often not mentioned, though, is that the inline-style of &lt;span class='caps'&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; definition does not scale well beyond the typical demo program.  What you see really &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; what your get.  (Trust me; I would not want to have to work on &lt;a href='http://www.getjotbot.com'&gt;JotBot&lt;/a&gt; hand-coding the UI.)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Of course, maybe you don’t want much more than a handful of buttons and some text fields.  Maybe all you want is the desktop equivalent of &lt;span class='caps'&gt;HTML 3&lt;/span&gt;.2.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Sometimes that’s all I need for given screen in some larger app, and having Monkeybars provide this would make it that much sweeter.  Best would be that it would not alter how one uses the full power of the library.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So here’s what my fork of Monkeybars adds:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Some code to the  base View class to aid in detecting when the Swing UI class is in fact created via Ruby, so that the appropriate reflection/meta-programming can be done&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;An additional app generator that gives you an &lt;span class='caps'&gt;MVC&lt;/span&gt; tuple, with a basic view UI class, written in  Ruby, in place.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Because I’m interested in getting people to play with this, I renamed the key files from &lt;code&gt;monkeybars&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;jimpanzee&lt;/code&gt;.  Now if you install the code as a gem you won’t stomp on any existing Monkeybars installation. (The code should be completely compatible with the current actual Monkeybars &lt;span class='caps'&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;, but the renaming is cleaner.)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;With jimpanzee, you can do this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;
james@james06:~/tmp$ jimpanzee MyCoolApp :demo
Creating directory MyCoolApp
Copying jimpanzee project structure
Creating  default code for MyCoolApp ...

Final steps:

  1. Place a copy of jruby-complete.jar in the MyCoolApp/lib/java directory
  2. cd into the MyCoolApp/src directory
  3. Run the code using jruby:

       jruby main.rb

Happy hacking!
&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;and if you follow those final instructions you’ll have a simple cross-platform &lt;span class='caps'&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; app running. Toss in &lt;a href='http://rawr.rubyforge.org/'&gt;rawr&lt;/a&gt; and you’re three steps away from having redistributable executables ready.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;You can see it here (except for the Rawr part):&lt;/p&gt;


&amp;lt;object height='344' width='425'&gt;&amp;lt;param&gt;&amp;lt;/param&gt;&amp;lt;param&gt;&amp;lt;/param&gt;&amp;lt;embed src='http://www.youtube.com/v/u_g245nW_vg&amp;amp;#38;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;amp;#38;color2=0xcfcfcf&amp;amp;#38;hl=en&amp;amp;#38;feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;#38;fs=1' height='344' width='425'&gt;&amp;lt;/embed&gt;&amp;lt;/object&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;There’s more to be done, not the least of which is ensuring that my approach is robust.  The generator needs improvement; it’s pretty brain-dead.  (For example, &lt;code&gt;:demo&lt;/code&gt; is a hard-coded flag for the generator code, and you can’t tell it what to name the generated tuple.  But these are not difficult things to change. The real issue is what to change them to.)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;There’s a certain “gee whiz” factor in this, because there’s a low limit on what such generators can buy you, and how much inline UI code you’ll want, but the flip side is that it &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; lower the barrier to entry, and it is of practical value when coupled with Monkeybars’ other killer features.  The best part is that it is in addition to, not in place of, all the power the &lt;a href='http://www.monkeybars.org'&gt;best &lt;span class='caps'&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; toolkit&lt;/a&gt; offers for creating robust &lt;span class='caps'&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; apps of all shapes and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Please keep in mind when you see &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; demo that looks a bit too good or too easy that maybe the cool comes with a cost.  The most common is that what makes some things easy ends up making other things hard.   Always try to ask the presenter what the limits are, if a tool will grow with you if the size your application expands, or if will you find yourself stuck once the gee whiz has worn off.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Whatever tools you pick, consider the long view.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/12/8/monkeybars-with-inline-ruby-swing-code-and-gee-whizz-generator</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-12-02:908</id>
    <published>2008-12-02T05:41:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-02T05:44:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Random shit" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/472085610/self-facts-randomly_select-7" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>self.facts.randomly_select(7)</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;That’s not actual code; I made that up.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Here’s something not made up:  Stellar talent &lt;a href='http://steamcrow.com/about'&gt;Daniel Davis&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href='http://steamcrow.com/you-summoned-us'&gt;challenged me  to present seven random facts&lt;/a&gt; about myself.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I’m not a fan of anything that smacks of a chain-letter, but Daniel rules so I’ll at least spew out some unneeded detail.  (But I won’t be inflicting this on on seven other people.  Feel free to take up the challenge on your own if you feel so inclined.)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;0. Favorite color: Plaid &lt;br&gt;
1. Born and raised on an island&lt;br&gt;
2. First cat was named George Sand&lt;br&gt;
3. First 45 &lt;span class='caps'&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; vinyl single bought: &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x1mV_5-bRPo'&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/a&gt;  by Edgar Winter Group  &lt;br&gt;
4. Learned &lt;span class='caps'&gt;FORTRAN&lt;/span&gt; in college by coding cellular automata for a semester. Still do not understand how I passed the Numerical Analysis with &lt;span class='caps'&gt;FORTRAN&lt;/span&gt; course since, oddly enough, CA were not on any test or assignment.&lt;br&gt;
5. Have never skied&lt;br&gt;
6. Favorite movie is Metropolis, unless it’s Citizen Kane or Animal House&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/12/2/self-facts-randomly_select-7</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-11-30:906</id>
    <published>2008-11-30T14:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-30T17:27:51Z</updated>
    <category term="2008" />
    <category term="Monkeybars" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <category term="RubyConf" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/470402298/rubyconf2008-videos-now-appearing-online" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>RubyConf2008 videos now appearing online</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://rubyconf2008.confreaks.com/'&gt;RubyConf2008 videos&lt;/a&gt; are now going up.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;First one you should watch: &lt;a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/danbenjamin/3012060667'&gt;David’s&lt;/a&gt;  talk on &lt;a href='http://rubyconf2008.confreaks.com/monkeybars-easy-cross-platform-guis.html'&gt;Monkeybars: easy cross platform GUIs.&lt;/a&gt; Learn about making &lt;a href='http://www.getjotbot.com'&gt;commercial desktop apps in Ruby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Monkeybars means &lt;a href='http://www.monkeybars.org'&gt;Ruby &lt;span class='caps'&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; apps  done right.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/11/30/rubyconf2008-videos-now-appearing-online</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-11-28:907</id>
    <published>2008-11-28T22:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-28T22:57:15Z</updated>
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/468774884/i-has-occured-to-me" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>I has occured to me ...</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Some people write to say what they believe.   I write to see what I believe.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It’s the difference between creative acts to express yourself, v. creative acts to explore and provoke yourself.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Self-expression tends to be pretty tedious all around, but self-exploration (leading to self-invention) is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/11/28/i-has-occured-to-me</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-11-25:905</id>
    <published>2008-11-25T20:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-25T20:18:12Z</updated>
    <category term="MtWest" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <category term="RubyConf" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/465388020/mountainwest-rubyconf-sponsorship" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>MountainWest RubyConf Sponsorship</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mtnwestrubyconf.org/'&gt;MountainWest RubyConf&lt;/a&gt;, among the most super cool awesome Ruby gatherings around, is looking for sponsors for the 2009 event in Salt Lake City, UT.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;You can read the prospectus &lt;a href='http://mtnwestrubyconf.org/2009/downloads/prospectus.pdf'&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;If you or your company is looking to support the Ruby community, and get some solid advertising in front of some of the best geeks in the world, this is for you.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;If you know someone or some company who would be interested in sponsoring the conference, please pass this information on.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/11/25/mountainwest-rubyconf-sponsorship</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-11-22:904</id>
    <published>2008-11-22T23:10:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-22T23:12:40Z</updated>
    <category term="JRuby" />
    <category term="Monkeybars" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/462274098/monkeybars-at-ruby-manor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Monkeybars at Ruby Manor</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;There’s a &lt;a href='http://effectif.com/2008/11/22/notes-from-the-ruby-manor'&gt;nice write-up about recent events at Ruby Manor&lt;/a&gt; that describes a talk involving &lt;a href='http://www.monkeybars.org'&gt;Monkeybars.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I want add a few comments.  First, while it is true that using JRuby means some gems do not work, the upside is that you have at your disposal the hojillion&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href='#fn1'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Java libraries.  While it is a goal that all Ruby code, gem or not, work with JRuby (with some caveats about native code), the ability to call into Java libs is a major win.   The post mentions that a particualr gem for using Twitter could not be used; I’m fairly sure this is the exact situation Logan Barnett encountered when he started on &lt;a href='http://gitorious.org/projects/twit-and-twitter'&gt;Twit-and-Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for the Java One &lt;a href='http://java.sun.com/javaone/sf/2008/articles/scripting.jsp'&gt;Script Bowl.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Logan was able to use a Java lib for Twitter, one that (as I recall) offered a more robust &lt;span class='caps'&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;.  Big win.  So, not to diminish the problem JRuby may have with certain gems, but there are two ways of looking at this: Some gems don’t run (glass 99/100 empty), vs. full use of Java libs (glass overflowing onto the floor and out the door).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Second, Monkeybars was compared (so to speak) with Shoes.  No mention was made of Shoes having stability issues (something I’ve seen for myself), but even were it rock-solid there is no way one would want to build a serious app of any complexity. (To fair, I don’t think Shoes was created for that purpose, though some enthusiasts mistake the ease of use as demonstrated in demo apps as something that scales to commercial-grade desktop applications. If and when there is a &lt;span class='caps'&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/span&gt; editor for Shoes that might change.)  I’m deeply skeptical that, for example, &lt;a href='http://www.getjotbot.com'&gt;JotBot&lt;/a&gt; could have been made in Shoes, if only because of the lack of sophisticated components.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;However, for those who really &lt;span class='caps'&gt;REALLY&lt;/span&gt; want to build &lt;span class='caps'&gt;GUI&lt;/span&gt; apps that way, good news: Work is afoot to add this to Monkeybars.  We hope before too long to allow Monkeybars to offer the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;  This is a really big number.  Really. Big.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/11/22/monkeybars-at-ruby-manor</feedburner:origLink></entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://www.jamesbritt.com/">
    <author>
      <name>james</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:www.jamesbritt.com,2008-11-19:887</id>
    <published>2008-11-19T20:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-19T20:22:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Ramaze" />
    <category term="Ruby" />
    <link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JamesBritt-Home/~3/458748000/why-ramaze-and-more-ramaze-by-example" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <title>Why Ramaze?  And more. Ramaze by Example</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;blockquote cite='http://blog.purepistos.net/index.php/2008/11/18/ramaze-by-example/'&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;With king of the hill Rails chugging along, and up-and-comer Merb picking up steam, why bother with Ramaze?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The number one thing that makes Ramaze stand out from the crowd is that you write very little code and you write it all yourself. No generators.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Before Rails, people wrote lots and lots of code when making a web app, and they did it over and over as they did web app after web app. With each new app, they would spend time “ramping up” with just the base application before they got into the real meat of the matter, the core functionality which varied from client to client, application to application. Rails and Merb and their ilk try to make your life easier by generating this “lots and lots of code” for you, so you don’t have to spend time repeating the motions of getting the skeleton of your application coded.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Ramaze takes a different approach. It asks: How about we dump the “lots and lots of code” part altogether? This way, you get the benefit of nearly nil ramp up time, without the gaping jaw effect that hits you after you run a code generator script and sit staring at the big filetree that just sprouted out of the ground (think Jack and the Beanstalk).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/blockquote&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://blog.purepistos.net/index.php/2008/11/18/ramaze-by-example/'&gt;Ramaze by Example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  <feedburner:origLink>http://www.jamesbritt.com/2008/11/19/why-ramaze-and-more-ramaze-by-example</feedburner:origLink></entry>
</feed>
