<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>jobs.joelonsoftware.com</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/</link>
<description>Job listings from Joel on Software.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>Copyright &#x00A9;2006-2007 Fog Creek Software, Inc. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
<managingEditor>customer-service@fogcreek.com (Fog Creek Software)</managingEditor>
<webMaster>customer-service@fogcreek.com (Fog Creek Software)</webMaster>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>3D software Engineer at Auryn, Inc (Los Angeles, CA  90045)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4471</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4471</guid>
<pubDate>23 Jan 2009 01:43:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Auryn is a next-generation publisher of animated digital content. <br />
<br />
Founded by experienced industry veterans and top academics, Auryn is breaking new grounds in the field of animated story telling. Its one-of-a-kind patented technologies makes possible visual styles deemed unfeasible with current animation technologies. <br />
<br />
Be a part of history. <br />
<br />
Main responsibilities include<br />
&#8226; Research and develop cutting edge computer graphics software for non-photoreal rendering and animation. <br />
&#8226; The individual will need to work in a team environment and should be excellent at oral and written communications. <br />
<br />
Qualifications<br />
<br />
&#8226; Programming experience required in C/C++, Mel,  Maya API, Python and Perl. At least 5 years experience in C++.  <br />
&#8226; Strong knowledge of rendering technologies. <br />
&#8226; Strong background required in computer graphics, computer vision, image processing and mathematics. <br />
&#8226; PyQT, Maya, GPU experience desirable. <br />
&#8226; Knowledge of Renderman, Mental Ray, Houdini a plus.  <br />
&#8226; Flexibility and willingness to work as part of a small, dynamic team. <br />
<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Email: amit@auryn.com</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Engineer at Yelp, Inc (San Francisco, CA)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4470</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4470</guid>
<pubDate>23 Jan 2009 01:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Is Yelp For You?<br />
<br />
    * Are you excited about transforming an entire industry?<br />
    * Do you get excited about building products for millions of people?<br />
    * Do you want to help people find the best local services by the building the right tools for them?<br />
<br />
If your blood is pumping now, Yelp is the place for you. Yelp is looking for experienced enthusiastic Software Engineers to play an important role on the Yelp development team. Our developers do it all - from frontend to backend.<br />
Requirements:<br />
<br />
    * Excellent knowledge of programming languages: Python / Java / PHP / Ruby or C/C++ (especially in a server-side context)<br />
    * Problem solving skills and the ability to write efficient code that scales well<br />
    * Flexibility: we are small company, but we move quickly<br />
    * Great communication skills<br />
    * Sense of humor<br />
<br />
Pluses:<br />
<br />
    * Experience with MySQL and/or Lucene<br />
    * Interest in fields of local search, social networking, blogging and related technologies, recommendation systems, and data mining<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? <a rel="nofollow" href="http://tbe.taleo.net/NA11/ats/careers/requisition.jsp?org=YELP&amp;cws=1&amp;rid=45">http://tbe.taleo.net/NA11/ats/careers/requisition.jsp?org=YELP&amp;cws=1&amp;rid=45</a></p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scientist - Decision Management at Charles River Analytics Inc (Cambridge, MA  02138)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4469</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4469</guid>
<pubDate>22 Jan 2009 20:34:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Charles River Analytics&#8217; Decision Management Systems Division designs and develops cutting-edge solutions to our customers&#8217; problems by applying the latest techniques from artificial intelligence, behavior modeling, cyber security, and computational optimization. We are looking for a research scientist with knowledge of one or more of these areas to join our team. As part of a small, elite team of researchers and software developers, you will be responsible for identifying innovative artificial intelligence solutions, supporting system architecture design, implementing prototype solutions, performing system simulation and analyses, and presenting our results to our customers. <br />
<br />
Minimum requirements include M.S. in a technical field or a B.S. with three years applicable experience. Candidates must possess strong verbal and written skills to support technical proposal writing and business development efforts, including interaction with customers and presentations at technical conferences. Experience with artificial intelligence, cognitive/behavior modeling, advanced optimization techniques, cyber security data fusion, data mining, statistics, and strong programming skills using JAVA, C#, and C++ will be considered a plus. <br />
<br />
Founded in 1983, Charles River Analytics has developed a variety of custom intelligent systems for a number of government and commercial customers. These systems range from individual autonomous robotic platforms to large-scale, multi-agent systems for information management, command, and control. Charles River has also developed trend-setting intelligent agent-based software products for personal computer platforms, agent-operated web-based services, and third-party application developers.<br />
<br />
At Charles River, we know that the key factor in our success over the past twenty-six years has been our ability to attract and retain a dedicated group of individuals who strive for personal excellence while contributing to our mutually supportive team. We are always interested in talking with bright, enthusiastic individuals who would thrive as members of our team. Our working environment is dynamic, collegial, and team-oriented. Our Principal Scientists actively participate in all project initiatives, and there are multiple opportunities for leadership at every level and in every area of the Company. Our established researchers and developers are true innovators with extensive publishing credits and nationwide peer recognition.<br />
<br />
We are proud to offer our employees a highly comprehensive and competitive benefits package including 100% paid medical and dental, life insurance, three weeks vacation, gym membership, incentive compensation, and a profit sharing/retirement plan with generous annual company contributions. Just minutes from Harvard Square, we enjoy the convenience of being on a busy MBTA bus route, and we also have plenty of parking for our staff and guests. To learn more, visit us at <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.cra.com">http://www.cra.com</a>.<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Please email resume to: jobs@cra.com INCLUDE CODE S-DM109 in the subject line. Or fax to: 617-868-0780. Reach Human Resources at: 617-491-3474, ext. 526 Charles River Analytics, 625 Mt. Auburn St., Cambridge, MA02138. <br />
Charles River Analytics is an Equal</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>eCommerce Web Programmer at Pro Athlete, Inc. (Kansas City, MO)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4467</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4467</guid>
<pubDate>21 Jan 2009 22:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Pro Athlete, Inc. an eCommerce company which owns and operates several websites providing sporting goods is looking for energetic, qualified candidates to fulfill the duties of a full-time Web Programmer.  This position is required to develop, test, and maintain website functions and applications as well as other duties reasonably assigned.<br />
<br />
The ideal candidate will possess the following:<br />
&#8226;	4+ Years Experience with .Net techologies (i.e. VB.NET and ASP.NET)<br />
&#8226;	Experience with web development (specifically e-commerce)<br />
&#8226;	Extensive experience with SQL Server 2000 or 2005<br />
&#8226;	Photoshop<br />
&#8226;	Crystal Reports<br />
&#8226;	API Integration Experience<br />
&#8226;	Bachelor&#8217;s Degree in Computer Science or Software Engineering<br />
<br />
Work samples will be required.<br />
<br />
Benefits include health, dental, and 401K.  Other benefits include an in-house chef, (all meals provided), exercise facility, batting cage, and employer matched charity program.<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Email clint@beapro.com</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Developer at BedandBreakfast.com (Austin, TX  78701)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4466</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4466</guid>
<pubDate>21 Jan 2009 20:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Job Description<br />
<br />
BedandBreakfast.com is looking for a Software Developer.  Candidates should have proven experience, or at least the ability to show potential, and the desire to learn.  Typically our developers own a project from start-to-finish &#8211; so being able to take responsibility and deliver is crucial.<br />
<br />
Detailed Requirements include experience with at least some of the following:<br />
&#8226;	Proven track record delivering high traffic web applications in .NET<br />
&#8226;	Expert in ASP.NET, C#, SQL, Html, Javascript, CSS<br />
&#8226;	Solid OO design/architecture skills<br />
&#8226;	Experienced in maintaining mission critical web servers and databases; ability to provide after hour response to production outages<br />
&#8226;	Excellent research and problem-solving skills<br />
&#8226;	Experience with mobile web development and UI design a plus<br />
<br />
About BedandBreakfast.com:<br />
<br />
BedandBreakfast.com is the  leading specialty lodging website.  Our employees benefit from competitive pay, a great team-oriented office environment in downtown Austin, and learning about many aspects of an online business.  BedandBreakfast.com has a diverse business that includes everything from partnerships with Expedia and hotels.com, to sales of Gift Cards through retailers like Costco, Safeway, Walmart, Office Depot, CVS Pharmacy, Randalls, Winn Dixie, and others, to sales of a Microsoft Certified distributed application to the lodging industry.  Our staff is made up of experienced leaders with backgrounds in travel, technology, retail, publishing, and telecom.  Our employee turnover is minimal, the company is profitable, and is the dominant player in the B&amp;B and Inn space.<br />
<br />
We provide a highly competitive benefits package, including 15 days of PTO (paid time off), generous Health, Dental, Life, and Disability Insurance, a 401(k) savings plan, and pre-tax Flexible Spending Accounts for Health and Dependent Care expenses. <br />
</p>
<p>Interested? email mgregory@bedandbreakfast.com<br />
</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lead QA Engineer at Central Desktop, Inc (Anaheim, CA  92808)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4465</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4465</guid>
<pubDate>21 Jan 2009 19:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.centraldesktop.com"><img align="right" src="http://www.centraldesktop.com/i/logo.gif" border="none" /></a>Overview<br />
We are looking for talented and motivated QA Engineers to join our team. You will be ON the Software Development team working in a collaborative, not adversarial, environment. You must believe a product is only as good as its test suite. You will take the lead in all aspects of QA including test automation, manual testing and coordinating part time internal and external testers.<br />
<br />
You will OWN the QA process but overall product quality is the responsibility of the ENTIRE engineering team.<br />
<br />
<br />
Responsibilities<br />
* Own and drive software quality assurance lifecycle as part of SCRUM/Agile processes<br />
* Deliver high quality releases on time.<br />
* Design test plans, test cases and automate/implement test cases.<br />
* Assist Engineers with unit testing. Be the advocate for improving code coverage and test effectiveness.<br />
* Conduct white box and gray box testing. Perform API level testing.<br />
* Maintain regression suite.<br />
* Participate in story and task estimation.<br />
<br />
Skills<br />
* 3+ years experience in Software QA with focus on web based applications<br />
* Experience with Unix or Unix like systems.<br />
* Experience with test driven development, either in a QA or a developer role.<br />
* Experience with test automation<br />
* Experience with at least four of the following: PHP, HTML, CSS, XML, JavaScript/AJAX, SQL, HTTP. Java is a plus.<br />
* Experience testing large-scale web applications running on multiple servers<br />
* Experience with tools like Ant, JUnit, PhpUnit, HtmlUnit, Selenium, JMeter<br />
* Familiarity with Continuous Integration.<br />
* Knowledge of Agile, SCRUM, and XP a huge plus.<br />
<br />
Compensation<br />
DOE: Competitive salary, good benifits<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Email your resume and a *PERSONALIZED* cover letter to jobs@centraldesktop.com</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>C# Software Developer - &quot;MailStore&quot; E-mail Archive at deepinvent Software GmbH (Viersen, Germany)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4463</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4463</guid>
<pubDate>21 Jan 2009 12:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.mailstore.com"><img align="right" src="http://www.mailstore.com/images/boxserver180.jpg" border="none" /></a>The German company deepinvent Software GmbH, located in the greater Duesseldorf area, is specialized in the development and sales of e-mail archiving solutions for small- and medium sized enterprises. The dynamically growing IT Company is controlled by its owners, offering the MailStore archiving solutions to an international market.<br />
With over 250.000 users, the freeware MailStore Home undoubtedly constitutes the most widespread e-mail-archiving solution worldwide. The software's quality and level of innovation is additionally highlighted by the international trade press on a regular basis.<br />
<br />
About the position<br />
<br />
We are looking for a talented software developer who helps us improve our MailStore product line (<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.mailstore.com/en/">http://www.mailstore.com/en/</a>).<br />
<br />
Technology<br />
<br />
The MailStore product line is built primarily with C# (some Win32 parts written in Delphi)<br />
<br />
Responsibilities<br />
<br />
&#8226; Participate in all activities of development including requirements analysis, estimation, architecture, coding, testing, change management, and deployment<br />
&#8226; Apply automated processes for testing and application deployment<br />
&#8226; Monitor application performance and troubleshoot problems<br />
&#8226; Deliver high quality technical solutions<br />
<br />
Requirements<br />
<br />
&#8226; Three or more years of experience in software engineering<br />
&#8226; Knowledge of C#, .NET, and Win32 technology and knowledge of database software<br />
&#8226; Excellent design, development, and debugging skills<br />
&#8226; Ability to write secure software (MailStore Server is a high-load 3-tier software). Awareness of which errors can lead to software vulnerabilities (at least <a rel="nofollow" href="http://cwe.mitre.org/top25/">http://cwe.mitre.org/top25/</a>)<br />
&#8226; Experience as member of multi-person software development team<br />
&#8226; Strong written and verbal communication skills<br />
&#8226; Excellent written and spoken German and English<br />
&#8226; Experience a plus but not required &#8211; Firebird SQL, MAPI, Exchange Server, Lotus Notes, Lucene<br />
&#8226; ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, AJAX experience a strong plus<br />
&#8226; Legal right to work in Germany<br />
<br />
What we offer<br />
<br />
&#8226; Work on a software that is used by hundreds of thousands of people over the world, and that is regularly reviewed by major computer magazines (such as ComputerBILD, CHIP, PC World etc.)<br />
&#8226; A fun and exciting start-up environment with a bright young team guided by experienced entrepreneurs<br />
&#8226; Competitive compensation package<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Please send your resume via email: jobs at deepinvent.com. In your cover letter, please include your high/low salary requirements and please explain why this role seems like a good match for you. Qualified applicants will be responded to as quickly as pos</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Development Programmer - Surveying Applications at ESRI (Redlands, CA  92373)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4462</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4462</guid>
<pubDate>21 Jan 2009 01:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Be a key technical member of the survey development team working to envision, design, and develop cutting-edge survey applications. This is a challenging opportunity to utilize your solid software engineering background, core programming skills, and passion for development.<br />
<br />
As part of the software engineering team at ESRI, you will help build cutting-edge software in areas including 2D and 3D visualization and spatial analysis, robust server-based GIS development using the latest platforms, and industry standard enterprise architectures such as SOA. Working in a creative and challenging team setting, your contributions will have a real impact on the next generation of our innovative geospatial analysis, modeling, and visualization technology. <br />
<br />
Responsibilities:<br />
Envision, design, and develop software for survey solutions, working with ArcGIS Server, ArcGIS Mobile, and ArcGIS Desktop.<br />
Work closely with programmers, product engineers, and business partners to provide cutting-edge solutions for ESRI customers.<br />
Apply good software design and development practices in daily activities.<br />
Write comprehensive technical specifications and support documentation.<br />
Actively and effectively participate in various activities within the software development life cycle.<br />
<br />
Requirements:<br />
Bachelors, masters, or Ph.D. in computer science, geography, surveying, or a GIS-related field, depending upon position level.<br />
Three or more years of experience in design and development.<br />
Strong Windows background.<br />
In-depth knowledge of C++ and COM technology.<br />
Ability to clearly analyze/describe a problem and propose a solution.<br />
Excellent problem solving, design, development, and debugging skills.<br />
Ability to work with a team in a constantly challenging environment.<br />
Excellent verbal and written communication skills.<br />
<br />
Recommended Qualifications:<br />
Experience with GIS, surveying, and/or cadastral applications.<br />
Knowledge of C#, .NET, and MFC/WIN32 technology.<br />
Knowledge of commercial RDBMS software.<br />
Ability to rapidly prototype applications to showcase new ideas.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Since 1969, ESRI has been giving customers around the world the power to think and plan geographically. We develop and support innovative tools for visualizing, analyzing, and managing geographic data on the desktop, on a server, across the enterprise, in a mobile environment, and on the Web. With annual revenues of $660 million and our software used in more than 300,000 organizations worldwide, ESRI is the market leader in GIS. <br />
 <br />
ESRI employs 2,700 people in the U.S., 1,900 of whom are based at our Redlands headquarters, a community ideally located in Southern California. We offer exceptional benefits, competitive salaries, 401(k) and profit sharing programs, scholarships, tuition assistance, a Cafe complete with Starbucks coffee bar, an onsite fitness center, and much more. <br />
<br />
ESRI is an equal opportunity employer (EOE) supporting diversity in the workforce.</p>
<p>Interested? Learn more about a career in Software Engineering at ESRI and apply online at www.esri.com/programmers.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>IT Project Manager at ESRI (Redlands, CA  92373)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4461</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4461</guid>
<pubDate>21 Jan 2009 00:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Apply your project management and relationship building skills to guide cross-functional teams of programmers, software architects, and business analysts. This is a challenging opportunity to collaborate with others to identify, research, implement, and maintain technology solutions that support the business objectives of ESRI.<br />
<br />
Technical expertise. Good communication skills. The ability to analyze and solve problems. These are some of the characteristics members of our IT team share. They use these skills to manage advanced technologies in all aspects of computer network, telecommunications, and business application development. We are looking for people who thrive in a team environment and have a passion for designing, developing, and supporting new applications and computer systems technologies.<br />
<br />
Responsibilities:<br />
Gather business requirements and offer critical assessment and recommendation concerning the viability of proposed projects to management including anticipated resource requirements and project risks.<br />
Develop and maintain project plans, task lists, goals, and timetables that meet project objectives.<br />
Understand and implement strong software development life cycle practices among projects and team members.<br />
Promote the professional development of assigned staff.<br />
Negotiate and resolve technical alternatives with project team members.<br />
Collaborate with other project managers regarding their responsibilities including regular communication about shared opportunities or possible shared risks.<br />
When efficient and effective, organize and lead cross-functional teams.<br />
<br />
Requirements:<br />
Bachelors or masters in information technology, computer science, or related field.<br />
Previous professional work experience with hands-on software or Internet applications programming.<br />
Experience analyzing and defining business requirements and processes as they relate to technology solutions including the ability to determine project benefits in context to the cost of the solution&#8217;s design, development, and integration.<br />
Aptitude towards identifying root issues and determining best solutions.<br />
Project management and leadership experience that focuses on the effort of engaging others in the delivery and execution of technical solutions.<br />
Ability to identify and drive a phased development and release approach to application development in an agile manner.<br />
Ability to develop relationships with clients through the use of strong communication, collaboration, and negotiation skills.<br />
<br />
Recommended Qualifications:<br />
MBA or additional certifications in project management such as PMP.<br />
Previous work experience in quality assurance programming, software testing, or process improvement within the software development life cycle. <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
Since 1969, ESRI has been giving customers around the world the power to think and plan geographically. We develop and support innovative tools for visualizing, analyzing, and managing geographic data on the desktop, on a server, across the enterprise, in a mobile environment, and on the Web. With annual revenues of $660 million and our software used in more than 300,000 organizations worldwide, ESRI is the market leader in GIS. <br />
 <br />
ESRI employs 2,700 people in the U.S., 1,900 of whom are based at our Redlands headquarters. We offer exceptional benefits, competitive salaries, 401(k) and profit sharing programs, scholarships, tuition assistance, a Cafe complete with Starbucks coffee bar, an onsite fitness center, and much more. <br />
<br />
<br />
ESRI is an equal opportunity employer (EOE) supporting diversity in the workforce.</p>
<p>Interested? Learn more about a career in Information Technology at ESRI and apply online at www.esri.com/careers/it.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Senior Data Analyst at GrayHair Software Inc (Telecommute)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4460</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4460</guid>
<pubDate>20 Jan 2009 22:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Immediate opportunity for a &#8220;Senior Data Analyst&#8221; at fast growing Mail Technology company headquartered in Mt. Laurel, New Jersey.  The absolute key for this job is strong critical thinking skills and an analytical mindset.  <br />
<br />
The &#8220;Right&#8221; candidate must have the following technical &amp; behavioral skill set:<br />
&#8226;Must be comfortable in guiding/advising and interacting with clients of various levels. <br />
&#8226;Must be able to obtain information from other sources to validate &amp; confirm results while maintaining status information on the disposition of accounts in production process. <br />
&#8226;Must possess the ability to write effectively, demonstrating and presenting the results of analysis conducted.  <br />
&#8226;Demonstrate ability to learn new technology and industries.<br />
&#8226;Ability to work independently with limited supervision and complete complex analysis. <br />
&#8226;Possess a minimum of (5) yrs working experience with database applications and data analysis. <br />
&#8226;Ability to create and manipulate spreadsheets and PowerPoint presentation materials.  <br />
&#8226;Must possess bachelors&#8217; degree in technical or scientific field or related field.<br />
<br />
Additional preferred factors:<br />
1.Experience with Crystal reports<br />
2.Knowledge of the postal industry or other government regulated industries<br />
3.Working knowledge of Domestic Mail Manual with particular knowledge in postal address management programs such as (NCOA, ACS, CASS, MASS and DSF2).<br />
4.Experience with statistical analysis tools/languages, SAS, SPSS, R<br />
5.Experience with building and validating statistical models<br />
6.Knowledge of PAVE regulations preferred<br />
7.SQL server expertise is a plus<br />
8.Experience in software, direct mailing/marketing arenas is a huge plus<br />
9.Master degree in statistics or similar technical field<br />
<br />
GrayHair Software offers an excellent compensation &amp; benefits package. This position offers a unique telecommuting benefit however travel to office and/or customer site (1) out of every (3) weeks is required. <br />
<br />
Please submit resumes w/ salary reqs. for consideration to the Vice President of Human Resources - dlemon@grayhairsoftware.com.<br />
  <br />
<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Please submit resumes w/ salary reqs. for consideration to the Vice President of Human Resources - dlemon@grayhairsoftware.com.<br />
</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Web Developer, PHP/Java at SumoBrain (Perry Hall, MD  21128)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4458</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4458</guid>
<pubDate>20 Jan 2009 18:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.freepatentsonline.com"><img align="right" src="http://www.ryley.com/376x90-sb-logo.jpg" border="none" /></a>We run several web sites, with the best known being FreePatentsOnline.com and SumoBrain.com -- both patent-oriented. However, patents is only the beginning.<br />
<br />
Our mission is to aggregate large quantities of data in the technical, scientific, and medical arenas, bringing them to the masses with greater ease of use and more powerful search tools. So, don't let the name fool you -- we are not just about patents.<br />
<br />
FreePatentsOnline.com gets millions of hits per month, has a full-text database running into the hundreds of gigabytes, has terabytes of associated images, and has the best search and account features on the web in the free patent searching space.<br />
<br />
In addition to constantly improving freepatentsonline.com and sumobrain.com, we are ready to launch a new site in the biomedical space, and have other sites on the drawing board.<br />
<br />
The development we do is complex. Our hardware infrastructure consists of hundreds of servers and associated devices and the amount of data we work with, and trhe nubmer of hits our sites get, requires excellent architecting and coding.<br />
<br />
We need excellent, intelligent, programmers who are intellectually thirsty, want to work on tough, interesting problems, and understand the web and associated technologies intimately.<br />
<br />
We primarily develop in Java and PHP, and familiarity with one or both of these is a prerequisite. Some of the other technologies we use include MySQL and Lucene.<br />
<br />
We are committed to a great working environment with excellent tools and hardware. Our tools include SVN and the entire Atlassian suite (Crucible, Fisheye, JIRA, Wiki, Greenhopper), and all developers have state-of-the-art multi-monitor machines.<br />
<br />
This job offers technical challenges, a large degree of autonomy, and the chance to work with a great team.  Plus, all our sites are free (monetized with AdSense -- we are Google premium partners and have truly world-class knowledge in this space) so you can feel good about the fact that you are helping scientists, doctors, students, and many others worldwide!</p>
<p>Interested? Please send resume with cover letter to jryley@freepatentsonline.com and erik.reeves@sumobrain.com</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Engineer - Java Web Applications Developer at Rally Software Development (Boulder, CO)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4457</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4457</guid>
<pubDate>20 Jan 2009 18:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Rally is a dynamic start-up that provides software-driven enterprises a complete solution of knowledge, coaching and tooling to succeed with Agile, the next generation of software development practices. We are recognized nationally as the best product in our category (Jolt Award 2006 - 2008), locally as the most innovative product (IQ Awards) and as a top &quot;Best company to work for in Colorado&quot; 2006 - 2008.<br />
<br />
SOFTWARE ENGINEERS/JAVA WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPERS looking for work/life balance? Want to work in a highly creative, collaborative environment where you can stand-up and contribute? Enjoy the beautiful Rocky Mountains every day and 300+ days of sunshine every year?<br />
<br />
Rally Software Development (www.rallydev.com) located in Boulder, Colorado is a dynamic, growing company that provides software-driven enterprises with the knowledge, coaching and tooling needed to succeed with Agile development practices. By joining our agile software development team, you will be a part of a group building a collaborative platform for agile software teams of all sizes. Enjoy all the benefits of working with the hottest technologies in small, highly collaborative teams while we service users in 20+ countries and 50% of the largest software development firms in the world from a hosted platform.<br />
<br />
Responsibilities include:<br />
Designing, developing and testing a rich browser based application.<br />
Ideal candidates will have experience in the following:<br />
- Experience writing rich, browser based GUIs<br />
- Java (will accept C# programmers who would like to do Java Web Application programming)<br />
- Spring<br />
- Servlet 2.0 Web-App development<br />
- JavaScript (YUI or script.aculo.us a plus)<br />
- AJAX<br />
- O/R Mapping<br />
- SQL and Relational database experience<br />
- A history of successful delivery and career progression in software development.<br />
- Prior experience building scalable solutions.<br />
- The experience and skills to understand our entire scope of products and process.<br />
- A track record of collaboratively designing, developing and testing database driven web applications.<br />
- Mad foosball skills.<br />
<br />
Culture:<br />
To coordinate four teams, we do pull-based release planning, lock our release train and make and meet our publicly, committed releases eight time per year. Our daily visibility is high with automated tests coverage, and immediate code quality reporting. Productive and skilled object-oriented developers who can collaborate do well in our environment. The core values at Rally center on employees understanding their personal and professional goals and regularly making and meeting daily, iteration and release commitments. You will find Rally makes decisions through a highly creative and collaborative process and our employees stand-up and contribute. As a Boulder company, we strive to maintain a work/life balance and give back to the community. We are recognized as the best product in our category through the Jolt Product Excellence Award in 2006, 2007 and 2008, received recognition as one of the best companies to work for in Colorado in 2006, 2007 and 2008, and were named the #1 fastest-growing company in 2007 by the Boulder County Business Report. We fielded five Boulder Peak Triathlon relay teams and continually give back 1% of our time to the non-profit community. Rally has also set aside 1% of its equity, upon founding, as part of Entrepreneurs Foundation of Colorado.<br />
<br />
At Rally we're looking for people who are passionate about the software industry and want to work with the best and brightest. We value teamwork, the ability to meet commitments as well as skill and a successful track record. We strive for a healthy, productive work/life balance, while enjoying the opportunity to substantially contribute to the direction and success of a vibrant software business. Rally offers excellent compensation, benefits and stock options with an exceptional opportunity to grow. If it sounds like you might thrive in an environment like this, we'd like to hear from you.</p>
<p>Interested? Please apply via our Careers section on our website @ www.rallydev.com.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Web Development Manager at TheLadders.com (New York, NY)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4454</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4454</guid>
<pubDate>19 Jan 2009 23:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p><br />
TheLadders was named one of the 2009 Best Companies to Work for in New York and we&#8217;re looking for a Development Manager! <br />
<br />
Silicon Alley Insider Names TheLadders most valuable Digital Startup in NYC!<br />
<br />
The Ladders is one of fastest growing companies in the US with 300+ employees. Our Technology Department is experiencing unprecedented growth and as a result we are currently looking to hire multiple Software Engineers, Web Developers, and Managers for our Tech Department. If you have a strong background in Web 2.0 in a Java environment, passion for cutting edge technology and solving live production problems &#8211; TheLadders might be the place for you!<br />
<br />
We are looking for a highly technical Development Manager who can drive projects and provide leadership for our engineers in an innovative and fast paced environment. You will be responsible for the overall planning, execution, and success of several projects. We are looking for someone with a passion for technology coupled with great communication skills. We are seeking a hard-working, adaptable problem solver, who loves challenges and feels comfortable working directly with marketing, product, creative and other teams. <br />
<br />
This position will lead an advanced technology team using new programming paradigms such as Agile/Test Driven Development and industry leading technologies such as the Spring Framework, AJAX, Lucene, design patterns, etc. This is a fast, open environment where innovation and participation is encouraged through blogging, custom tool development, hack-day events or other out-of-the-box techniques. <br />
<br />
Responsibilities<br />
<br />
&#8226;	Provide leadership and mentoring to Engineering staff<br />
&#8226;	Create and document the technical design to meet requirements<br />
&#8226;	Ownership and development of end-to-end projects using both Java backend and web technologies<br />
&#8226;	Participate in the creation of project plans, resource allocation and estimated timelines<br />
&#8226;	Strong attention to detail; passion for technology, challenging environments and excellence<br />
&#8226;	Excellent communication skills a must<br />
&#8226;	Interact with the business owners, product and quality assurance teams to set priorities and resolve defects, change requests and issues<br />
&#8226;	Work with the following technologies: Java, Spring, JSP, MySQL, Tomcat, Lucene, Javascript, Ant/Ivy, CVS<br />
<br />
Requirements<br />
<br />
&#8226;	6+ years experience as a developer including at least 2 years in a management capacity<br />
&#8226;	Experience developing J2EE applications using both backend Java and web technologies, e.g. JavaScript, JSTL, AJAX<br />
&#8226;	Strong communication skills <br />
&#8226;	Ability to understand business needs and liaise with business owners <br />
&#8226;	Ability to problem solve and troubleshoot issues<br />
&#8226;	Fluent in creating project plans and managing to them<br />
&#8226;	Experience developing and deploying a production system on the Unix platform (Linux preferred)<br />
&#8226;	Must know how to architect scalable, robust, highly available high performing web sites and have in-depth knowledge of web development methodologies, tools and techniques<br />
&#8226;	Must have strong understanding of relational database concepts including SQL, indexes, transactions and writing software that communicates with a database<br />
&#8226;	BS in Computer Science or related field, or equivalent experience<br />
<br />
TheLadders.com is the world's largest online service catering exclusively to the $100k+ career marketplace. Located in New York and London, we make the global search for senior talent and senior positions quick and effective. We give professionals the most senior-level job leads in one place and organize them by function for more efficient searching. Through TheLadders.com and our UK site, TheLadders.co.uk, we give our members the tools they need to take their next career step. Top recruiters value the ability to quickly and easily connect with qualified talent. Founded in 2003, TheLadders.com has grown into the largest specialty employment website with over 1,800,000 members and 35,000 recruiters. To learn more about TheLadders.com, pl</p>
<p>Interested? Please submit resume at <a rel="nofollow" href="http://hostedjobs.openhire.com/epostings/jobs/submit.cfm?fuseaction=dspjob&amp;id=23&amp;jobid=275730&amp;company_id=15772&amp;version=1&amp;source=ONLINE&amp;JobOwner=988183&amp;level=levelid2&amp;levelid2=23018&amp;parent=Technology%3B%3B%3BSoftware%20Development&amp;s">http://hostedjobs.openhire.com/epostings/jobs/submit.cfm?fuseaction=dspjob&amp;id=23&amp;jobid=275730&amp;company_id=15772&amp;version=1&amp;source=ONLINE&amp;JobOwner=988183&amp;level=levelid2&amp;levelid2=23018&amp;parent=Technology%3B%3B%3BSoftware%20Development&amp;s</a></p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Software Developer at Two Sigma Solutions (New York, NY)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4451</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4451</guid>
<pubDate>16 Jan 2009 23:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Our software developers hail from a broad range of backgrounds and experience levels, coming together to work as one highly motivated, dynamic technology team. They face a wide array of technical challenges, including those involving high-performance distributed systems and real-time applications. We're always looking for new talent to join this energetic team of high achievers, a group that includes PhDs from top universities, as well as other accomplished professionals. <br />
<br />
Our developers all have at minimum a bachelor's degree in computer science and experience using several different programming languages including Java. Successful candidates will typically have strong analytical and organizational skills, exceptional programming skills, a true love of building quality software and a team spirit. Large-scale systems experience is highly desirable. Finance experience is not necessary.<br />
<br />
What We Offer<br />
<br />
Two Sigma offers a friendly, casual, stimulating work environment and a culture of respect. In addition to competitive compensation, our comprehensive benefits package includes a voluntary deferred compensation plan, a 401(K) plan with company match, excellent medical, dental and prescription drug plans, and more.<br />
<br />
Two Sigma is an Equal Opportunity Employer. In order to provide equal employment opportunities to all individuals, employment decisions at Two Sigma will be based on merit, qualifications and abilities. No applicant or employee should be treated less favorably on the grounds of his/her gender, marital status, pregnancy, race, color, ethnicity, national origin, disability, sexual orientation, age, religious belief, military service eligibility, veteran status or any other protected class. Simply put, we are committed to providing equal employment opportunities for all.<br />
<br />
For more information on Two Sigma, visit our website at www.twosigma.com.<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? <a rel="nofollow" href="http://tbe.taleo.net/NA2/ats/careers/requisition.jsp?org=TWOSIGMA&amp;cws=1&amp;rid=49">http://tbe.taleo.net/NA2/ats/careers/requisition.jsp?org=TWOSIGMA&amp;cws=1&amp;rid=49</a></p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Java Web Developer at CR England (Salt Lake City, UT  84120)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4450</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4450</guid>
<pubDate>16 Jan 2009 23:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p>CR England, one of the nation's largest refrigerated trucking companies, is looking for an experienced Java Web Developer to develop and maintain Java based web applications.<br />
<br />
Primary responsibilities include all or a combination of the following:<br />
Java Web Application Design and Development<br />
Meet with client business users and IT staff<br />
Analyze and evaluate IT projects<br />
Develop project plans and strategy<br />
Build new and enhance existing software applications<br />
Assist in developing training and support process, as needed<br />
<br />
Required Technical Experience:<br />
5+ years designing/building software applications<br />
3+years Hands-on Java experience<br />
Proven track record accomplishing organizational goals<br />
Excellent written and verbal communication skills<br />
Strong analytical skills, attention to detail, and problem solving<br />
J2EE, Hibernate, Spring,Flex, JSP, ANT, Maven<br />
<br />
Preferred Experience:<br />
Bachelor of Science, Information Technology or Computer Science<br />
Technical Certifications<br />
Apache Tomcat<br />
DB2, SQL server<br />
Search Engine Optimization<br />
OOD/OOP skills and experience applying modern design patterns<br />
Knowledge relational database design<br />
Technical Certifications<br />
Agile, (Scrum, Crystal, eXtreme Programming-XP) experience<br />
<br />
<br />
R England offers a competitive benefits package that includes, medical, dental, life insurance, vision, vacation, and 401K.<br />
<br />
Additional benefits include:<br />
<br />
On-site gym, <br />
Company sponsored Weight Watchers program, <br />
Medical clinic, chiropractor, and masseuse <br />
On-site vehicle leasing program for all employees. <br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
We are looking for individuals that are looking for a career not just a job.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
CR England is located in Salt Lake City, Utah; home of the 2002 Winter Olympics, minutes from ten ski resorts, mountain biking, and a number of hiking trails.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Please apply at: <a rel="nofollow" href="http://crengland.iapplicants.com/">http://crengland.iapplicants.com/</a> or fax resume to 801-977-6691<br />
</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Crazy-Smart Ruby Developer, Shop It To Me, Inc. (San Francisco, at Shop It To Me, Inc. (San Francisco, CA  94107)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4448</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4448</guid>
<pubDate>16 Jan 2009 18:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.shopittome.com"><img align="right" src="http://asset1.shopittome.com/images/logo.gif" border="none" /></a>Are you a crazy-good developer who is proficient in Ruby, loves tough challenges, working with an all-star team and is looking to help build the next big thing? Have you had that epiphany when you finally get 'metaprogramming'?<br />
<br />
Check out Shop It To Me, a small (under 10 employees), hot, profitable startup in the online shopping space. We're looking for 1-2 smart developers to help us build our next-generation shopping personalization engine.<br />
<br />
We're growing exponentially, have been described by Sara Lacy at Business Week as the &quot;Twitter of Shopping Applications&quot;, and recently have been featured on NBC, MSNBC, CBS, and Fox news. We are growing so fast, we now need a couple key developers to help us!<br />
<br />
You'll be working in a fun environment near South Park in SF with an all-star team. Your work will be appreciated by millions of adoring users.<br />
<br />
We are limiting space to 1-2 top-tier developers right now and we are picky, so if you are interested, please check your requirements and follow the instructions below.<br />
<br />
Required<br />
    * Thorough knowledge of Ruby and Ruby On Rails<br />
    * Solid understanding of object oriented design and patterns<br />
    * Understands web development languages and protocols (HTTP, HTML, CSS, AJAX, Javascript)<br />
    * Able to write scalable SQL<br />
    * Enjoys working on a small, quick-moving team of high quality.<br />
    * Takes pride in the quality of his/her work and the work of his/her team.<br />
<br />
<br />
Considered a plus:<br />
    * Experience with capistrano, sphinx, god (the monitoring tool, not the deity), puppet.<br />
    * Java knowledge and experience<br />
    * Linux knowledge<br />
    * SMTP, spam filtering, DomainKeys, and/or postfix<br />
    * Experience and desire to scale a web/email service<br />
</p>
<p>Interested? Email jobs@shopittome.com with your resume and a brief note explaining why you are interested in working at Shop It To Me. For fun, tell us the results of the Ruby code on this page:<br />
<a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.shopittome.com/employment/rubydeveloper">http://www.shopittome.com/employment/rubydeveloper</a><br />
</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Developer at ChildPlus Software (Atlanta, GA)</title>
<link>http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4447</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://jobs.joelonsoftware.com/default.asp?4447</guid>
<pubDate>16 Jan 2009 15:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.childplus.com"><img align="right" src="http://www.childplus.com/images/cplogo_home.jpg" border="none" /></a>ChildPlus is a 25 year old organization specializing in high-tech solutions for preschools.<br />
<br />
We develop primarily in C# and use IIS and SQL Server.  Our product employs a WinForms application web-deployed via VMWare ThinApp communicating with IIS Web Services and SQL Server.<br />
<br />
As a member of our small team of software engineers, you will have a significant voice in how we develop software.  You will also have a significant voice in design and development decisions and will work closely with system designers to help shape the optimum solution to each problem.<br />
<br />
Our unique optional weekend work queue has a constant supply of tasks with dollar amounts associated.  Bored one weekend?  Knock out a few tasks from the queue and earn an extra $1,000.<br />
<br />
ChildPlus is a solid, stable, family-owned company and provides a friendly, relaxed working environment.  Our flex time policy suits any personality from early riser to late sleeper.<br />
<br />
Please contact us for more information.<br />
<br />
<br />
Skills you will need include: <br />
&gt;&gt; NET/C# - 2+ years<br />
&gt;&gt; SQL Server &#8211; 2+ years<br />
&gt;&gt; Excellent written and verbal communication skills in English<br />
&gt;&gt; Permanent right to work in the United States<br />
<br />
<br />
Helpful skills:<br />
&gt;&gt; Crystal Reports<br />
&gt;&gt; Developer Express Windows Forms Components<br />
&gt;&gt; Developer Express XtraReports Suite<br />
&gt;&gt; Experience with Agile Methodologies</p>
<p>Interested? Sumbit resume to: careers@childplus.com.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>
</channel></rss>