<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-us" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Joyeur</title>
<subtitle type="text">The Joyent Weblog</subtitle>
<link rel="self" href="http://www.joyeur.com/atom/" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/" />
<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2005:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1</id>
<generator uri="http://textpattern.com/" version="4.0.6">Textpattern</generator>
<updated>2009-01-19T22:48:44Z</updated>
<author>
		<name>Joyent Inc.</name>
		
		<uri>http://www.joyeur.com/</uri>
</author>

<entry>
		<author>
			<name>David Young</name>
		</author>
		<published>2009-01-19T22:43:05Z</published>
		<updated>2009-01-19T22:48:44Z</updated>
		<title type="html">The Dark Star Is Born</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2009/01/19/the-dark-star-is-born" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2009-01-19:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/497cf7f3373402c779a48d33ff08a45f</id>
		<category term="Industry" />
		<category term="Industry" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>With Cisco&#8217;s announcement that the company is getting into the server business (<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/01/20/technology/companies/20cisco.html">news here</a>), it is easily seen that all infrastructure businesses are collapsing into vertically integrated entities. This, in my opinion, is especially true/possible in the cloud. Why not offer all the primitives: compute, networking, storage? Why not offer cloud management software? Why offer all the web services need by developers and customers? Everything and all collapses into a dense, dark star.</p>

	<p>Cisco just became a non-virtual, fully integrated systems company&#8230;just as everyone is moving on to be completely virtual.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Benjamin Black</name>
		</author>
		<published>2009-01-17T00:28:37Z</published>
		<updated>2009-01-18T04:17:54Z</updated>
		<title type="html">The new library</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2009/01/17/the-new-library" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2009-01-17:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/fed58032750b96f9950cbc297d0c61f3</id>
		<category term="Industry" />
		<category term="general" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>Time was you did systems and networking work, you had The Library.  <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Programming-Perl-3rd-Larry-Wall/dp/0596000278">Programming Perl</a> , <a href="http://www.amazon.com/sendmail-4th-Bryan-Costales/dp/0596510292">sendmail</a> , <a href="http://www.amazon.com/DNS-BIND-5th-Cricket-Liu/dp/0596100574"><span class="caps">DNS</span> and Bind</a> , <a href="http://www.amazon.com/TCP-Illustrated-Protocols-Addison-Wesley-Professional/dp/0201633469"><span class="caps">TCP</span>/IP Illustrated</a> , <a href="http://www.amazon.com/UNIX-System-Administration-Handbook-3rd/dp/0130206016"><span class="caps">UNIX</span> System Administration Handbook</a> .  These books documented the core knowledge to operate effectively in our industry.  You&#8217;d add others as your level of badassery increased, perhaps <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Mastering-Regular-Expressions-Jeffrey-Friedl/dp/0596528124">Mastering Regular Expressions</a> , <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Internet-Routing-Architectures-Networking-Technology/dp/157870233X">Internet Routing Architectures</a> , or <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Programming-Environment-Addison-Wesley-Professional-Computing/dp/0201433079"><span class="caps">APUE</span></a> , depending on your passions and your role.</p>

	<p>Times have changed.  You still need to have all the old knowledge, but you need quite a bit more to meet the bar in the modern, massive-scale, online services world.  Thousands of servers, distributed storage, databases with billions of rows, real-time monitoring of it all.  The books below should be in your library and considered core for you and anyone else in the field.</p>

	<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Scalable-Internet-Architectures-Developers-Library/dp/067232699X">Scalable Internet Architectures</a> by Theo Schlossnagle</p>

	<p>Architecture is the most important thing in building and operating a scalable service, and this book is the best book around on the topic.  Read it, internalize its message, build better systems.  I&#8217;ve never met him, but all signs point to Theo being an awesome guy, to boot.  His blog is <a href="http://lethargy.org/~jesus/">here</a> .</p>

	<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Solaris-Performance-Tools-Techniques-OpenSolaris/dp/0131568191">Solaris Performance and Tools</a> by Richard McDougall, Jim Mauro, and Brendan Gregg</p>

	<p>You&#8217;ve got your badass architecture laid out, code written, now what?  You need visibility as far into your system as you can manage so you know the state of the world and where you can make the most impact in server and application performance.  Enter DTrace.  Yes, this is a book about Solaris, but DTrace is built into OS X and FreeBSD (and Apache, thanks, Theo!) now, as well.  DTrace is a quiet revolution in system performance monitoring.  Master it.</p>

	<p>A couple of the authors blog often enough to matter: Richard McDougall&#8217;s is <a href="http://blog.richardmcdougall.com/">here</a> and Brendan Gregg&#8217;s is <a href="http://bdgregg.blogspot.com/">here</a> .</p>

	<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/High-Performance-MySQL-Optimization-Replication/dp/0596101716">High Performance MySQL</a> by Baron Schwartz, Peter Zaitsev, Vadim Tkachenko, Jeremy Zawodny, Arjen Lentz, and Derek Balling</p>

	<p>Database tuning has always been a bit of voodoo to me, perhaps because most of my exposure to it has been ninjas like the DB architects at Amazon tuning Oracle to within an inch of its life.  This book demystifies the space, and thank goodness, because you are going to need it to get the most out of your infrastructure.  How can you go wrong with folks like Jeremy Zawodny?  You can&#8217;t.  Here&#8217;s his <a href="http://jeremy.zawodny.com/blog/">blog</a> .</p>

	<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/High-Performance-Web-Sites-Essential/dp/0596529309">High Performance Web Sites</a> by Steve Souders</p>

	<p>You&#8217;ve mastered your architecture, instrumented your servers, and learned to tune the crap out of your databases.  Now you can, and should, turn your attention to the performance experienced by your users.  That was the whole point, right?  Steve Souders created YSlow while Chief Performance Yahoo! at the purple giant, and is now doing similarly useful work at the <span class="caps">GOOG</span>.  Follow him <a href="http://stevesouders.com/">here</a> .</p>

	<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Art-Capacity-Planning-Scaling-Resources/dp/0596518579">The Art of Capacity Planning</a> by John Allspaw</p>

	<p>Let&#8217;s get this out of the way: I love this book!  Allspaw knows capacity planning for online services because he lives and breathes it and his passion comes through clearly in his writing.  Think &#8220;the cloud&#8221; world of dynamic, on-demand resources free you from having to do real capacity planning?  Think again.  Now you have to do it even faster and the flexibility of the new tools means you will discover and exploit all sorts of new capacity planning and management techniques.  Get the latest from John <a href="http://www.kitchensoap.com/">here</a> .</p>

	<p>So, there you have it!  Get to reading and then get to building.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>David Young</name>
		</author>
		<published>2009-01-14T16:03:17Z</published>
		<updated>2009-01-14T16:37:43Z</updated>
		<title type="html">Joyent Acquires Reasonably Smart</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2009/01/14/joyent-acquires-reasonably-smart" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2009-01-14:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/c0c5cec969e83aac5a6643d2c40ea42e</id>
		<category term="Announcements" />
		<category term="Announcements" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m very excited to announce that Joyent has acquired the Montreal-based <a href="http://reasonablysmart.com">Reasonably Smart</a> platform. James Duncan and Bryan Bogensberger, founders of the company and platform, have joined Joyent.</p>

	<p>This acquisition comes at an important point in time for Joyent. We&#8217;ve just finished our best year, ever. Revenue doubled in 2008 from 2007 even as the economy continues to tank. Customers are moving spend from cap-ex to op-ex and Joyent products are ideally situated for this trend. However, more and more customers are expecting auto-scale from their cloud vendors and this acquisition allows Joyent to respond to those demands.</p>

	<p>Reasonably Smart is an auto-scaling platform-as-a-service; it is a direct, open-source competitor to Google App Engine. We believe the future of cloud computing is found in open, transparent platforms that allow customers to move between clouds easily, if desired. Unfortunately, that is not the case for most cloud vendors today. This acquisition underscores Joyent&#8217;s commitment to customers and their interests in cloud computing.</p>

	<p>This acquisition also underscores a bet that Javascript will become the language of scale for the web. When I talk of scale, I don&#8217;t only mean &#8220;big&#8221; but also &#8220;very small&#8221; since most applications developed are used by a handful of people from time-to-time. The platform will support other languages in the coming months, but we feel confident that Javascript is a very competent first start.</p>

	<p>I want to welcome James Duncan and Bryan Bogensberger to Joyent. James will continue to develop the platform. He has been a champion and contributor of open source for many years and has experience in building platforms at enormous scale. Bryan will be serving as Joyent&#8217;s VP of Marketing. Jason Hoffman and I knew they both were great fits for Joyent since they like to have fun and they are passionate about doing what is right for customers.</p>

	<p>The Reasonably Smart platform is off-line for a couple months while we integrate it with Joyent backend services. Meanwhile, please sign up at <a href="http://reasonablysmart.com">http://reasonablysmart.com</a> (running on Joyent Accelerators) to allow us to keep you informed of progress.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Kent Langley</name>
		</author>
		<published>2008-12-09T23:28:39Z</published>
		<updated>2008-12-10T00:52:52Z</updated>
		<title type="html">Joyent Two for One Christmas Sale!</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2008/12/09/joyent-two-for-one-christmas-sale" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2008-12-09:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/a5df3a48b7fd28fa78114376e27f8c86</id>
		<category term="Infrastructure" />
		
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.joyeur.com/images/136.png" align="left" width="289" height="230" float="left" />Tis&#8217; the season and Joyent is happy to announce the always popular and often demanded <span class="caps">TWO</span> <span class="caps">FOR</span> <span class="caps">ONE</span> Joyent Accelerator sale!</p>

	<p>This sale is a limited time from now through the end of December.</p>

	<p>How it works is that you get 24 months of Joyful Accelerator goodness for the price of 10 months.  If you do that the math, that&#8217;s quite a deal.  </p>

	<p>Let&#8217;s look at a 1 GiB example:</p>

	<p><strong>Regular Monthly Pricing</strong><br />
1 GiB Monthly = $125 / month or $1500 / yr</p>

	<p><strong>Regular Annual Pricing</strong><br />
1 GiB Annual = $125 / month or $1250 / yr</p>

	<p><strong>December Sale Pricing</strong><br />
1 GiB Sale = equivalent to $52.08 / GiB per Month when you pay $1250 for 24 months!</p>

	<ul>
		<li> All pricing includes <strong>10 TB</strong> of data transfer per month per customer.</li>
		<li>All Accelerator plans have a one-time setup fee equal to the regular one month charge for that size accelerator. For example, the set up fee on a 1GB accelerator is $125.</li>
	</ul>

	<p><strong>To Order, just order from our secure order form:</strong></p>

	<p><a href="https://secure.joyent.com/">https://secure.joyent.com/</a></p>

	<p>All Our Best During the Holiday Seasons,</p>

	<p>Team Joyent</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Rod Boothby</name>
		</author>
		<published>2008-11-14T22:20:31Z</published>
		<updated>2008-11-15T19:59:57Z</updated>
		<title type="html">Final Schedule for Enterprise Cloud Computing Seminar</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2008/11/14/final-schedule-for-enterprise-cloud-computing-seminar" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2008-11-14:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/bfd2244e01e4b768ff82bcadec586ac5</id>
		<category term="Events" />
		<category term="Cloud-Computing" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>We have finalized the schedule for Monday&#8217;s Enterprise Cloud Computing Seminar.</p>

	<p>If you are in the BayArea, please join us for what will be an extremely interesting and useful event.   <a href="http://enterprisecloudcomputing.eventbrite.com/">You can sign up here</a></p>

<h2>Seminar Schedule:</h2>

<h3>5:30PM &#8211; Enterprise Class Cloud Computing</h3>

	<p>Presentation by Dr. Jason Hoffman, Joyent Co-founder and <span class="caps">CTO</span></p>

	<p>Separating the hype from the reality of how successful enterprise class applications are deployed on the Cloud, this talk will discuss the following issues: Security, Operations, Migration, The promise of infinite scale, the reality of how to scale, appropriate use cases, private clouds and <span class="caps">VPN</span> connections to legacy infrastrctures, <span class="caps">SLA</span>s, achieving high availability and predicting total cost of ownership.</p>

<h3>6:15PM &#8211; Delivering an Integrated <span class="caps">IDE</span> Product using Cloud as a Service</h3>

	<p>Presentation by <a href="http://www.aptana.com">Aptana</a></p>

<h3>6:40PM &#8211; Refreshments</h3>
<br/>
<h3>7:00PM &#8211; Tactics and Execution &#8211; Real World Experience on the Cloud</h3>

	<p>Moderated by <strong>Ken Langley, Senior Director of Scale Consulting, Joyent</strong></p>

	<p>Participants</p>

	<p><b>Mark Lay, Director of Technology, <a href="http://www.akqa.com"><span class="caps">AKQA</span></a></B></p>

	<p>Mark Lay is responsible for technical delivery for all <span class="caps">AKQA</span> San Francisco’s clients.   A recognized pioneer, <span class="caps">AKQA</span> is an independent agency with 700 employees and offices throughout the <span class="caps">USA</span>, Europe and Asia. An ideas-led agency, <span class="caps">AKQA</span> works in partnership with brand leaders to deliver innovation.  <span class="caps">AKQA</span> has received Agency of the Year honors from Advertising Age, Adweek and <span class="caps">SHOOT</span> Magazines in 2008 and was included in Advertising Age’s 2008 “A-List” as well as Fast Company’s Fast 50, featuring the world’s 50 most innovative companies.  AKQA’s clients include Nike, Visa, Xbox, Coca-Cola and Target, among others. For more information about <span class="caps">AKQA</span>, visit www.akqa.com.</p>

	<p><b>Rafi Jacoby, Director of Engineering, <a href="http://www.contextoptional.com">Context Optional</a></b></p>

	<p>Rafi Jacoby oversees development and operations for Context Optional, the leading provider of scalable solutions for brand marketing across social networks. Context Optional offers a full suite of social marketing services including social media ad buys and optimization, licensed branded applications, brand page management and promotion, and custom viral application development. Context has delivered measurable marketing results for many of the world&#8217;s leading brands, including Microsoft, EA, Timberland, Ford, Samsung, Bank of America, and Viacom. Recent projects include Travel Channel&#8217;s Kidnap!, a top 10 game on Facebook with over 3 million users.</p>

	<p><b>Frank Anan, Founding Partner, <a href="http://www.solutionset.com">SolutionSet</a></b></p>

	<p>Frank currently serves as a founding partner of SolutionSet and manages San Francisco operations.   Launched in 2003, SolutionSet combines industry-leading technology with user-centered creative to deliver the latest approaches in web development, digital marketing and brand experience. SolutionSet stage the convergence of brand and technology which allows them  to view each client challenge with a bigger picture in mind and offer strategic solutions based on that visibility. SolutionSet has a proven track record for delivering to clients like Chevron, EBay, Tivo, Verisign, Cisco, Autodesk, and Kodak. SolutionSet is a Webby Award recipient and is number 23 on the Inc Magazine Top 500 Fastest Growing Companies overall list and number 2 in the IT Services category.</p>

<h3>7:45PM &#8211; The Future of Cloud Computing for the Enterprise</h3>

	<p>Moderated by <strong>Jason Hoffman</strong></p>

	<p>Participants: </p>

	<p><b>Geva Perry – General Manager, Cloud Computing, <a href="http://www.gigaspaces.com">GigaSpaces</a></b></p>

	<p>GigaSpaces Technologies is a leading provider of a scale-out application server for Java, .Net and C++.  The GigaSpaces eXtrema Application Platform provides applications with scalability, reliability and high-performance in distributed environments, such as <span class="caps">SOA</span>, clusters, grids and cloud computing.   GigaSpaces&#8217; customers include some of the world’s largest corporation in financial services, telecommunications, manufacturing and the Internet. GigaSpaces was founded in 2000 and has offices worldwide.</p>

	<p><b>Benjamin Black &#8211; VP, Research, <a href="http://www.joyent.com">Joyent</a></b></p>

	<p>Ben is currently part of Joyent&#8217;s Cloud Development team, working on next-generation solutions to issues of scalability, monitoring, metrics and security.   Prior to joining Joyent, Ben held senior technical roles at Amazon, Microsoft and Internap.</p>

	<p><b>Sunil Potti &#8211; VP of Product Development, <a href="http://www.f5.com">f5</a></b></p>

	<p>Sunil leads the Product Development forthe Acceleration and Virtualization Group at F5 Networks. Sunil brings many years of experience in delivering enterprise applications and next generation application infrastructure technologies to the market. In his current role, he is responsible for delivering F5’s application acceleration products including <span class="caps">WAN</span> optimization and web acceleration solutions. Prior to F5, Sunil was Director of Engineering at Cisco Systems where he led the Application Oriented Networking product group. He has also held positions at Synchrony and Sybase</p>

	<p><b>Jamie Lerner &#8211; President &amp; <span class="caps">CEO</span>, <a href="http://www.cittio.com/index.html"><span class="caps">CITTIO</span></a></b></p>

	<p>Jamie Lerner, CITTIO’s President and <span class="caps">CEO</span>, has over fifteen years of experience in software development and high growth company management.  In 2001, Lerner founded <span class="caps">CITTIO</span> to address the need for cost-effective, easy-to-use, enterprise management software that he found was not available in the industry.     	<span class="caps">CITTIO</span> provides automated network and systems monitoring software for today’s modern datacenters and complex, ever changing networks. With automated network monitoring, systems monitoring, application monitoring and edge device support &#8211; <span class="caps">CITTIO</span> delivers &#8220;single pane of glass&#8221; visibility into your IT infrastructure performance and availability so your team can be proactive and focus on the business, instead of maintaining its monitoring software.</p>

	<p><a href="http://enterprisecloudcomputing.eventbrite.com/">You can sign up here for the Enterprise Cloud Computing Seminar</a></p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>David Young</name>
		</author>
		<published>2008-11-11T00:45:00Z</published>
		<updated>2008-11-11T00:45:00Z</updated>
		<title type="html">Lessons Learned</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2008/11/11/lessons-learned" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2008-11-11:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/fab5fbeff97387c9930ee3823ed67dce</id>
		<category term="Industry" />
		<category term="Infrastructure" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>This video from a Frontline documentary speaks volumes about what the state-of-the-art is for computers providing autoscale in the cloud. It still comes down to piloting (architectures).</p>

	<p><object width="425" height="344"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/SoPmKiDw-y0&hl=en&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/SoPmKiDw-y0&hl=en&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"></embed></object></p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>David Young</name>
		</author>
		<published>2008-11-06T23:53:26Z</published>
		<updated>2008-11-07T00:00:27Z</updated>
		<title type="html">In the Business Cycle of Create, Improve, Destroy: What Sun Needs to Do Now</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2008/11/06/in-the-business-cycle-of-create-improve-destroy-what-sun-needs-to-do-now" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2008-11-06:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/6348b3e9f5f349f28488ffc7dc250e13</id>
		<category term="Industry" />
		<category term="Industry" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>I can&#8217;t quit thinking about Sun after last Thursday&#8217;s (Oct 30, 2008) <a href="http://www.sun.com/aboutsun/pr/2008-10/sunflash.20081030.1.xml">news</a>. Listening to Elgar&#8217;s Ninth Enigma Variation (<a href="http://ax.itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewAlbum?i=252486135&amp;id=252485732&amp;s=143441">Nimrod</a>) has provided me with a soundtrack for my thoughts. I&#8217;ve <a href="http://www.joyeur.com/2006/06/21/sunshine">written about Sun</a>, a company I deeply admire, in the past. Jason <a href="http://www.joyeur.com/2006/03/20/the-sun-doesnt-shine-on-me">wrote</a> about Sun&#8217;s ability to create amazing products, but inability to ship them. I&#8217;ve compared Sun to the god Apollo, in a <a href="http://www.joyeur.com/2006/06/21/sunshine">post</a> that some at Sun claimed I wrote after eating magic mushrooms, to beautiful Apollo up against the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en/us/default.aspx">Leviathan</a> and the <a href="http://www.google.com/corporate/execs.html">Juggernaut</a> as they build their gargantuan data centers down-by-the-river.</p>

	<p>Last Thursday (Oct 30, 2008) Sun announced a loss $1.7 billion, most of that in accounting write downs (for acquisitions). The good news for Sun is, just as much seems lost, the wizard of hardware has departed, the red ink is piling up, financial sector customers are sick, not to mention the economy, the entire game of &#8220;vertically integrated systems company&#8221; (&#8220;<span class="caps">VISC</span>&#8221;) is shifting radically. Yes, radically as is &#8220;radix&#8221; from the root. What an opportunity! and happy timing!</p>

	<p>It won&#8217;t be possible to acquire or open source or lead the company out of the funk unless Sun embraces its path on the axiomatic history of successful companies: it has created, it has improved, it must now destroy. Why own a database company? The database is dead. Destroy. Tape? Tape is dead. Destroy. Java? Java is dead. Destroy. Servers? Who buys servers? Dead. Destroy. The list is nearly endless for Sun since it is a collection of so many important baubles from its first incarnation as a <span class="caps">VISC</span>. &#8220;Young, you&#8217;re crazy. That&#8217;s not a rational position. We made X on Java in FY2007. We made X on Database <span class="caps">YTD</span> FY2008. We made X on Tape in Quarter over Quarter in 2007/2008. We made X on Servers, and see the business growing in 2009.&#8221; I understand all that. So, sell it. But it is dead to Sun. You can&#8217;t truly create until you have destroyed. Nimrod came down from the mountain / with a sword made of flame / He smote down all his children / and his children grew again.</p>

	<p>Now then, having destroyed, create. It will be very exciting. Psst: you&#8217;ll be a startup with billions in the bank. Sun did $124 million in software sales in its first quarter of 2009 with tremendous growth. Focus on that. Become a $500 million dollar growth business. It also mean shrinking down from 34,000 employees&#8230;by a lot. I don&#8217;t see how the market can punish Sun for taking this tack. The share price has been destroyed already. If Sun did something like this, wow! What a move! Sun can kick ass again. Sun can outwit Leviathan and Juggernaut.</p>

	<p>P.S. There&#8217;s likely no iPod business out there to save Sun. Those are lightning strikes.</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Rod Boothby</name>
		</author>
		<published>2008-11-05T22:57:30Z</published>
		<updated>2008-11-05T23:59:27Z</updated>
		<title type="html">Enterprise Cloud Computing Seminar</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2008/11/05/enterprise-cloud-computing-seminar" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2008-11-05:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/a3f5ded1644fd7caf10833caaaf7919b</id>
		<category term="Events" />
		<category term="Press-Release" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>Join us on evening of Nov. 17th for a free <a href="http://enterprisecloudcomputing.eventbrite.com/">Enterprise Cloud Computing Seminar</a> . </p>

	<p><img src="http://www.joyeur.com/images/134.png" alt="" /></p>

	<p>The seminar will include participation and presentations for <a href="http://www.solutionset.com/">SolutionSet</a>, <a href="http://www.aptana.com/">Aptana</a> , and a series of other companies who have had experience deploying on the cloud.</p>

	<p>We are going to address the practical questions of enterprise <span class="caps">CTO</span>s and <span class="caps">CIO</span>s</p>

	<p><span class="caps">CTO</span>s and <span class="caps">CIO</span>s realize the potential benefits of Cloud Computing, but they also have reasonable questions about the following:</p>

	<ul>
		<li>How to achieve enterprise class security on the Cloud?</li>
		<li>What are the operational issues and best practices associated with running applications on the Cloud?</li>
		<li>How do you scale an application on the Cloud?</li>
		<li>What are the appropriate enterprise use cases for Cloud Computing?</li>
		<li>How do you build and deploy a highly available application on the Cloud?</li>
		<li>What do Cloud <span class="caps">SLA</span>s mean to enterprise users?</li>
		<li>What are the total costs of running an application on the Cloud?</li>
	</ul>

	<p>The event will begin at 5:30pm and go until 8:00pm, with an opportunity to socialize and network from 8:00pm until 9:00pm. </p>

	<p>We are holding the event at <a href="http://tinyurl.com/5gh24n">Sun&#8217;s Menlo Park campus</a><br />
15 Network Circle Building 15<br />
Menlo Park, CA 94025 </p>

	<p>You can register at <a href="http://enterprisecloudcomputing.eventbrite.com/">http://enterprisecloudcomputing.eventbrite.com/</a></p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Kent Langley</name>
		</author>
		<published>2008-11-05T18:15:27Z</published>
		<updated>2008-11-11T16:52:29Z</updated>
		<title type="html">Joyent Accelerator 2.1.4 Release</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2008/11/05/joyent-accelerator-214-release" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2008-10-30:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/3cb50b180e9c6bc65d6df625445edb97</id>
		<category term="Announcements" />
		<category term="Cloud-Computing" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s with excitement that I announce the newest version of the Joyent Accelerator.  The Joyent Technology team deserves a round of applause for their diligent  work on this latest version of the Accelerator template.  It is a tremendous piece of technology, and I certainly tip my hat to the team and say thank you, as both a client and an employee.  To that end, I wanted to write a brief overview to explain a bit more about what an Accelerator is, what it comes with, and some of the ways Joyent customers use them.</p>

	<p><strong>What is a Joyent Accelerator?</strong></p>

	<p>Joyent Accelerators are virtual servers based on the OpenSolaris Nevada operating system, but imbued with more friendly <span class="caps">GNU</span> userland tools and the <span class="caps">PKGSRC</span> packaging system.  Joyent Accelerators are the ideal building blocks for serious work at serious scale.  You can start small and grow big on-demand.  Web 2.0 Developers, SaaS, and PaaS providers enjoy the ease of use and simplicity of the Joyent &#8216;Infrastructure as a Service&#8217; (IaaS) Cloud.  The enterprise-class technology stack that surrounds an Accelerator, which we call a Pod, is comprised of routers, firewalls, load balancer, networks, high speed internet connections, switches, remote access, and much more.   By embedding our virtual servers in this core technology stack, Accelerators enable extreme computing and scalability at the level necessary for today&#8217;s online applications.  This allows developers and service providers to focus primarily on the application, reduce total cost of ownership, and add &#8216;agile&#8217; to the words used to describe the IT arsenal your business brings to the table.</p>

	<p>Moreover, all Accelerators come with the built-in support of a tremendous pkgsrc repository of over 600 packages!  We work hard on these packages to help you keep your systems up-to-date, easy to build and deploy.  There are probably thousands of cumulative Systems Administrator hours put into this, which you get by default just for being a Joyent Accelerator customer.</p>

	<p><strong>What Frameworks or Programming Languages can I use on a Joyent Accelerator?</strong></p>

	<p>Most existing frameworks and languages run very well on Joyent Accelerators.  A Joyent Accelerator can easily run the most demanding applications written in Java, Perl, <span class="caps">PHP</span>, Python, Ruby, and Erlang.  A partial list of the frameworks we have personally tested or know to work well are:</p>

	<p>Tomcat, Gigaspaces <span class="caps">XAP</span>, Axiom Stack, GlassFish, CakePHP, Symfony, Drupal, Django, Merb, Ruby on Rails, CouchDB, .NET in mono, Ejabberd, SunGridEngine, and more.  You can find how-to guides and installation information for all of these and more on our wiki at http://wiki.joyent.com.</p>

	<p><strong>What are people doing with their Accelerators?</strong></p>

	<p>Here are some recent examples of ways our clients are using Joyent Acclerators:</p>

	<p>We have what is likely one of the largest Drupal installations anywhere.  It has been tested to run at upwards of 1000 req/sec!  That&#8217;s 2.5 billion page views per month!</p>

	<p>The recent launch of Aptana Cloud powered by Joyent&#8217;s IaaS was an exciting step as well.  Aptana cloud compute nodes launch in about 45 seconds and cost as little as $0.04 per hour.</p>

	<p>Static asset clusters using BigIP and Nginx that easily serve 2000 req/sec per node and more, and can scale nearly linearly with the addition of our managed load balancing services.  These are frequently used to augment dynamic web sites.</p>

	<p>Large scale ejabberd installation that runs for Major League Baseball live chat during games.</p>

	<p>A Symfony site serving as many as 12,000 <span class="caps">SELECT</span> queries per second and huge numbers of <span class="caps">HTTP</span> requests for a large application that has been successfully handling the substantial bursts of activity during the recent presidential campaign debates.</p>

	<p>A distributed java application development platform with Gigaspaces <span class="caps">XAP</span> on Joyent. This makes developing and deploying distributed cloud computing applications a breeze.</p>

	<p>Sun Grid Engine working out traditional <span class="caps">HPC</span> work loads on-demand in our environment.</p>

	<p><strong>Summary</strong></p>

	<p>We are excited about this new release and so are our early release clients and beta testers.  The Accelerator is a tremendously flexible IaaS offering, that has customers saying things such as:</p>

	<p>&#8220;The new template is so fully configured that pretty much everything that had been causing me issues is now just installed by default.&#8221; -Client</p>

	<p>&#8220;I really like it as it is full of the latest and greatest stuff ready to be used. Really cool!&#8221; -Client</p>

	<p>&#8220;Only thought I had for you was that it’s nice that the accelerator comes with subversion, bzr, mercurial, and git, along with enough ruby gems to choke a horse (including both merb and camping).&#8221; -Client</p>

	<p>&#8220;Congrats for the release. I&#8217;m sure your clients will love it. I do ;-)&#8221; -Beta Tester</p>

	<p><strong>Joyent Accelerator 2.1.4 (aka 2008Q2) Release Notes:</strong></p>

	<p>Here is a list of the highlights of this release.  I&#8217;m sure there is more that I missed, but this gives a good idea.</p>

	<p>MySQL 5.0.67<br />
Apache 2.2.9<br />
Memcached 1.2.6<br />
Merb 0.9.2<br />
Nginx 0.6.32<br />
Perl 5.8.8<br />
<span class="caps">PHP</span> 5.2.6<br />
Phusion Passenger (mod_rails)<br />
Ruby on Rails 2.1.2<br />
Subversion 1.5<br />
Git 1.5.6.4<br />
RugyGems 1.2.0<br />
Erlang 12.0nb2<br />
Python 2.5.2<br />
PostgreSQL 8.3.3<br />
Postgrey 1.31	Postfix 2.5.5<br />
Varnish 1.1.2<br />
Ejabberd 2.0.0nb2<br />
GraphicsMagick 1.2.4   <br />
ImageMagick 6.3.6.1<br />
Java 1.6.0_06<br />
Mono 1.9<br />
SpamAssassin 3.2.5<br />
Build a Boost (boost-libs) package<br />
cmake package for use by hypertable and kfs<br />
Cleaned Up a lot of orphaned <span class="caps">SMF</span> services<br />
Fixed a postscript <span class="caps">SMF</span> restart bug<br />
Upgrade Virtualmin to 3.62<br />
Disable mod_fcgid out of the box<br />
Update ruby to fix a vulnerability<br />
Update MySQL to fix vulnerability<br />
Update RMagick to 2.7.0<br />
Create a package for the fastthread gem<br />
Enable Phusion Passenger for use on Joyent<br />
Fixed a Python Symlink issue<br />
Upgraded Rails to 2.1.1<br />
Upgraded Mongrel to 1.1.5<br />
Upgraded Rake to 0.8.2<br />
Upgraded RMagic to 2.6.0<br />
Upgraded Ruby Hoe to 1.7.0<br />
Updated RedCloth<br />
Added Accelerator version info to <span class="caps">MOTD</span> banner on shell login<br />
Several Email-related improvements<br />
Postgrey 1.31<br />
Spamassassin 3.2.5<br />
Update to <span class="caps">PHP</span> <span class="caps">PDO</span><br />
Fixed an Eventmachine Dependency Issue<br />
Improvements to Nginx<br />
Added <span class="caps">PHP</span>-Tidy<br />
Updated Ruby to 1.8.7<br />
Improved mysql <span class="caps">SMF</span> scripts<br />
Add several extras for Merb users<br />
memcached and PHP5 updates<br />
Increased the default file descriptor limit out of the box<br />
fixed some log rotation issues<br />
MySQL slow query log on by default<br />
A large number of updates related to making Elrang Apps run better out of the box</p>

	<p>[Update: a review <a href="http://www.agileweboperations.com/review-joyent-accelerator-21-beta">http://www.agileweboperations.com/review-joyent-accelerator-21-beta</a>]</p>]]>
</content>
</entry>
<entry>
		<author>
			<name>David Young</name>
		</author>
		<published>2008-10-31T21:16:48Z</published>
		<updated>2008-11-01T03:28:09Z</updated>
		<title type="html">Laissez les bon temps roulez. RIP is for suckers. Joyent in the NYT.</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.joyeur.com/2008/10/31/laissez-les-bon-temps-roullez-rip-is-for-suckers-joyent-in-the-nyt" />
		<id>tag:www.joyeur.com,2008-10-31:333be79fb409eb2a6d45784158fd6cd1/39744a84abcbe06c5d2ff1231441df51</id>
		<category term="Cloud-Computing" />
		<category term="Press-Release" />
		<content type="html">
<![CDATA[<p>Recently, so much ink has been spilt on our VC-backed brethren racing for the cash-conserving hills. Why they weren&#8217;t shooting for revenue and profitability from day one is beyond us.</p>

	<p>Joyent believes when a company is built to be profitable from day one, market context is much less meaningful than the ability to expend effort and succeed. As companies move from CapEx to OpEx, a flight to quality in operations and product, companies such as Joyent are sure to benefit. GigaOM and the <span class="caps">NYT</span> <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/external/gigaom/2008/10/31/31gigaom-glum-economy-brings-on-good-times-for-joyent-27511.html">picked up</a> today on our success in a down market. Congrats to my fellow Joyeurs!</p>]]>
</content>
</entry></feed>