<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent Jobs</title>
    <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs.rss</link>
    <description>Recent jobs posted to the 37signals Job Board</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>Yelp.com: Software Engineer</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; San Francisco, CA
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.yelp.com"&gt;www.yelp.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is Yelp For You?&lt;/p&gt;
* Are you excited about transforming an entire industry?
* Do you get excited about building products for millions of people?
* Do you want to help people find the best local services by the building the right tools for them?
&lt;p&gt;If your blood is pumping now, Yelp is the place for you. Yelp is looking for experienced enthusiastic Software Engineers to play an important role on the Yelp development team. Our developers do it all &amp;#8211; from frontend to backend.&lt;br /&gt;
Requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
* Excellent knowledge of programming languages: Python / Java / &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; / Ruby or C/C++ (especially in a server-side context)
* Problem solving skills and the ability to write efficient code that scales well
* Flexibility: we are small company, but we move quickly
* Great communication skills
* Sense of humor
&lt;p&gt;Pluses:&lt;/p&gt;
* Experience with MySQL and/or Lucene
* Interest in fields of local search, social networking, blogging and related technologies, recommendation systems, and data mining


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Visit &lt;a href="http://www.yelp.com/jobs"&gt;www.yelp.com/jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 01:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4766</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4766</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clinton Global Intiative: Web Producer (New Media Specialist)</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; New York, NY
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.clintonglobalinitiative.org"&gt;www.clintonglobalinitiative.org&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Web Producer (New Media Specialist) plays a key role in the areas of Web site design/development and online communications production.&lt;br /&gt;
Responsibilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Web Producer is responsible for:&lt;/p&gt;
* Developing front-end Web site components
* Managing and publishing content
* Integrating Web-based communication tools
* Building out Web pages
* Maintaining and updating Clinton Foundation Web sites
* Overseeing back-end functionality of all online properties
* In addition, the Web Producer assists with:
o Development of e-News
o Online fundraising projects
o Implementation of Web site features, including media-rich components
o Management and hosting of domains
&lt;p&gt;Skills Required&lt;/p&gt;
* Proficient with the following scripting languages and technologies: &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; I, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; II, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHTML&lt;/span&gt;, JavaScript.
* Experienced in Web page design, layout and construction &amp;#8211; both hand-coding and using &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/span&gt; tools, such as DreamWeaver.
* Ability to develop and test Web content for cross-platform and cross-browser Internet display, and to manage content from a variety of departments (Communications, Marketing, Digital Media, Development, etc.)
* Demonstrated skill in application of Web usability standards, information design, and principles of search engine optimization.
* Experienced with the Linux server environment, and knowledgeable of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; scripting language and the MySQL relational database.
* Familiarity with server-side scripting, database connectivity, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds, and third-party tool integration.
* Knowledgeable of Web site analytics, content management systems (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CRM&lt;/span&gt; tools such as Blackbaud Net Community, blogging platforms, pod casting, and Web site hosting.
&lt;p&gt;Qualifications&lt;/p&gt;
* The Web Producer is Mac and PC literate, and will have a minimum of three years experience in professional Web production, new media and/or interactive work.
* The successful candidate will demonstrate an attention to detail, be skilled at time management, communicate effectively, have the ability to work both as a member of a team and independently, and be committed to the mission of the Foundation and its initiatives.
* A Bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree is required; an advanced degree is preferred.
&lt;p&gt;This position reports to the Director of Digital and New Media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TO &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APPLY&lt;/span&gt;: Please send cover letter and resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%64%6e%6d%6a%6f%62%73@%63%6c%69%6e%74%6f%6e%66%6f%75%6e%64%61%74%69%6f%6e.%6f%72%67"&gt;dnmjobs@clintonfoundation.org&lt;/a&gt;. Please type Web Producer (New Media Specialist) in subject line of your email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The William J. Clinton Foundation &amp;amp; Office of President Clinton are Equal Opportunity Employers. This job description is intended to convey information essential to understand the scope of the position. It is not intended to be an exhaustive list of skills, efforts, duties, or responsibilities associated with the positions.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Please send cover letter and resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%64%6e%6d%6a%6f%62%73@%63%6c%69%6e%74%6f%6e%66%6f%75%6e%64%61%74%69%6f%6e.%6f%72%67"&gt;dnmjobs@clintonfoundation.org&lt;/a&gt;. Please type Web Producer (New Media Specialist) in subject line of your email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 19:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4765</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4765</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyte Media: Web Designer</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Chicago, IL
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#8217;re looking for a talented web designer to work with us on a very special project.  We wish we could tell you more about it here other than it&#8217;s about making the world a healthier place.  We can tell you more when we meet.  It&#8217;s an amazing gig for a seasoned and seriously creative designer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	&#8230;and the Adobe Creative Suite are &#8220;likethis&#8221;&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Are committed to clear, simple design and web standards&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Have solid experience creating e-commerce sites&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Code in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AJAX&lt;/span&gt; and Javascript (jQuery) too.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Have an borderline unhealthy passion for typography&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Can illustrate&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Have designed sweet sweet logos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other stuff about you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	Detail-oriented (of course)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Fun, energetic, play well with others, doesn&#8217;t throw sand, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Are comfortable working on multiple projects&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	You have really good taste&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	You see things from the user&#8217;s point of view&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Like mixed nuts (we went to CostCo and bought too much)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyte Media is a new (funded) startup, based in Chicago.  We&#8217;re a consumer healthcare e-commerce company.  We create groundbreaking web experiences to help people find products and services to stay on top of their health.  We believe that healthcare should be as transparent and accessible as anything else we buy and consume.  We&#8217;re a healthy mix of creatives and analysts.  The left brainers and right brainers co-exist peacefully as we work toward a common goal of making the world a healthier place.  We prefer if you were in Chicago but if you rock and live elsewhere, we can deal.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Please send your resume and portfolio to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%6d%69%63%68%65%6c%6c%65@%61%6e%61%6c%79%74%65%6d%65%64%69%61.%63%6f%6d"&gt;michelle@analytemedia.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 17:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4764</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4764</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meltwater Group: Senior Program Manager - Senior Faculty</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1772/logo.gif?1232641994" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Accra, Ghana
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.meltwater.com"&gt;http://www.meltwater.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior Program Manager &amp;#8211; Senior Faculty&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
The following description is quite detailed. Our intention is to provide insight into the opportunity so that you can make a well-informed choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opportunity Overview&lt;br /&gt;
If you want to make an impact in the global community, here is your once in a lifetime opportunity. . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Senior Faculty member at Meltwater Entrepreneurial School of Technology (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MEST&lt;/span&gt;), based in Accra, Ghana, you will join a team of individuals working to develop and train African software entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With over 2 million residents, Accra is the capital of Ghana and its largest city. Located on the coast of West Africa, Accra is one of the wealthiest and most modern cities in the African continent. You will work alongside other Senior Faculty and join a team that includes some of the most talented members of Meltwater&amp;#8217;s corporate team, as well as teaching assistants recruited from top international universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will enjoy the excitement of being a key contributor in establishing the institute and will be a critical force in developing Africa&amp;#8217;s technology generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meltwater Group, the Company &lt;br /&gt;
Meltwater is a fast growing IT company developing and selling software solutions to businesses and organizations worldwide. Meltwater group has 42 offices globally and more than 12,000 of the world&amp;#8217;s most successful companies and organizations on its client list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MEST&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Meltwater Entrepreneurial School of Technology (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MEST&lt;/span&gt;) is a not-for-profit &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NGO&lt;/span&gt; funded by Meltwater Group. It is the realization of our belief in corporate social responsibility and our vision to give some of our knowledge and resources back to the world. Based in an area of the world carefully chosen for maximum impact, MEST&amp;#8217;s mission is to train and develop young African entrepreneurs to become future players in the global information technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MEST&lt;/span&gt; is a post-graduate program for a select group of some of Africa&amp;#8217;s highest potential students, all with undergraduate degrees and a passion for technology and entrepreneurship. The end goal is to equip these students with the tools and confidence to start new software companies and generate wealth locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Requirements&lt;br /&gt;
Essential attributes: &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A belief in social change and a passion for teaching/developing young people. &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Charisma and enthusiasm, ability to set the tone for an exciting learning atmosphere.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Excellent communication skills and fluency in English.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	The ability to commit to a two year contract in Accra, Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for individuals who have the ability to:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Develop and manage a business and technology curriculum that includes current trends and best practices in software development and elements required for a comprehensive business plan.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Create and deliver lectures; think out-of-the box and be creative in ways to effectively teach software development using interactive methods, rather than strict text-book style in order to encourage independent thinking.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Manage a small staff of junior teaching assistants, who will assist in delivering lecture and lab material.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Act as a positive role model and mentor to entrepreneurs-in training and teaching assistants.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Motivate and inspire small teams of entrepreneurs-in-training in completing software development projects by creating a positive and dynamic learning environment.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Analyze project deliverables, conduct performance evaluations and give constructive feedback.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Coach trainees in developing their critical thinking abilities and strengthening their interpersonal and communication skills.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Introduce trainees to the latest business practices in the global market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for individuals who have:&lt;br /&gt;
&#61548;	Bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree in Computer Science or closely related field. (Master&amp;#8217;s, Ph.D. a plus)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree in Business or Entrepreneurship (Master&amp;#8217;s a plus)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Previous teaching experience at the college level or corporate training experience.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	10 or more years of technology/business working experience; 5 or more years of developing or managing web development and or/mobile projects using recent technologies.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Hands-on programming experience and familiarity with several programming languages, open source software, databases &amp;amp; web architecture.&lt;br /&gt;
&#61548;	Broad knowledge of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SDLC&lt;/span&gt; and proven track record of successfully delivering software projects.&lt;br /&gt;
&#61548;	Excellent business knowledge, ranging from principles of management to writing business plans.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Proven ability to lead, direct and motivate development teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desirable:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Experience in an entrepreneurial start-up or in launching a new product.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Experience with mobile technologies.&lt;br /&gt;
Keys to Success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your technical knowledge is critical, but what will make you &amp;#8212; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MEST&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8212; a true success is the level of passion and commitment you bring to the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also critical are your: &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Management and leadership skills, particularly the ability to communicate effectively.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Compassion and empathy necessary to transcend cultural differences. &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Drive and stamina to set goals and reach those goals in the face of challenges. &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Collaborative approach and willingness to be a &amp;quot;team player&amp;quot;.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Effective training &amp;amp; mentoring skills and charismatic presence. &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Sense of humor and the ability to foster a fun environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meltwater Group is an equal opportunity employer. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EOE&lt;/span&gt; M/F/D/V&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now accepting and evaluating applications for the start in August 2009 in Ghana. The final interview session will be held end of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send a letter of interest and your resume/CV to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%72%65%63%72%75%69%74%6d%65%6e%74.%66%61%63%75%6c%74%79@%6d%65%6c%74%77%61%74%65%72.%6f%72%67"&gt;recruitment.faculty@meltwater.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information contact: Kimling Lam, &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%6b%69%6d%6c%69%6e%67.%6c%61%6d@%6d%65%6c%74%77%61%74%65%72.%63%6f%6d"&gt;kimling.lam@meltwater.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%72%65%63%72%75%69%74%6d%65%6e%74.%66%61%63%75%6c%74%79@%6d%65%6c%74%77%61%74%65%72.%6f%72%67"&gt;recruitment.faculty@meltwater.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 16:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4763</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4763</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Internet Startup: Ruby on Rails Web Lead</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Palo Alto, California, US
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a young but well-funded startup setting up office in Palo Alto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ambition is to modernize the way talent from Ivy League universities finds work in top companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, we are looking for an experienced Web Developer to put together and lead a small team of Ruby on Rails talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be working closely with the technical lead of our sister European startup, in order to develop a new, U.S.-focused, version of their social recruitment platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we are looking for, more so than specific skills, is an experienced, passionate, quick learning generalist with at least a couple of years of commercial Ruby on Rails experience, and an extensive background in web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would have dipped your toes (up to the last knuckle!) into all aspects of modern web development: from server side deployment with capistrano, mongrel, thin, apache, memcached et al., to front end interface magic using Javascript, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;. And from agile development and testing methodologies (take your pick, we are not dogmatic!) to modern day development and communication tools such as git, svn, twitter, irc, campfire; the lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you have an eye or an opinion about good usability and design, all the better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We offer flexible work conditions, personal development opportunities, and we respect your right to an opinion about everything, no matter how unreasonable.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Interested? Get in touch. &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%63%68%72%69%73%74%6f%73@%34%32%6c%69%6e%65%73%6f%66%63%6f%64%65.%63%6f%6d"&gt;christos@42linesofcode.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 15:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4762</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4762</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iExplore: Web Designer</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1771/logo.gif?1232635741" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Chicago, IL
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.iExplore.com"&gt;http://www.iExplore.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web Designer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re a leading, Chicago-based, online adventure travel company who is seeking a professional and accomplished Web Designer. The ideal candidate will be well-rounded, possess a broad range of graphic design skills, and be able to work well with a small, collaborative marketing and technology team. Candidates should be comfortable designing standards-based web sites (including a redesign of iExplore.com), newsletters, and creative elements for online marketing campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Required:&lt;br /&gt;
- Solid design background with a keen eye for details&lt;br /&gt;
- Solid experience with Adobe CS&lt;br /&gt;
- Solid experience with Flash and ActionScript&lt;br /&gt;
- Strong knowledge of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- A strong belief in developing and promoting brand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also desired:&lt;br /&gt;
- Ability to design/develop &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; email campaigns&lt;br /&gt;
- Ability to design online marketing campaigns, microsites, landing pages, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
- Comfortable working around (or even with) server-side code (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, Rails, Java)&lt;br /&gt;
- Some experience with print design&lt;br /&gt;
- Familiarity with any of the JavaScript frameworks&lt;br /&gt;
- Familiarity with version control&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested?&lt;br /&gt;
Send us your r&#233;sum&#233;, salary requirements, and samples of your work (links, your online portfolio, a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;-based portfolio, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job Perks&lt;br /&gt;
- Competitive compensation&lt;br /&gt;
- Medical and dental&lt;br /&gt;
- 401K with employer match&lt;br /&gt;
- Paid lunch with a co-worker once per week&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Send a resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%63%61%72%65%65%72@%69%65%78%70%6c%6f%72%65.%63%6f%6d"&gt;career@iexplore.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 14:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4761</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4761</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>readMedia: Talented, Motivated, Experienced Ruby on Rails Application Developer</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Albany, NY
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.readmedia.com/company/about"&gt;http://www.readmedia.com/company/about&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;readMedia is looking for a talented software developer to join a profitable, fast-growing company that is on a path to revolutionize a big segment of the media industry. We have blue-chip backers, paying customers, a proven vision, lots of interesting work for you and a lot of upside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently working at enhancing and extending our online hyper local press release syndication application, as well as launching many new projects and offerings to better connect the media with the news they need via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds and efficient search algorithms. Our application relies on many parts working together, as well as very close attention to our clients&#8217; user experience and needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be a key member of our team and we will trust you with the freedom and responsibility to accomplish readMedia&#8217;s goals by writing elegant, stable code. You must be self-motivated and able to excel without someone looking over your shoulder all of the time. We prefer people who are intellectually curious, like to solve problems, and who are passionate about their work. Ideally, you&#8217;ll be curious about the business side of what we do and play a role beyond your day-to-day responsibilities. We prefer people who &#8220;punch above their weight&#8221; and can contribute more than the nuts and bolts listed on a resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, we&#8217;re looking for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	Real world experience developing, deploying and maintaining web-based applications.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A strong understanding of Object Oriented Programming and design. &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A strong understanding of database design.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Proficiency in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt;, Javascript, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNIX&lt;/span&gt;, and at least one other object oriented programming language such as Java or C++.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Someone who (programmatically) tests the code they commit.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A team player with strong communication skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIG&lt;/span&gt; bonus points for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	B.S. in Computer Science or equivalent.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Experience programming with geographic data sets and Google Maps.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Amazon Web Services experience.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Mongrel, Apache, Memcached, Capistrano, Monit experience.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNIX&lt;/span&gt; systems administration experience.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	MySQL administration experience.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	An eye for design and the skills to execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We subscribe to the Joel Spolsky criteria for all of our employees: people who are,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.	Smart, and&#8230;&lt;br /&gt;
2.	Get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why work with readMedia?&lt;br /&gt;
readMedia offers a very competitive salary, equity, a workplace that encourages you to have a life of your own, and people who appreciate what you can do. We&#8217;re not a sweatshop and there&#8217;s very little ego here. We value people who contribute thoughtfully and well to our efforts and share our commitment to excellence and dedication to our customers. You will of course also get health and dental, paid holidays, a 401(k) matching plan, paid parking, and a cool looking office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This job is at our home office in Albany, New York. There are lots of great reasons to live here that we&#8217;ll tell you all about when we hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DO &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APPLY&lt;/span&gt; IF &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YOU&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ARE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOOKING&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FOR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CONTRACT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WORK&lt;/span&gt; OR IF YOU&#8217;RE A &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CONTRACT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SHOP&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;THIS&lt;/span&gt; IS A &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FULL&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;TIME&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;POSITION&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#8217;t just send a resume! Please send a cover note that tells us a bit about you, what you&#8217;re especially good at or like to work on, why you&#8217;re interested in the position, and what you think you bring to the table&#8212;this note is a really important requirement.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Send it to Colin at jobs &amp;lt;at&amp;gt; readMedia &amp;lt;dot&amp;gt; com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 22:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4760</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4760</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WestEd: Interaction Designer #2815</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; San Francisco, CA  
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.wested.org/cs/we/view/hr_pos/2815"&gt;http://www.wested.org/cs/we/view/hr_pos/2815&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WestEd &amp;#8211; &amp;quot;Voted Best Places to Work&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apply online at: &lt;a href="http://www.wested.org/cs/we/view/hr_pos/2815"&gt;http://www.wested.org/cs/we/view/hr_pos/2815&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Position Title: 	Interaction Designer&lt;br /&gt;
Reports to:	Art Director&lt;br /&gt;
Program: 	WestEd Interactive&lt;br /&gt;
Department: 	Information Services&lt;br /&gt;
Salary: 	Level G &amp;#8211; $65,802 &amp;#8211; $82,252&lt;br /&gt;
Location: 	San Francisco, CA&lt;br /&gt;
Time Base:	100%&lt;br /&gt;
Position No: 	2815&lt;br /&gt;
Type:	Regular Employee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WestEd, a nonprofit research, development, and service agency, works with education and other communities to promote excellence, achieve equity, and improve learning for children, youth, and adults. While WestEd serves the states of Arizona, California, Nevada, and Utah as one of the nation&amp;#8217;s Regional Educational Laboratories, our agency&amp;#8217;s work extends throughout the United States and abroad. WestEd has 16 offices nationwide, from Washington and Boston to Arizona, Southern California, and its headquarters in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to apply your design skills with an organization that is dedicated to improving education and learning? Join our diverse and rapidly growing web team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WestEd, a nonprofit agency, is a respected leader in the education sector and has been ranked in the top 100 places to work in the SF Bay Area multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WestEd Interactive, the organization&amp;#8217;s web technology group, creates education-related web sites and tools. We help educational organizations build online communities, implement web 2.0 strategies, share and publish research, and perform complex tasks through web applications. As one of the country&amp;#8217;s largest not-for-profit development teams in the education industry, we have supported over 100 projects in the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Position Description&lt;br /&gt;
Making technology easy to use&amp;#8212;We are seeking an Interaction Designer to join our User Experience group who can strike the right balance between creative and analytical thinking. Participate in concept development, user-centered design, and specifications for a wide variety of projects. Good communication skills and the ability to manage priorities in a fast-paced environment are a must for our busy team. The job is located in our downtown San Francisco office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibilities&lt;br /&gt;
The Interaction Designer will work collaboratively with art director, project manager, tech team and clients to design for web applications, content-based websites, data visualizations, mobile devices and multimedia presentations. Activities include requirements gathering, task analysis, personas, user scenarios, information architecture, interaction design, screen layouts, prototypes, observe or conduct usability testing. Create specifications, ensure usability and that design standards are applied throughout entire site. Graphic design skills are a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BIG&lt;/span&gt; plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qualifications&lt;br /&gt;
- Minimum 4-5 years relevant experience desired (as user interface designer, information architect, web designer)&lt;br /&gt;
- Strong understanding of and enthusiasm for user-centered design principles&lt;br /&gt;
- Strong visual, verbal and written communication skills, with ability to successfully communicate design rationale to a mixed audience&lt;br /&gt;
- A curious outlook and ability to develop new approaches to complex design problems&lt;br /&gt;
- Ability to create navigation flowcharts, wireframes/storyboards&lt;br /&gt;
- Knowledge of current web technologies and how they create opportunities or limitations for interface design&lt;br /&gt;
- Understanding of W3C and 508 accessibility guidelines&lt;br /&gt;
- Proficiency with Illustrator and Photoshop (Mac platform preferred)&lt;br /&gt;
- Proficiency with OmniGraffle or similar software for flowcharts, wireframes, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
- Clean, modern visual design sense for simple and intuitive interfaces&lt;br /&gt;
- Links to example projects or portfolio with a clear description of role played for each&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice to Have&lt;br /&gt;
- Graphic design skills: concept development and design graphic systems via screen layout templates, color palettes, iconography, typography, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application Process&lt;br /&gt;
We invite you to apply online at &lt;a href="http://www.WestEd.org/jobs"&gt;www.WestEd.org/jobs&lt;/a&gt; or you may send your resume, a letter of interest (specify Job No. 2815) and a list of three references to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human Resources&lt;br /&gt;
WestEd&lt;br /&gt;
730 Harrison Street&lt;br /&gt;
San Francisco, CA 94107&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAX&lt;/span&gt;: 415-565-3012&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.WestEd.org"&gt;http://www.WestEd.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benefits Highlights&lt;br /&gt;
    * All health benefits effective day one of employment&lt;br /&gt;
    * 15% contribution toward retirement effective day one of employment&lt;br /&gt;
    * 20 vacation days, 10 holidays, 2 personal days&lt;br /&gt;
    * 12 sick days&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Apply online at: &lt;a href="http://www.wested.org/cs/we/view/hr_pos/2815"&gt;http://www.wested.org/cs/we/view/hr_pos/2815&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 19:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4759</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4759</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiceworks: Rails Programmer</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1769/logo.gif?1232557399" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin, TX
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.spiceworks.com"&gt;http://www.spiceworks.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiceworks (&lt;a href="http://www.spiceworks.com"&gt;www.spiceworks.com&lt;/a&gt;) is a small well funded three year old start-up located in Austin, Texas. The Spiceworks IT Network is rapidly growing social application used by over half a million  IT Professionals. Spiceworks has been featured in publications like the Wall Street Journal, PC Magazine, and Advertising Age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a great opportunity for a motivated rails developer who is looking to own, design, build, and successfully launch new features that thrill our users. We use Prototype, Scriptaculous, RoR, Apache, and Postgres. We&#8217;re light on unnecessary process and big on collaboration. We need your strong problem-solving and analytical skills as we tackle challenging problems. You will own a critical piece of the backend infrastructure and help us scale our rapidly growing site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RoR experience is preferred&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expertise in designing and building scalable web applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience in designing database schemas, crafting, and tuning &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt; queries. Postgres experience is a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience with configuring or maintaining Apache is a plus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience with building UIs in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, Javascript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bachelors in Computer Science is desired&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3+ years of professional experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start-up or small company experience is a plus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passion for building a great product is a must&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Send a resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%74%61%62%72%65%7a@%73%70%69%63%65%77%6f%72%6b%73.%63%6f%6d"&gt;tabrez@spiceworks.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 17:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4758</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4758</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The College Board: User Experience Analyst, Dot.Com Department</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; New York, NY or Reston, VA
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.collegeboard.com/careers"&gt;www.collegeboard.com/careers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The College Board, a national educational organization, is conducting a search for a User Experience Analyst to work within the College Board Dot.Com department. This position can be based out of our New York City or Reston, Virginia office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;POSITION&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SUMMARY&lt;/span&gt;                                             &lt;br /&gt;
The User Experience Analyst, working alongside senior user experience team members, will gather customer insights, conduct usability analyses, and create personas; task analyses, page flow diagrams and other artifacts associated with a user-centered design methodology, and develop and present recommendations and findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal candidate is an empathetic listener and creative thinker who is passionate about the Web and who can work with ease among team members from various disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RESPONSIBILITIES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In collaboration with senior user experience team members, will:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Gather user feedback, develop an understanding of user needs, and create the appropriate tools to translate that understanding into actionable information&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Maintain and build on the College Board&amp;#8217;s in house usability practice&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Plan, design and conduct high quality user experience research projects for the Web site and related products (mobile, etc.)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Oversee the planning, creation and execution of research surveys for the Web site and related products&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Work closely with product teams to provide user insights&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Validate requirements and design solutions with customers and internal users through usability testing, cognitive walkthroughs, heuristic evaluations, and other testing methods&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Document and present research and usability findings and recommendations to development teams&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Create personas, task analyses, task flow diagrams, and information architecture diagrams&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Research and recommend latest best practices in user interface design, barrier free design, and information design, revising established standards and guidelines as warranted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;QUALIFICATIONS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
2-5 years user research experience (e.g., standard usability testing, eye-tracking, card sorting, focus groups and survey design), user interface/interaction design or development, or visual/information design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bachelor&amp;#8217;s degree required; Master&amp;#8217;s a plus.  Degrees or studies in anthropology, cognitive or experimental psychology, cognitive science, human factors, human-computer interaction, computer science, or related field a plus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;REQUIREMENTS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;   Experience with a variety of research methods&lt;br /&gt;
Familiarity with Morae or other usability analyst tools&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;   An understanding of user interface technology and barrier-free and accessible design&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;   Strong project management and decision-making skills&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;   Excellent oral and written communications skills&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;   Able to use insights from user research to provide product strategy and innovation recommendations&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;   A passion for the Internet and a keen interest in how people think, behave, and feel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The College Board is a national educational association of schools, colleges and universities founded to aid the transition of students from secondary school to higher education. Our mission, &#8220;Connect to College Success,&#8221; emphasizes both high academic standards and a commitment to prepare all students across the entire social and economic spectrum. We offer our employees an outstanding benefits package, which includes 4 weeks of vacation, a generous retirement plan, tuition reimbursement and ongoing professional development and training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining the College Board apply by visiting our website at &lt;a href="http://www.collegeboard.com/careers"&gt;www.collegeboard.com/careers&lt;/a&gt;. Please forward your resume and a cover letter that includes salary expectations.  The College Board is dedicated to the principle of equal opportunity and its programs, services and employment policies are guided by that principle.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Apply by visiting our website at &lt;a href="http://www.collegeboard.com/careers"&gt;www.collegeboard.com/careers&lt;/a&gt;. Please forward your resume and a cover letter that includes salary expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 14:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4757</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4757</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Web Strategy: WEB DESIGNER</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1768/logo.gif?1232481259" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Alexandria, VA/Washington DC
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.workwithiws.com/"&gt;http://www.workwithiws.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMPLOYMENT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;INTERACTIVE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;POSITION&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8211; Washington, DC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WEB&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DESIGNER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a full-time Web Designer/Graphic designer who is fluent in design applications and has an understanding of design and web site usability principles. The ideal candidate must:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;    Be an expert in Photoshop, Illustrator and DreamWeaver (or hand coding)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Have a working knowledge of Flash&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Be able to code in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; and/or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; (cutup)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Have experience in creating effective interactive user flow&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Be comfortable (fearless) presenting creative ideas to clients and colleagues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLUSES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;    Print design&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Illustration skills&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Advanced Flash/Action Scripting skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;POSITION&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;REQUIRES&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;    Ability to work independently and take initiative&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Ability to multi-task, work well under pressure and deadlines&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Excellent communication skills (written, verbal &amp;amp; interpersonal)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;    Must be highly organized and motivated, able to &amp;quot;hit the ground running&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TO &lt;span class="caps"&gt;APPLY&lt;/span&gt;: Please send resume and cover letter to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%62%72%69%61%6e@%77%6f%72%6b%77%69%74%68%69%77%73.%63%6f%6d"&gt;brian@workwithiws.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EOE&lt;/span&gt;, NO &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CALLS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLEASE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Send resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%62%72%69%61%6e@%77%6f%72%6b%77%69%74%68%69%77%73.%63%6f%6d"&gt;brian@workwithiws.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 19:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4756</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4756</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canonical: QA Engineer, Online Services</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Home Worker
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.canonical.com"&gt;www.canonical.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a QA Engineer with the Online Services team, you will be responsible for ensuring that the service quality is at the best possible level by developing processes and tools for monitoring complex web based services, performing &lt;br /&gt;
automated testing and performance measurements, and working with the rest of the development team to triage, prioritize, and resolve issues. You will help us scale services from small initial deployments through to millions of users.&lt;br /&gt;
Key responsibilities:&lt;br /&gt;
-Develop and maintain error reporting and log analysis tools written in python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Monitoring and meaningful reporting of health of large scale web service deployments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Identify and coordinate the resolution of errors from logs and automated tools&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Work with the development team and the operational team to test and launch the initial version, and then to deploy new releases of the service without disrupting users of the service.&lt;br /&gt;
-Offer expert guidance to the team on how to design systems to run in a cloud environment like Amazon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-EC2 and designing services to be highly available using load balancers and other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Participate in continuous code review along with the rest of the team, learning and offering constructive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific job skills:&lt;br /&gt;
-Management and configuration of services in Linux, with a solid grasp of web technologies, web services, and networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Ability to debug, identify and pinpoint problems in complex networked web applications (load balancers, caching servers, etc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Strong English communication skills, especially over phone, email, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Strong testing and development skills (python or other dynamic language). Experience with packaging software (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DEB&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt;) is a plus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Experience with tools such as HAProxy, Windmill, EC2/Eucalyptus is a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Must know how to monitor hundreds of servers and keep them all running smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Please send your resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%56%61%6c%65%6e%74%69%6e%61.%6c%61%7a%61%72%65%76%69%63@%63%61%6e%6f%6e%69%63%61%6c.%63%6f%6d"&gt;Valentina.lazarevic@canonical.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 11:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4755</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4755</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinfo: Senior Rails Developer</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; San Francisco, CA
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.kinfo.com"&gt;http://www.kinfo.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senior Ruby on Rails Developer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kinfo is a well-funded start-up located in San Francisco, CA. We&#8217;re building a great consumer service that people will love. We&#8217;ve got an awesome small team, and a collaborative environment filled with smart, high energy, passionate people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly motivated, self-directed Ruby on Rails developer with at least 5 years of full-stack web development and 2 years of Rails experience to join our tightly knit team. We believe strongly in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;TDD&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;BDD&lt;/span&gt; and are committed to RSpec and RSpec stories, but as humans we know that 100% code coverage is an ideal, not dogma. On the front end we use Prototype, Scriptaculous, and Low Pro (yes, we know jQuery is the one our mother wishes we had married). On the back end we use MySQL, S3 and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQS&lt;/span&gt;. In the middle, of course, is Rails &#61514;(currently 2.1.0, we&amp;#8217;re up to date, but not so edgy as to use Edge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We manage our process using Scrum. We do our best to limit overhead, protect developers from distractions, and keep the focus on making a great product from top to bottom. You&amp;#8217;ll have the opportunity to work on a wide variety of projects. The engineering team does a comprehensive code review at the end of each sprint, so you will benefit from our experience and we from yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers have pride of place in our Victorian office near South Park with a sunny &amp;quot;Dev Parlor&amp;quot; in front and a couch-filled &amp;quot;Conference Parlor&amp;quot; in the back. Our office manager keeps our larder stocked with fruit, sweet &amp;amp; salty snacks, and sodas. We have mastered the subtleties of brewing Blue Bottle coffee, which we keep in plentiful supply. We also mix it up by spending occasional days teleworking at home or in cafes, as suits the needs of our individual team members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salary and stock options are competitive and we offer great health and dental insurance.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%6b%69%6e%66%6f.%6a%6f%62%73@%67%6d%61%69%6c.%63%6f%6d"&gt;kinfo.jobs@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 02:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4754</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4754</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TheLadders.com: Web Development Manager</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; New York, New York
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.theladders.com"&gt;www.theladders.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TheLadders was named one of the 2009 Best Companies to Work for in New York and we&#8217;re looking for a Development Manager!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silicon Alley Insider Names TheLadders most valuable Digital Startup in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NYC&lt;/span&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ladders is one of fastest growing companies in the US with 300+ employees. Our Technology Department is experiencing unprecedented growth and as a result we are currently looking to hire multiple Software Engineers, Web Developers, and Managers for our Tech Department. If you have a strong background in Web 2.0 in a Java environment, passion for cutting edge technology and solving live production problems &#8211; TheLadders might be the place for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a highly technical Development Manager who can drive projects and provide leadership for our engineers in an innovative and fast paced environment. You will be responsible for the overall planning, execution, and success of several projects. We are looking for someone with a passion for technology coupled with great communication skills. We are seeking a hard-working, adaptable problem solver, who loves challenges and feels comfortable working directly with marketing, product, creative and other teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This position will lead an advanced technology team using new programming paradigms such as Agile/Test Driven Development and industry leading technologies such as the Spring Framework, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AJAX&lt;/span&gt;, Lucene, design patterns, etc. This is a fast, open environment where innovation and participation is encouraged through blogging, custom tool development, hack-day events or other out-of-the-box techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	Provide leadership and mentoring to Engineering staff&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Create and document the technical design to meet requirements&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Ownership and development of end-to-end projects using both Java backend and web technologies&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Participate in the creation of project plans, resource allocation and estimated timelines&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Strong attention to detail; passion for technology, challenging environments and excellence&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Excellent communication skills a must&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Interact with the business owners, product and quality assurance teams to set priorities and resolve defects, change requests and issues&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Work with the following technologies: Java, Spring, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSP&lt;/span&gt;, MySQL, Tomcat, Lucene, Javascript, Ant/Ivy, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CVS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	6+ years experience as a developer including at least 2 years in a management capacity&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Experience developing J2EE applications using both backend Java and web technologies, e.g. JavaScript, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JSTL&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AJAX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Strong communication skills &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Ability to understand business needs and liaise with business owners &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Ability to problem solve and troubleshoot issues&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Fluent in creating project plans and managing to them&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Experience developing and deploying a production system on the Unix platform (Linux preferred)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Must know how to architect scalable, robust, highly available high performing web sites and have in-depth knowledge of web development methodologies, tools and techniques&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Must have strong understanding of relational database concepts including &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt;, indexes, transactions and writing software that communicates with a database&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	BS in Computer Science or related field, or equivalent experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TheLadders.com is the world&amp;#8217;s largest online service catering exclusively to the $100k+ career marketplace. Located in New York and London, we make the global search for senior talent and senior positions quick and effective. We give professionals the most senior-level job leads in one place and organize them by function for more efficient searching. Through TheLadders.com and our UK site, TheLadders.co.uk, we give our members the tools they need to take their next career step. Top recruiters value the ability to quickly and easily connect with qualified talent. Founded in 2003, TheLadders.com has grown into the largest specialty employment website with over 1,800,000 members and 35,000 recruiters. To learn more about TheLadders.com, please visit &lt;a href="http://www.theladders.com"&gt;www.theladders.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.theladders.co.uk"&gt;www.theladders.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a dynamic, fast-paced, high-growth internet company that rewards meritorious performance. We work hard and have big fun. We are a results oriented, goals driven team with a strong commitment to excellence. We hire the best and the brightest individuals without regard to race, color, religion, creed, age, sex, sexual orientation, pregnancy, national origin, ancestry, marital status, veteran status, citizenship status, alienage, mental or physical disability, genetic predisposition or genetic carrier status, on the basis of knowledge or belief that the employee or applicant has tested positive for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AIDS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AIDS&lt;/span&gt;-related complex or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HIV&lt;/span&gt;, or any other basis protected by federal, state or local law. TheLadders.com is an equal opportunity employer.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Please submit resume at &lt;a href="http://hostedjobs.openhire.com/epostings/jobs/submit.cfm?fuseaction=dspjob&amp;amp;id=23&amp;amp;jobid=275730&amp;amp;company_id=15772&amp;amp;version=1&amp;amp;source=ONLINE&amp;amp;JobOwner=988183&amp;amp;level=levelid2&amp;amp;levelid2=23018&amp;amp;parent=Technology%3B%3B%3BSoftware%20Development&amp;amp;s"&gt;http://hostedjobs.openhire.com/epostings/jobs/submit.cfm?fuseaction=dspjob&amp;amp;id=23&amp;amp;jobid=275730&amp;amp;company_id=15772&amp;amp;version=1&amp;amp;source=ONLINE&amp;amp;JobOwner=988183&amp;amp;level=levelid2&amp;amp;levelid2=23018&amp;amp;parent=Technology%3B%3B%3BSoftware%20Development&amp;amp;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 23:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4753</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4753</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ShareThis: Team Leader, Web Team</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1766/logo.gif?1232401525" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Mountain View, CA
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://sharethis.com/"&gt;http://sharethis.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About ShareThis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ShareThis is a service in the emerging social media space that enables site publishers and site users to utilize a simple one-button option to share site content with others through email, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SMS&lt;/span&gt;, instant messenger, social networks, and social bookmarking. ShareThis offers a widget for use by publishers, a browser plugin for users and a ShareBox to see and store past shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already experienced significant growth both in adoption by site publishers and share actions by users. Over 70,000 publishers have incorporated the ShareThis widget driving nearly two billion page views monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team shares a deep passion for making sharing simple, bringing together a diverse set of talent and experience from companies such as Advertising.com, Amazon, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AOL&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IAC&lt;/span&gt;, LinkedIn, Nielsen Buzzmetrics, Yahoo! and Google/YouTube. Investors are Draper Fisher Jurvetson, Blue Chip Venture Company, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DFJ&lt;/span&gt; Mercury, Reservoir Partners, Illinois Ventures, Queen City Angels and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RPM&lt;/span&gt; Ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal profile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idealized candidate is most likely to be a hybrid: part visionary/part architect/and part builder.  This needs to be a candidate that is clearly passionate about the large opportunity associated with online advertising, and social media. As such, it demands a person that is extremely attracted to the opportunity and is never satisfied with the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to apply innovative technology to business problems and execution comes first for this candidate. It is essential for the candidate to have outstanding technical and product sense.  From a technical perspective, the candidate must have direct domain experience in the latest web technologies relevant to user experience such as Ajax, Javascript, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, Widget containers, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;. The candidate must demonstrate first hand experience in building and deploying large traffic websites and related user interaction elements on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal candidate is likely to come from a company involved in web portals, social networking, or related web 2.0 services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The job:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Team Leader will lead a team chartered with design, implementation, and delivery of ShareThis web presence including website, widgets, and various other innovative content delivery artifacts in the future. This is a key initiative for the company since it reflects our presence with users; as such garners significant visibility at senior levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position reports to the Chief Technology Officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibilities of this position include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-	Innovative Product Development: The successful candidate will be responsible for innovating and shaping our web presence that benefits consumers, publishers, and partners. You will lead a team to conceptualize product components, technology architecture, implementation and integration between various systems within the company that will collectively work together to deliver a solution. Much of this involves significant innovation in user experience and &#8220;breaking new ground&#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-	Technology Architecture: As the senior technology leader you will own the platform architecture and insure that it is highly scalable, extensible, and adaptive as it evolves through the next 12-18 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-	Product Rollout:  The product plan is to make significant improvements in the content and method of how users interact with ShareThis web elements through 2009. You will work with Product Management and other technology groups in defining the roadmap, scope, deliverables.  You will be responsible to drive an iterative approach to rollout in testing, refining, and improving features based on audience response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-	Business Integration: There are a number of ways to develop and grow our web experience such as web containers that deliver content to users on other sites, and new innovative Ad Units that actively engage users when visible on partner properties, to name a few. You will develop collaborative relationships with our Business Development &amp;amp; Sales teams to help analyze and scope solutions that impact our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Educational Requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.S/M.S in computer science from a leading school or related technical discipline with a bias towards Information Architecture, and User Experience Design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional traits necessary for all ShareThis team members:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.	Is right a lot.&lt;br /&gt;
2.	Helps hire and develop great technical talent.&lt;br /&gt;
3.	Has relentlessly high standards &lt;br /&gt;
4.	No task is beneath this person.&lt;br /&gt;
5.	Expects and requires innovation of her/his team.&lt;br /&gt;
6.	Has conviction.&lt;br /&gt;
7.	Results oriented.&lt;br /&gt;
8.	Thinks big.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Please send your email cover letter and resume with the subject &amp;quot;Your name &#8211; Team Leader, Web Team &#8211; via 37signals&amp;quot; to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%6a%6f%62%73@%73%68%61%72%65%74%68%69%73.%63%6f%6d"&gt;jobs@sharethis.com&lt;/a&gt;. All communication and correspondence is held in the strictest confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 22:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4752</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4752</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SceneDaily.com: Open Source Web Developer</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Charlotte, NC
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.scenedaily.com"&gt;http://www.scenedaily.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media site seeks candidates with open source development skills for the role of Sr. Web Developer. Some of the skills needed include: Ruby on Rails, Python (Django), &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt;, Velocity, MySQL, javascript, and more. An open mind and flexibility is a must in this fast-paced environment. Some, but minimal, hardware/sys admin skills also needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Role will assume responsibilities for coding, testing, deploying and maintaining all web-based efforts for the site. This includes collaborating with other members of the online team to ensure that the entire development process from planning, design, development, implementation, and maintenance, are executed with the highest quality in mind. This role will advocate for standards compliant best practices at all levels of development. This role will work closely with the Senior Web Designer on design and development concerns to ensure an effective and efficient workflow for the overall development cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, this role will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Maintain, de-bug, optimize and enhance existing code in place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Participate in and contribute to the planning process for new projects and give input on specific technologies utilized to complete projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Develop new code according to project specs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This position is on-site in Charlotte.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Send resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%63%68%61%72%6c%6f%74%74%65%77%65%62%64%65%76%65%6c%6f%70%65%72@%67%6d%61%69%6c.%63%6f%6d"&gt;charlottewebdeveloper@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 18:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4751</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4751</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VYRE: Web Designer</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1765/logo.gif?1232382600" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; London
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.vyre.com"&gt;http://www.vyre.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you code what you design? At &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VYRE&lt;/span&gt; we build web applications and content managed sites from our relaxed office in Old Street, London. We need a talented and technically savvy Web Designer to design and code sites for our big name clients. We also get fruit delivered twice a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, we&#8217;re looking for the following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	3+ Years experience&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Experience working on commercial or information driven web sites&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A portfolio and/or some sample URLs to look at&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A high level of spoken and written English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	Very good with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; and Photoshop&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Pretty good with Illustrator&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Cross browser compliant&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	An all rounder &#8211; on top of client sites you&#8217;ll be helping out with our web site and print based marketing materials&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Able to present work to clients in an appropriate and professional way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would also be nice if you were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226;	Really good at print work&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Able to write Flash (ActionScript)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A dabbler in Javascript/Jquery&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Knowledgeable about Content Management Systems&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A tea and cake connoisseur&lt;br /&gt;
Your working week would include:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Designing sites that look really good&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Writing clean css for new (and existing) sites&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Internal company branding (print mainly, but also online)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VYRE&lt;/span&gt; is software development company that specialises in web based technology. &lt;br /&gt;
Headquartered in London the key product is Unify, a web based application building framework and content management solution.&lt;br /&gt;
Unify from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VYRE&lt;/span&gt; is a complete, &#64258;exible framework for the creation and management of dynamic content driven websites and web based applications. Rapidly implemented and easily adopted by users of all skill levels, Unify is a feature rich architecture which offers versatility and performance whilst providing a cost effective way of managing both structured and unstructured content. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;VYRE&lt;/span&gt; has a large portfolio of clients ranging from Diageo (the largest drinks company in the world) to Sony, Virgin and Woolworths.  Our projects range from large public facing websites to internal intranets, extranets and internal business process applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This position is Full Time working out of our offices in London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%64%65%73%69%67%6e%6a%6f%62@%76%79%72%65.%63%6f%6d"&gt;designjob@vyre.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 16:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4750</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4750</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serious Business: Rails Engineer</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; San Francisco, CA
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.seriousbusiness.com"&gt;http://www.seriousbusiness.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WHO&lt;/span&gt; WE &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ARE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to fun games, it&amp;#8217;s Serious Business. We&amp;#8217;ve got Facebook&amp;#8217;s top social game, the world&amp;#8217;s largest rails cluster, and we&amp;#8217;re just getting started&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some press:&lt;br /&gt;
San Francisco Chronicle: &lt;a href="http://tinyurl.com/5pwqz6"&gt;http://tinyurl.com/5pwqz6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
TechCrunch: &lt;a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/04/25/lightspeed-funding-turns-facebook-application-into-serious-business/"&gt;http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/04/25/lightspeed-funding-turns-facebook-application-into-serious-business/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
VentureBeat: &lt;a href="http://venturebeat.com/2008/04/25/creators-of-facebook-app-friends-for-sale-raise-round-not-for-sale/"&gt;http://venturebeat.com/2008/04/25/creators-of-facebook-app-friends-for-sale-raise-round-not-for-sale/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WHAT&lt;/span&gt; WE &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ARE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOOKING&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FOR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking to hire rockstar Ruby/Rails engineers, like, yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know Ruby but not Rails?&lt;br /&gt;
No sweat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know Rails but not Ruby?&lt;br /&gt;
Sweat. But apply anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t know either ruby or rails?&lt;br /&gt;
Sweaty McSweaterson. But if you&amp;#8217;ve got mad skillz we&amp;#8217;d still like to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t live in the Bay Area?&lt;br /&gt;
We&amp;#8217;ll move you here. We subsidize 5k in relocation expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got friends?&lt;br /&gt;
We pay a 10k referral bonus to anyone who refers a developer that we hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WHAT&lt;/span&gt; YOU&amp;#8217;LL &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GET&lt;/span&gt; TO DO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Be one of the guys that makes Rails scaling happen&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Build out infrastructure to support rapid, scalable social application development&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Work on products that millions (we&amp;#8217;re serious) of people use every single day&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Contribute back to open source projects like god and merb&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Have a life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CULTURE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are serious about culture here at Serious. More than just great engineers, we want to hire great people. We are going to be spending a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOT&lt;/span&gt; of time together, so we want you to know our expectations up front:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Smart, this is Serious Business after all&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Gets things done &amp;#8211; we value prototypes and code over posturing and talk&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Agile, tee dee dee, able to work on a variety of projects&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We&amp;#8217;re a team &amp;#8211; so everybody does the dishes&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurial &amp;#8211; everybody has serious ownership and serious say in Serious Business&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Excited to work on projects with lots of unknowns and designing elegant solutions for problems that have quite literally never been solved before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOCATION&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtown San Francisco (2nd and Market)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLUS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LOTS&lt;/span&gt; OF &lt;span class="caps"&gt;BULLET&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;POINTS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;30 inch monitors (because we love pixels)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Aeron chairs (used from Craigslist, but hey)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;MacBook Pros (standard)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Full health, vision, dental&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Commuter passes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and when you respond please let us know how you found out about this job opening.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Please send resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%77%6f%72%6b@%73%65%72%69%6f%75%73%62%75%73%69%6e%65%73%73.%63%6f%6d"&gt;work@seriousbusiness.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 07:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4749</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4749</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master Web Design: Ruby on Rails programmer with frontend experience.</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1764/logo.gif?1232307891" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Austin, TX
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.masterwebdesign.net"&gt;http://www.masterwebdesign.net&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Master Web Design is an Austin, TX web design and development firm. We focus on creating complex web applications which focus on usability, maintainability, and brilliant design. We are a tight knit team of developers who work closely with each other to deliver the strongest possible product to our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We work hard, we play hard, and we all have a blast doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We currently have an opening a Ruby on Rails Developers who can demonstrate the following skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note this is an onsite, full time contract to hire position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; 2+ years experience in Web Production with a focus (1 year+) on Ruby on Rails or similar environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Intermediate to Advanced level of understanding of Ruby on Rails best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Experience with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; and JavaScript. You must be able to hand-code, analyze, debug, and deliver clean, maintainable code which is similar in all major browsers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Strong background in Web Design, ability to design for usability, information architecture, and willingness to keep up with the latest in internet technologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Willingness and ability to test your Rails, Javascript, and interface code with rSpec, Selenium, or other test suites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Excellent organizational, analytical, problem solving, and research skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Strong cross-team project management and communication skills in a fast paced, deadline driven environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Ability to work in the Apple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OSX&lt;/span&gt; environment or equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidate should demonstrate proficiency with:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Hand coding &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Hand coding complex &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt; joins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8226; Testing Frameworks&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Please send resume to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%44%61%6c%6c%61%73.%50%6f%6f%6c@%6d%61%73%74%65%72%77%65%62%64%65%73%69%67%6e.%6e%65%74"&gt;Dallas.Pool@masterwebdesign.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 19:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4747</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4747</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spitball: PHP/MySQL Developer</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1762/logo.gif?1232126658" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; NJ or East Coast preferred
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.spit-ball.com"&gt;http://www.spit-ball.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be developing simple websites to complex custom applications. You will need to see these projects through from start to finish. The projects will range from:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Building content management systems&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Custom eCommerce systems with integrated or external inventory database integration&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Architecting and building unique online content, experiences and systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must be able to play nice with others including designers, project managers and especially clients &amp;#8211; who you will need to interface with at times to understand, document and deliver upon their requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things you &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GOTTA&lt;/span&gt; have:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; 3-5 years of web development&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, MySQL, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SSL&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience with open-source &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt; as well as creating custom &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Passion for what you do&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Communication skills&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Attention to detail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things we&amp;#8217;d like you to have:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Sense of humor&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AJAX&lt;/span&gt;, RoR&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Front-end development (slicing and coding)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an off-site position. This is not full-time but could lead to it for the right person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spitball is a creative agency located in Red Bank NJ focusing on developing unique advertising and online ideas. With clients including Save Ellis Island, mtvU, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt; as well as local businesses, the range and style of work varies from one day to the next.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Send resume with URLs with descriptions of relevant web applications you've developed and include your role in each to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%68%72@%73%70%69%74-%62%61%6c%6c.%63%6f%6d"&gt;hr@spit-ball.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 17:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4746</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4746</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GS Design: Interactive (Visual) Designer</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1757/logo.gif?1232125392" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Milwaukee, WI
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.gsdesign.com"&gt;http://www.gsdesign.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GS Design is seeking an extremely creative interactive designer to play a pivotal role in helping us create high-quality, innovative and engaging online user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Interactive Designer will be involved with various interactive design projects including web sites, intranets, mini/micro sites, web applications, banner ads and email campaigns. You will work closely with design, project management, IA/UX and technical teams to create designs and satisfying user experiences that meet our clients&#8217; business objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for someone who:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;&#160;Enjoys being challenged and is not scared to push the envelope&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Is a perfectionist who is capable of working on multiple projects simultaneously&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Is highly self-motivated as well as a good team player&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Is comfortable presenting the creative vision and business thinking behind their concepts&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Excels at maintaining design consistency and brand identity across all projects they work on&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; To apply for this position, please send a cover letter, resum&#233;, salary history and portfolio to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%63%61%72%65%65%72%73@%67%73%64%65%73%69%67%6e.%63%6f%6d"&gt;careers@gsdesign.com&lt;/a&gt;. We respond to qualified applicants. No phone calls please.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 17:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4745</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4745</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Roamer: Software Developer</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1756/logo.gif?1232060725" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Memphis, TN
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.americanroamer.com"&gt;www.americanroamer.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a stable, 20 year old company that provides data and research services to the wireless telecommunications industry. Our team is responsible for providing web-based customer solutions, data management and analysis, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GIS&lt;/span&gt; development, and application &amp;amp; systems architecture. We are a small company, so we are looking for people who are looking to see their daily work make a big impact on our future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be a smart, multi-talented developer with a love for technology and a strong desire to &amp;quot;get things done.&amp;quot; We work with a large range of software technologies and platforms and we have a bunch of challenging projects to peak any developers interest. We&amp;#8217;ve grown and changed quite a bit recently and plan to continue this trend, so you should thrive in a place where exciting change is always happening. We&amp;#8217;re in the process of migrating our internal database management system to a stack of Adobe Flex, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL. In addition, we&amp;#8217;re moving our production infrastructure to Amazon Web Services, which we are thrilled with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things we&amp;#8217;d like to see in our ideal candidate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A few years of real experience. You&amp;#8217;ve built things, made mistakes, and learned from them.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Work with open or closed source. You can fairly weigh pros and cons of each.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A good understanding of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt; (we use PostgreSQL) and good database design principles.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;#8217;t mind going it alone or working in a team.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You seek out new technology, get excited about it, and can find applications for it that make sense.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You have a liking for Ruby.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You&amp;#8217;re able to work in Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Experience with source control, bug tracking, and agile development methodology.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You like to test your software automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We offer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An opportunity to work with a great set of cutting-edge development technology.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A great work environment and work/life balance.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A well-equipped, multi-screen workstation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%68%72@%61%6d%65%72%69%63%61%6e%72%6f%61%6d%65%72.%63%6f%6d"&gt;hr@americanroamer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 23:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4744</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4744</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synacor: Web Architect</title>
      <description>&lt;img alt="Logo" src="/logos/0000/1752/logo.gif?1232029143" /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Buffalo, NY
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.synacor.com"&gt;http://www.synacor.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Synacor is a dynamic, fun and exciting company.  Jeans and t-shirts are typical office attire, even for the executives. Flexible work hours accommodate employees with special scheduling needs, early risers and those who need a little caffeinated kick-start each morning. Synacor&amp;#8217;s headquarters are located along Buffalo&amp;#8217;s waterfront and the Erie Basin Marina. Taking a few minutes to stretch your legs is as easy as walking the 1,000 feet or so to the water. The office wireless network even reaches a beautiful gazebo, making it easy to spend a little time outdoors while still being productive. We are looking for great people to join our team and be given the freedom to do the work they were hired to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently searching for a Web Architect who will partner with the Product organization to help drive product innovation and specification, as well as provide guidance during development.  The web architect will be responsible for defining the technical architecture of web applications.    We&#8217;re looking for someone who has an extensive background in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; application development in a high volume environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duties and Responsibilities:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Own the technical design of Web applications and write technical specifications, including information architecture, data design, and technical details&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Work with product team to define software products by consulting during specification stage, performing research, developing prototypes or proofs-of-concept, participating in calls and vendor selection activities, and acting as an expert technical contributor&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Contribute to general development efforts by producing documentation and training materials and conducting training sessions&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Develop and maintain expertise in a wide range of industry technologies including cable/&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ISP&lt;/span&gt; billing and provisioning systems, end-to-end video distribution (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IPTV&lt;/span&gt;) and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt; technologies, federated identity initiatives, and emerging Internet technologies&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Generate proposals for the Executive team and conduct presentation/training sessions for Synacor staff. Participate in open source initiatives, standards organizations and industry groups&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Work with the development teams to ensure implementation of the product vision&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Provide communication and integration point to other parts of Engineering, IT, and System organization including other architects to identify and address any issues or impact that projects might have on those areas&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Other duties as assigned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you&#8217;ll need to bring to the table:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; A passion for Internet development&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Relentlessly seeks to expand your knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Strategic, sensible, and able to see both the forest and the trees&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Great collaborator with both technical and non-technical staff&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Great organizational skills&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Quality focused&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Mandatory experience with building high-volume Web applications&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Extensive programming expertise in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LAMP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience writing software design specifications&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Familiarity with a wide range of Internet applications, technologies, sites, and business models&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Bachelor&#8217;s Degree in Computer science or related degree; or related expertise and experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional desired experience depending on architect role:&lt;br /&gt;
Video&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Expertise working with embedded video players (Windows Media, flv_playback, etc.), their features and functionality&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Expertise with the capabilities of streaming servers such as Helix or Flash Media Server&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience with CDN&#8217;s&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Communications/Convergence&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience with webmail systems (ex. Zimbra) especially from the development standpoint&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience with mobile applications&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Familiarity with digital home technologies (UPnP, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DLNA&lt;/span&gt;) or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OCAP&lt;/span&gt; a plus&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VOIP&lt;/span&gt; softswitch integrations a plus&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PIE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Expertise using Web integration methods including &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SOAP&lt;/span&gt;, and proprietary API&#8217;s and protocols&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Experience with Web-based premium service offerings a plus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we&#8217;ll bring to the table:&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; 100% Company paid benefits (health, dental, vision)&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Competitive compensation&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; 25 cent vending machines&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Free Spot coffee, popcorn and cappuccino&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Award winning company culture&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Casual dress and flexible environment&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; Generous paid time off&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; H1B Visa Sponsorship available&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226; The opportunity to make a difference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Relocation to Buffalo, NY is required for this position &#8211; relocation assistance is available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply please visit our website; &lt;a href="http://www.synacor.com/jobs"&gt;www.synacor.com/jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; Apply online at: &lt;a href="http://www.synacor.com/jons"&gt;http://www.synacor.com/jons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 14:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4742</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4742</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Institute of Mental Health: Chief, Electronic Communications Branch</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Rockville, MD
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.nimh.nih.gov/"&gt;http://www.nimh.nih.gov/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Mental Health, a major research component of the National Institutes of Health (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIH&lt;/span&gt;) and the Department of Health and Human Services (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHHS&lt;/span&gt;), is seeking exceptional candidates for the position of Chief for the Electronic Communications Branch. This position reports to the Director of the Office of Science Policy, Planning and Communications, and serves as the Branch Chief as well as a chief strategist for electronic communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Role:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIMH&lt;/span&gt; is seeking an enthusiastic and creative visionary for Chief of the Electronic Communications Branch&#8212;the component responsible for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIMH&lt;/span&gt; Web sites and other ways to disseminate information electronically. There has been an exponential growth in the public relying on our Web site to find the latest news, information, and content on mental health research. As the Branch Chief, you will supervise a total of 6 technical information and IT specialists and direct all web content &amp;amp; operations in the Branch, including oversight of the content management system. You will also be responsible for setting the creative direction for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIMH&lt;/span&gt; Web site and electronic communications, which could include site redesign, changes to information architecture, podcasting, and graphics/video incorporation, among other activities. In addition, you will evaluate  site analytics, trends, and feedback to make the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIMH&lt;/span&gt; Web site a more efficient and attractive resource for the public. Duties of the Chief will include assisting the Branch members with their daily responsibilities and advising Institute staff on policies and procedures for displaying and disseminating information electronically. Additional responsibilities include directing and overseeing all Section 508 compliance activities for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIMH&lt;/span&gt; Web sites and networking with other components of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIH&lt;/span&gt; on the Web and Web-based technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qualifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Proficient knowledge of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XHTML&lt;/span&gt; strict and Web-based technologies&lt;br /&gt;
-Proficient in Section 508 compliance&lt;br /&gt;
- Superior management skills&lt;br /&gt;
-Superior customer service skills&lt;br /&gt;
-Organized, responsible, and detail-oriented&lt;br /&gt;
-Excellent verbal and written communication skills&lt;br /&gt;
-Ability to work under pressure and commit to deadlines&lt;br /&gt;
-Ability to multi-task and prioritize&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact:&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
Interested candidates should send a letter of interest, resume, a a brief description of career interests to: Cheryl Leone, Administrative Officer,  Office of Science Policy, Planning and Communications, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIMH&lt;/span&gt; at 6001 Executive Blvd, Room 8112, Bethesda, MD 20892; Tel. (301) 443-3836; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FAX&lt;/span&gt;: (301) 443-6893; email: &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%63%6c%65%6f%6e%65@%6d%61%69%6c.%6e%69%68.%67%6f%76"&gt;cleone@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a&gt;.   The Institute has a strong commitment to the diversity of its workforce and a biomedical research environment that reflects the diversity of the American population (&lt;a href="http://eoe.od.nih.gov"&gt;http://eoe.od.nih.gov&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DHHS&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NIH&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ARE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EQUAL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OPPORTUNITY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EMPLOYERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%63%6c%65%6f%6e%65@%6d%61%69%6c.%6e%69%68.%67%6f%76"&gt;cleone@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2009 15:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4741</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4741</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Onion: Merchandising Manager - Ecommerce</title>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Chicago, IL
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; theonion.com
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Onion, America&#8217;s Finest News Source, is looking for an experience E-Commerce Merchandising Manager for our Chicago office. Candidates with a passion for e-commerce / retail and a creative mindset for increasing website traffic and growing business, coupled with an expansive knowledge of the market, is ideal if not required. Similarly, the most competitive candidates will display a strong understanding of The Onion&#8217;s unique brand and readership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The E-Commerce Merchandising Manager will collaborate with our creative staff to develop business strategies that drive online sales growth, enhance selection and user experience. This position will require the use of various analytical tools and customer profiling to grow sales, thus ensuring an exceptional customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall responsibility of the E-Commerce Merchandising Manager is to meet and exceed company budgets for sales and gross margin through new product merchandising and vendor relationships. In addition, this person will maintain ownership of the store&#8217;s website layout (e.g., content, navigation, design, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibilities&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Develop and own the annual business plan for online store.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Constantly work toward upgrading the merchandise assortment; drive financial results, maximizing sales&lt;br /&gt;
   and bottom line profitability.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Analyze store needs and demographics. Analyze actual sales results to plan and forecast sales and&lt;br /&gt;
     inventories on a regular basis.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Develop and grow partnerships with variety of vendors, including product, technology and marketing.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Develop and maintain effective working relationships with members the creative and finance teams.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Consistently evaluate the layout of the store online, working with the tech team to improve the financial&lt;br /&gt;
     performance of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qualifications&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Experience in online retail, including 3-5 years with a well established retailer and a strong&lt;br /&gt;
understanding of retail logistics.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Product development, product management, and marketing experience.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Previous budgetary responsibility and ability to connect marketing strategy and initiatives with profit&lt;br /&gt;
   and loss.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Track record of developing and driving product plans, increasing sales.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Ability to formally present business strategies and action plans to management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Qualifications&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	A Bachelor&#8217;s degree in Marketing, Business Management or related field. &lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Candidates must possess initiative, be a quick study, organized, punctual, detail oriented, and able to work independently and within a team environment.&lt;br /&gt;
&#8226;	Only those with strong Microsoft Suite experience (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), ideally on a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MAC&lt;/span&gt;, will be considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Onion is an Equal Opportunity Employer.  We offer compensation commensurate with experience, a  lucrative bonus plan, and a competitive benefits package that includes comprehensive medical, dental, group life insurance and matching 401K plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested applicants should forward a cover letter, resume and compensation requirements to &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%73%63%75%72%74%69%73@%74%68%65%6f%6e%69%6f%6e.%63%6f%6d"&gt;scurtis@theonion.com&lt;/a&gt;. Please, no phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;%73%63%75%72%74%69%73@%74%68%65%6f%6e%69%6f%6e.%63%6f%6d"&gt;scurtis@theonion.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 22:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4740</guid>
      <link>http://jobs.37signals.com/jobs/4740</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
