<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Regator Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.regator.com/blog</link>
	<description>News and Views from the Regator Team</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 23:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.7</generator>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
			<item>
		<title>Happy Holidays from Regator</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=325</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=325#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 22:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=325</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
All of us at Regator wish you and yours the very best this holiday season. 2008 has been a great year for us (we hope for you too!) and we&#8217;re looking forward to an even better 2009! So, whether you love the holidays because of the presents, religion, time off work, or all of the [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="alignnone" src="http://regator.com/blog/blogimages/regatorchristmas.gif" alt="" width="580" height="385" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">All of us at <a href="http://regator.com">Regator</a> wish you and yours the very best this holiday season. 2008 has been a great year for us (we hope for you too!) and we&#8217;re looking forward to an even better 2009! So, whether you love the holidays because of the presents, religion, time off work, or all of the above, have a great and safe time.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In the spirit of the holiday season, Team Regator is giving a donation on behalf of our users to <a href="http://www.aarfatlanta.org/">Atlanta Animal Rescue Friends</a>&#8230; because after all, this is the season for giving. If you would like to donate more to this very worthy Atlanta charity, you can do so with the widget below.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Cheers,</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Scott, Chris and Kimberly</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><object width="250" height="250" data="http://widget.chipin.com/widget/id/a7f2f4f8690099ed" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><param name="wmode" value="transparent" /><param name="event_title" value="Help%20Support%20AARF" /><param name="color_scheme" value="red" /><param name="src" value="http://widget.chipin.com/widget/id/a7f2f4f8690099ed" /><param name="flashvars" value="event_title=Help%20Support%20AARF&amp;color_scheme=red" /></object></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=325</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regator Behind the Blog: Hemant Mehta of the Friendly Atheist</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=312</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=312#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 14:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Behind the Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=312</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tis the season to celebrate religious holidays such as Christmas, Hanukkah, and Kwanzaa, and Team Regator wishes you a happy holiday season, no matter what your religion may (or may not) be. According to the last U.S. Census info, more than 16 percent of Americans identify themselves as "unaffiliated" religiously, a figure that includes those who answered "atheist, agnostic, and nothing in particular." That percentage is even higher in many other countries. So while the blogosphere is abuzz with traditional religious celebrations, we're giving the floor to the other side for a moment by talking to Hemant Mehta, author of I Sold My Soul on eBay, high school math teacher, and blogger behind Friendly Atheist. ]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://regator.com/blog/blogimages/friendlyatheist.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="124" /></p>
<p>Tis the season to celebrate religious holidays such as Christmas, Hanukkah, and Kwanzaa, and Team Regator wishes you a happy holiday season, no matter what your religion may (or may not) be. According to the last U.S. Census info, more than 16 percent of Americans identify themselves as &#8220;unaffiliated&#8221; religiously, a figure that includes those who answered &#8220;atheist, agnostic, and nothing in particular.&#8221; That percentage is even higher in many other countries. So while the blogosphere is abuzz with traditional religious celebrations, we&#8217;re giving the floor to the other side for a moment by talking to <strong>Hemant Mehta</strong>, author of <em><a title="I Sold My Soul on eBay" href="http://www.amazon.com/Sold-My-Soul-eBay-Atheists/dp/1400073472">I Sold My Soul on eBay</a></em>, high school math teacher, and blogger behind <a href="http://friendlyatheist.com/" target="_blank">Friendly Atheist</a>. The blog aims to bring together atheists and Christians in open and &#8220;friendly&#8221; discussion, so both can understand each other a little better, even if they don&#8217;t always agree&#8230; much&#8230; ever.</p>
<p><strong>Why did you start blogging?</strong><br />
In 2006, I placed an eBay auction in which I (an atheist) offered to go to church services.  It got some media attention and a former Christian pastor won my services.  I ended writing about my church-going experiences on his website and I loved the idea that my writing could start these interesting conversations.  After I finished my church obligations, I began my own website at friendlyatheist.com.</p>
<p><strong>How would you describe Friendly Atheist, and what makes it different from the other atheism and religious blogs?</strong><br />
It&#8217;s a place for atheists and Christians to discuss issues in/about the atheist community.  It offers a less militant tone than other atheist websites (so religious people won&#8217;t mind checking it out and participating in the discussions).  Also, I think the comments people make on any particular posting are worth reading as much as the posts themselves&#8211;you don&#8217;t see that type of civil conversation and humorous/insightful comments on many other sites about atheism.  I&#8217;m proud of the level of dialogue that takes place on my site.</p>
<p><strong><span style="font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;;">What’s your favorite post you have ever written? </span></strong><br />
My favorite personal post is one in which I talked about <a href="http://friendlyatheist.com/450/why-im-not-an-angry-atheist/">why I&#8217;m not an angry atheist</a>.  I&#8217;m also very proud of an <a href="http://friendlyatheist.com/1302/interview-with-mike-jones-the-man-who-exposed-ted-haggards-hypocrisy/">interview I did with Mike Jones</a> (Pastor Ted Haggard&#8217;s gay male escort)&#8211;it went on my site right as Jones&#8217; book came out.  I interviewed him one-on-one with a recorder and a list of questions; I felt &#8220;professional,&#8221; like my interview was better than anything you would have found in mainstream or alternative media.  I was also very proud of the end product.  Mike was open about discussing his life and he answered just about everything I could have expected.  It didn&#8217;t get the page views I hoped it would, but I know I&#8217;d like to do more interviews like that in the future.  It gives me something to shoot for every time.</p>
<p><strong>With Christmas upon us, do you think the masses see Christmas as a religious holiday or just a good time with presents?</strong><br />
Good time with presents.  For most people, I think it&#8217;s really a secular holiday that happens to coincide with a lot of religious holy days.  Only the Christian Right gets mad that not everyone celebrates it as Jesus&#8217; birthday.  I&#8217;m planning to have a wonderful week with family and friends.</p>
<p><strong>How do you balance blogging with your other job as a high school math teacher?</strong><br />
From 5:30 a.m. till 6:00 p.m., I&#8217;m thinking of work and my students and Speech Team (I help coach it).  When I get home, I do website work, write posts for the next day, and check my emails.  It&#8217;s intense, but I&#8217;m at a time in my life where I can make it happen.  Might as well make the most of it.</p>
<p><strong>What is the best new blog you have found recently?</strong><br />
This sounds like a cop-out, but my favorite blogs are the ones that are virtually unknown.  I love reading personal stories and reading about what&#8217;s going on in their lives.  Most of the sites I read are news-related and they&#8217;re nice (especially when they include commentary) but I make a special effort to read blogs that are personal, funny, real, and updated. My favorite example of that from the past year is <a href="http://lindseysrantings.com/">Lindsey&#8217;s Rantings</a>.  It&#8217;s hilarious.</p>
<p><strong>What advice would you give to someone who was just starting to blog?</strong><br />
It&#8217;s tempting to just link to cool things you find on other websites, but you have a better chance of being successful if you&#8217;re forming and writing about your own opinions.  Don&#8217;t be afraid of getting challenged. You don&#8217;t have to write every day.  As long as we know you&#8217;re alive, and you have an interesting take on news stories&#8211;or your life is full of crazy/relevent stories&#8211;you&#8217;ll find an audience.  Also, don&#8217;t get upset if you don&#8217;t find an audience immediately.  It takes some time to get used to a regular blogging schedule.  When you&#8217;ve got that worked out, then alert websites you like of your own site.  Introduce yourself!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=312</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regator Wins Bronze in 2008 Open Web Awards!</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=293</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=293#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2008 05:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Open Web Awards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=293</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanks to everyone who voted and supported Regator in our very successful 2008 Open Web Awards campaign. Very successful? Absolutely. Even though we came in third to the worthy first place Help a Reporter Out and second place Hubdub, the competition has been fantastic for the site and for us personally. Since it started roughly a month ago we've seen dramatic increases in website traffic and awareness of the site.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://regator.com/blog/blogimages/openwebawards.jpg" alt="" width="256" height="308" /></p>
<p>Thanks to everyone who voted and supported Regator in our very successful <a href="http://mashable.com/openwebawards/home/" target="_blank">2008 Open Web Awards</a> campaign. Very successful? Absolutely. Even though we came in third to the worthy first place <a href="http://helpareporter.com" target="_blank">Help a Reporter Out </a>and second place <a href="http://hubdub.com" target="_blank">Hubdub</a>, the competition has been fantastic for the site and for us personally.  Since it started roughly a month ago we&#8217;ve seen dramatic increases in website traffic and awareness of the site.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re thrilled that Regator managed to make it all the way to the final round despite being only four months old. I mean, what were YOU doing when you were that age? Probably sleeping and learning to consume solid foods. I guess it&#8217;s possible you were beating out leading sites like <a href="http://digg.com" target="_blank">Digg</a> and <a href="http://mixx.com" target="_blank">Mixx</a> to get to the finals in the Open Web Awards, but we&#8217;re pretty sure that&#8217;s just baby Regator.</p>
<p>How did we do it (besides by irritating the hell out of everyone we know with Twitter and Facebook campaign messages)? Even though we are a new and relatively small (but fast growing!) website, we had incredible support from the people who use Regator every day. Add to that hometown support from Atlanta and homeland support from Australia, and we managed to achieve the unexpected by making it to the finals. Considering that we were one of very few non-funded (bootstrapped) start-ups in the final round, and up against far more established and recognizable brands, we did unbelievably well. If anything, this shows that if you work hard, have a product that people like to use, get creative, and don&#8217;t give up, there&#8217;s nothing you can&#8217;t do (except maybe develop x-ray vision&#8230;that&#8217;s tough).</p>
<p>Again, thanks to all the people who helped us win bronze. There are too many to list here but you know who you are and we&#8217;re tremendously grateful to you for voting, putting our widget on your blogs, and spreading the word. Also a big thanks to the great folks at <a href="http://mashable.com" target="_blank">Mashable</a> and the hundreds of other <a href="http://mashable.com/openwebawards/partners/">blogs</a> and <a href="http://mashable.com/openwebawards/sponsors/">sponsors</a> that participated in the awards.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
<p>Scott, Chris and Kimberly</p>
<p>p.s. we&#8217;ll be back next year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=293</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thanks to Everyone&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=285</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=285#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 20:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=285</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chris, Kimberly and I would like to thank everyone who, for the past few weeks, voted incessantly for Regator in response to our incessant requests and prodding for votes in the 2008 Mashable Open Web Awards. We find out tomorrow (Tuesday, December 16) if we have won the Social News category or not. ]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://regator.com/blog/blogimages/thankyou.jpg" alt="" width="485" height="140" /></p>
<p>Chris, Kimberly and I would like to thank everyone who, for the past few weeks, voted incessantly in response to our incessant requests and prodding for votes in the <a href="http://mashable.com/openwebawards/home/" target="_blank">2008 Mashable Open Web Awards</a>. We find out tomorrow (Tuesday, December 16) if we have won the Social News category or not. It was a tight race (we think) between <a href="http://regator.com" target="_blank">Regator</a>, <a href="http://hubdub.com" target="_blank">Hubdub</a> and <a href="http://helpareporter.com" target="_blank">Help a Reporter Out</a>.</p>
<p>Whether we win or lose we are better for the Open Web Awards experience. In the unfortunate event we do not get the cup, we still have a lot to be happy about. Regator made it into the top 3 social media sites as voted by internet users. Which isn&#8217;t too shabby for a 4 month-old web startup based in an Atlanta home by a husband, his wife and brother-in-law team. We also have gained a ton of new awareness of the site, with our twitter follows going up threefold in the last couple of weeks and our site traffic making a dramatic increase. I&#8217;m not trying to sound defeatist, as I am not - I think we have a fairly good chance. My point is that regardless of what gets announced tomorrow&#8230; we&#8217;ve already won.</p>
<p>So big thanks to all of our voters and supporters and a special thank you goes to our supporters in our hometown of Atlanta and my homeland of Australia!</p>
<p>Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.</p>
<p>Scott, Chris and Kimberly</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://bit.ly/iRWY" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=285</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s Hot in America?</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=281</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=281#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 15:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chris</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During my morning browsing today I came across a computerworld.com article about comments posted on President-elect Obama Change.gov web site.  Through the change.gov website the Obama transition team has begun a discussion with the American people.  This week the discussion has focused on the economy and how the economic crisis has affected Americans.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During my morning browsing today I came across <a title="An ad hoc story of America emerges from online posts to Change.gov " href="http://www.computerworld.com/action/article.do?command=viewArticleBasic&amp;articleId=9123342">a computerworld.com article</a> about comments posted on President-elect Obama <a title="Change.gov" href="http://change.gov/newsroom/entry/join_the_discussion_obama_economic_team_responds/">Change.gov</a> web site.  Through the change.gov website the Obama transition team has begun a discussion with the American people.  This week the discussion has focused on the economy and how the economic crisis has affected Americans.  The computerworld.com article described the resulting comments as a &#8220;searchable, portable and singular narrative that is, in many respects, an ad hoc story of America at this moment.&#8221;  Due to popular demand, the 3500+ comments on change.gov were compiled into a <a title="Change.gov comments" href="http://change.gov/page/-/open%20government/ChangeDOTgov_economy_discussion.zip">downloadable text file</a> for interested parties to use for whatever purposes might come to mind.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been impressed so far with President-elect Obama&#8217;s use of the modern social web to listen to the thoughts of the American people.  I&#8217;m not quite sure what uses they had in mind when posting the compiled comments file, but I found myself wondering what sort of data might emerge if I did some analysis of the &#8220;singular narrative.&#8221;  Here at <a title="Regator.com" href="http://regator.com">regator.com</a> we have a feature we call the What&#8217;s Hot List.  It&#8217;s basically just text analysis of blog posts to determine what people are writing about right now.  It ends up being functionally sort of similar to a tag cloud, but as an ordered list and without the content being tagged.  I was curious what would happen if I fed the comment data from change.gov into our What&#8217;s Hot algorithm in place of the usual blog posts.  The dataset ended up being fairly similar in size to what we typically take into consideration.  The results were largely what you might expect considering the topic being discussed, but I think it&#8217;s still interesting to see what terms comes up most in a discussion on the economy.  Anyway, here&#8217;s what it came up with:</p>
<ol>
<li>our economy</li>
<li>government</li>
<li>jobs</li>
<li>economic crisis</li>
<li>health care</li>
<li>this country</li>
<li>president-elect obama</li>
<li>debt</li>
<li>banks</li>
<li>student loans</li>
<li>income</li>
<li>financial</li>
<li>health insurance</li>
<li>mortgage</li>
<li>cost</li>
<li>loan</li>
<li>can afford</li>
<li>bailout</li>
<li>energy</li>
<li>federal government</li>
<li>gas prices</li>
<li>education</li>
<li>dollars</li>
<li>hope</li>
<li>future</li>
<li>small business</li>
<li>paid</li>
<li>taxes</li>
<li>workers</li>
<li>our retirement</li>
<li>problems</li>
<li>college</li>
<li>americans</li>
<li>agree</li>
<li>paying</li>
<li>living</li>
<li>middle class</li>
<li>provide</li>
<li>homes</li>
<li>new administration</li>
<li>social security</li>
<li>spend</li>
<li>unemployment</li>
<li>spending</li>
<li>increase</li>
<li>funds</li>
<li>infrastructure</li>
<li>savings</li>
<li>stimulus package</li>
<li>congress</li>
</ol>
<p>Multiple words show up together if they occur in pairs over a certain threshold, but for the most part it&#8217;s a fairly simple algorithm.  Looking at the list I think it sums up the concerned language people are using right now.  Though &#8220;hope&#8221; does squeeze in there at #24.  I was kind of surprised how high &#8220;student loans&#8221; showed up, though that may just be indicative of the demographic of internet commenters.  Anyway, I just thought I&#8217;d share that little experiment.  Do tell me what you think either in comments, or drop me a line on twitter @chris_regator</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=281</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regator Top 10 Posts of the Week</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=278</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=278#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 02:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Top 10]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wow! What an incredible week! The Regators have been hard at work building some sweet new things into the site and having fun reading some of the most interesting and entertaining blog posts on the internet. We have also been busy campaigning for the Mashable 2008 Open Web Awards and only have 2 more days of voting until the polls close. We are in the Social News Category and we'd absolutely be thrilled if you would vote for us. Your vote does count! We find out the results of the competition on Tuesday, December 16th.  Exciting! Here are the top 10 most popular posts on Regator this week, one completely dominated by posts about a football player letting it all hang out on national television. Enjoy!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.regator.com/blog/blogimages/top10dec12.jpg" alt="" width="503" height="290" /></p>
<p>Wow! What an incredible week! The Regators have been hard at work building some sweet new things into the site and having fun reading some of the most interesting and entertaining blog posts on the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EtOoQFa5ug8" target="_blank">internet</a>. We have also been busy campaigning for the <a href="http://mashable.com/2008/12/12/final-reminder-open-web-awards-voting-closes-sunday/" target="_blank">Mashable 2008 Open Web Awards</a> and only have 2 more days of <a href="http://bit.ly/YcN6" target="_blank">voting</a> until the polls close. We are in the Social News Category and we&#8217;d absolutely be thrilled if you would vote for us. Your vote does count! We find out the results of the competition on Tuesday, December 16th.  Exciting!</p>
<p>Here are the top 10 most popular posts on <a href="http://regator.com" target="_blank">Regator</a> this week, one completely dominated by posts about a football player letting it all hang out on national television. Enjoy!</p>
<blockquote>
<ol>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.inquisitr.com/11117/visanthe-shiancoe-vikings-locker-room/" target="_blank">Visanthe Shiancoe’s Vikings Locker Room Exposure</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:2690" target="_blank">The Inquisitr</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.sportsbybrooks.com/total-exposure-viking-pantless-in-locker-room-21270" target="_blank">Total Exposure: Viking Pantless In Locker Room</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:3305" target="_blank">SportsByBrooks</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://deadspin.com/5104161/nude-high-school-cheerleaders-now-less-nude-sue-school" target="_blank">Nude High School Cheerleaders Now Less Nude, Sue School</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:1296" target="_blank">Deadspin</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://friendlyatheist.com/6596/seattle-atheists-condemn-atheist-plaque-in-washington/" target="_blank">Seattle Atheists Condemn Atheist Plaque in Washington</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:456" target="_blank">Friendly Atheist</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://pysih.com/2008/12/07/the-dnepropetrovsk-maniacs/" target="_blank">The Dnepropetrovsk Maniacs</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:3860" target="_blank">People You&#8217;ll See In Hell</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.geekologie.com/2008/12/oops_girl_loses_virginity_text.php" target="_blank">Oops!: Girl Loses Virginity, Texts Her Dad</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:3865" target="_blank">Geekologie</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://walkinthewords.blogspot.com/2008/12/mcdonalds-coffee-billboard-semantic.html" target="_blank">McDonald&#8217;s Coffee Billboard - A Semantic Analysis</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:4058" target="_blank">A Walk in the Words</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.cracked.com/article_16849_7-dumbest-things-ever-done-by-airport-security.html" target="_blank">The 7 Dumbest Things Ever Done by Airport Security</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:2510" target="_blank">Cracked.com</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.thespoof.com/news/spoof.cfm?headline=s2i44933" target="_blank">Illini Gov Blagojevich Charged with Importing and Wearing Endangered Monkey Wigs</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:3020" target="_blank">The Spoof</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://feeds.gothamistllc.com/click.phdo?i=4f94cf82b38311a6b9fa9076b0e8bd24" target="_blank">Takes Two to Tango: A Look at Gov&#8217;s Chief of Staff</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:1766" target="_blank">Chicagoist</a></li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=278</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Open Web Awards Voting Ends Sunday - Vote For Regator!</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=265</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=265#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 04:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
We are in the final few days of voting in Mashable&#8217;s 2008 Open Web Awards. Voting ends midnight Sunday, December 14. Please help us out and vote for Regator once, twice, or as many times as you can between now and Sunday! We&#8217;d really appreciate it.
We have been working hard on improving the site and [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="http://www.regator.com/blog/blogimages/votedaily1.jpg"></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">We are in the final few days of voting in <a href="http://mashable.com/openwebawards/home/" target="_blank">Mashable&#8217;s 2008 Open Web Awards</a>. Voting ends midnight Sunday, December 14. Please help us out and vote for <a href="http://regator.com" target="_blank">Regator</a> once, twice, or as many times as you can between now and Sunday! We&#8217;d really appreciate it.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">We have been working hard on improving the site and responding to feedback from our users. We are really excited about the fantastic growth we are experiencing and especially making it into the top 3 Social News sites in this prestigious competition. </p>
<p>We&#8217;re working against the odds that says a 3 person startup working out of a house in Atlanta, Georgia can&#8217;t play with the big guys. Winning this award would go a long way to proving that we indeed can. So please take a moment to vote for us each day. You can vote once every 24 hours! We made it to the top 3 from votes like yours - your vote counts! </p>
<p>Thanks so much! We really appreciate your help!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">
<p><center><br />
<img src="http://regator.com/owa/VOTEDAILY.jpg" alt="" /><br />
<iframe width="200" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" frameborder="0" height="390" src="http://mashable.polldaddy.com/widget/x2.aspx?f=f&#038;c=4&#038;cn=53"></iframe> <noscript><a href="http://mashable.com/2008/12/03/openwebawards2-final-voting-round/">Mashable Open Web Awards</a></noscript></p>
<p>Check out our<br />
<a href="http://regator.com/owa/openwebawards.htm">Open Web Awards iPhone Widget</a><br />
</center></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=265</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regator Top 10 Posts of the Week</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=259</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=259#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 20:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[
It&#8217;s been a big week for the Regators! We made it into the finals of the 2008 Open Web Awards (You can vote for us every day until December 14th!). We also have been increasing our traffic on the site fairly dramatically over the past few weeks, so we are just elated in general. One [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.regator.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/weeklytop10edc5.gif"><img class="size-medium wp-image-261 aligncenter" title="weeklytop10edc5" src="http://www.regator.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/weeklytop10edc5-300x201.gif" alt="" width="300" height="201" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a big week for the Regators! We made it into the finals of the <a href="http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=250" target="_blank">2008 Open Web Awards</a> (You can vote for us every day until December 14th!). We also have been increasing our traffic on the site fairly dramatically over the past few weeks, so we are just elated in general. One thing we haven&#8217;t been doing all that well on lately is the Top 10 Posts of the Week . With everything going on, they had kind of fallen to wayside. But no more! We will be doing a Top 10 post each Friday afternoon from now on. Promise.</p>
<p>The Top 10 posts each week provide a really good snapshot of what was being talked about in blogs that week. So thanks for checking out Regator&#8217;s weekly top 10 and please take a second to vote for us!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
<blockquote>
<ol>
<li><strong><a href="http://gatewaypundit.blogspot.com/2008/11/mumbai-terrorists-had-dinner-drinks.html" target="_blank">Mumbai Terrorists Had Dinner, Drinks, Paid Their Bill&#8230; Then Shot the Place Up</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:224" target="_blank">Gateway Pundit</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.aheadoftheticker.com/2008/12/squawk-box-on-friday-where-did-matrix.html" target="_blank">Squawk Box: On Friday, where did Matrix Asset Management&#8217;s Dick Otto say oil would go?</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:142" target="_blank">Ahead of the Ticker</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://shine.yahoo.com/channel/health/first-info-on-new-weight-watchers-plan-momentum-323029/" target="_blank">First Info on New Weight Watchers Plan: Momentum!</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:3957" target="_blank">Shine Health</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://patterico.com/2008/12/04/barack-obama-birth-certificate-controversy-heads-to-supreme-court1111/" target="_blank">Barack Obama Birth Certificate Controversy Heads to Supreme Court! </a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:227" target="_blank">Paternico&#8217;s Pontifications</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.nationalledger.com/artman/publish/article_272624056.shtml?ref=rss" target="_blank">Captive Teen Case (Photos, Video) New Arrests, Details, Emaciated Boy</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:233" target="_blank">The National Ledger</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://vivirlatino.com/2008/11/28/black-friday-causes-death-and-a-miscarriage-at-a-long-island-walmart.php" target="_blank">Black Friday Causes Death and a Miscarriage at a Long Island Wal-Mart</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:3347" target="_blank">VivirLatino</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://pajamasmedia.com/instapundit/28710/" target="_blank">MUMBAI: Doctors shocked at hostages’ torture</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:238" target="_blank">Instapundit</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://feeds.gothamistllc.com/click.phdo?i=350e229cd4a9e7dc1957254104317b49" target="_blank">Elaborate Bank Robbery Stopped by Cops</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:675" target="_blank">Gothamist</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2008/11/30/palin-slammed-by-hometown_n_147214.html" target="_blank">Palin Slammed By Hometown Paper For Georgia Campaigning</a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:29" target="_blank">Huffington Post</a></li>
<li><strong><a href="http://friendlyatheist.com/6478/bill-oreilly-cant-deal-with-atheist-sign-in-washington/" target="_blank">Bill O’Reilly Can’t Deal with Atheist Sign in Washington </a></strong><br />
<a href="http://www.regator.com/#blogprofile:456" target="_blank">Friendly Athiest</a></li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=259</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regator Makes the Open Web Awards Top 3!</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=250</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=250#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 19:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Open Web Awards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is huge. Regator has made it into the Top 3 in the Social News Category beating out sites like Digg, Mixx and Socialmedian. We couldn't be happier! A big thanks to all of our users who voted for us, we really appreciate it. So, we are in the Final 3 and need your vote yet again. Please vote for us and tell your friends (and enemies) about the site. You can do it here on the blog, or on regator.com in the sidebar.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.regator.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/openwebawards_top3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-251 aligncenter" title="openwebawards_top3" src="http://www.regator.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/12/openwebawards_top3.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="337" /></a></p>
<p><strong>UPDATE: Voting has ended.</strong><strong> Thanks so much to everyone who took the time to vote for us. If we win, you win! Cheers!</strong></p>
<p>This is huge. Regator has made it into the Top 3 of <a href="http://mashable.com" target="_blank">Mashable</a>&#8217;s <a href="http://mashable.com/openwebawards/home/" target="_blank">Open Web Awards</a> in the Social News category beating out sites like Digg, Mixx and Socialmedian. We couldn&#8217;t be happier! A big thanks to all of our users who voted for us, we really appreciate it.</p>
<p>So, we are in the final round of voting and need your vote yet again. Please vote for us and tell your friends (and enemies) about the site. You can do it here on the <a href="http://regator.com/blog">regator blog</a> or on <a href="http://regator.com">regator.com</a> in the sidebar.</p>
<p>If you want to be extra special, you can embed the voting widget on your blog or MySpace page! Here&#8217;s the code:<br />
&lt;iframe width=&#8221;210&#8243; marginheight=&#8221;0&#8243; marginwidth=&#8221;0&#8243; frameborder=&#8221;0&#8243; height=&#8221;390&#8243; src=&#8221;http://mashable.polldaddy.com/widget/x2.aspx?f=f&amp;c=4&amp;cn=53&#8243;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;noscript&gt;&lt;a href=&#8221;http://mashable.com/2008/12/03/openwebawards2-final-voting-round/&#8221;&gt;Mashable Open Web Awards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=250</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regator made it into the voting round for Mashable&#8217;s Open Web Awards!</title>
		<link>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=244</link>
		<comments>http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=244#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 21:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kimberly</dc:creator>
		
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Open Web Awards]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[voting]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[woohoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.regator.com/blog/?p=244</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hurrah!! Thanks to everyone who nominated Regator earlier this month, we've made it past the primaries and are now a real, honest-to-goodness candidate for Best Social News site in Mashable's Open Web Awards. This is absolutely awesome news for our young site. ]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurrah!! Thanks to everyone who nominated <a title="Regator" href="http://regator.com" target="_blank">Regator</a> earlier this month, we&#8217;ve made it past the primaries and are now a real, honest-to-goodness candidate for Best Social News site in <a title="Mashable" href="http://mashable.com/2008/11/19/openwebawards-voting-1/" target="_blank">Mashable&#8217;s Open Web Awards</a>. This is absolutely awesome news for our young site.</p>
<p>Please vote for us and vote OFTEN (you&#8217;re allowed one vote every 24 hours) using the fancy blue widget on the right.</p>
<p>From here on out, it gets very David-and-Goliath. You see, our three-month-old startup is in the top ten with sites like Digg and Socialmedian. Yes, Digg. So we really need your help. We&#8217;re not only asking for your daily vote, we&#8217;re also asking (okay, begging) for you to share this great news with everyone you know who might enjoy Regator.</p>
<div id="attachment_245" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 208px"><a href="http://www.regator.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/david-goliath.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-245" title="David Goliath sumo" src="http://www.regator.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/david-goliath-198x300.jpg" alt="Regator vs. Digg. Stranger things have happened." width="198" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Regator vs. Digg. Stranger things have happened.</p></div>
<p>Do we honestly think a newbie like us is gonna take down a Goliath like Digg? Let&#8217;s just say we&#8217;re rooting for the underdog. And we hope you will too. Thanks for taking us this far.</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p>Team Regator</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.regator.com/blog/?feed=rss2&amp;p=244</wfw:commentRss>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
