<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Smarticus - Home</title>
  <id>tag:smartic.us,2009:mephisto/</id>
  <generator uri="http://mephistoblog.com" version="0.8.0">Mephisto Drax</generator>
  <link href="http://smartic.us/feed/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="http://smartic.us/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  <updated>2009-01-12T20:00:08Z</updated>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2009-01-12:33315</id>
    <published>2009-01-12T19:54:00Z</published>
    <updated>2009-01-12T20:00:08Z</updated>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2009/1/12/emacs-three-weeks-in" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Emacs three weeks in</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve been conducting an experiment over the last few weeks.  I decided
to put my money where my mouth was and try out a different editor for
a little while.  I plan on trying a few editors out, and Emacs was my first stop..  Emacs has a crazy learning curve.
The good thing is once you figure out the basics and learn a couple of
important keystrokes, you&#8217;ll be able to get along quiet nicely.  My fingers don&#8217;t mind any of M or C now.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The main reason I wanted to try something different than Textmate is
because I was missing split windows.  Split windows make me feel so
productive.  Emacs has a pretty good implementation, and I found myself
with a code window, a terminal, and an irc session up pretty much at
all times.  For this Emacs definitely was a &lt;em&gt;win&lt;/em&gt;, and after this, I
don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ll ever be able to go back to an editor which doesn&#8217;t
have split windows&#8230;  Nope. I&#8217;m not going to use an editor that doesn&#8217;t allow me to split my windows.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve also enjoyed &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ERC&lt;/span&gt;.  &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ERC&lt;/span&gt; is awesome now that I have everything
configured correctly.  Actually most things are great now that I have
them configured correctly.  I started out with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/technomancy/emacs-starter-kit/tree/master&quot;&gt;Emacs starter kit&lt;/a&gt;, and it gave me a great base to get started.  #emacs on freenode has also been a huge help.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So now everything is good.  Well almost everything.  There are some downsides to Emacs as well.
The first problem I&#8217;ve created for myself is wanting to run
everything from Emacs itself.  Emacs gives you plenty of rope, and I
took all that I could.  (Good thing I didn&#8217;t hang myself)  The few
times Emacs crashed, it took down my entire environment.  I didn&#8217;t
lose any files; Emacs has great autosaving.  I did lose my
concentration, because it was such a pain in the rear to get everything
just like it was before.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m a web developer.  Most of my activities revolve around html and
writing code to generate html.  Emacs presents more than a few tools
to get my job done.  Some of the tools are better than others.  I&#8217;ve
had good luck with the ruby modes.  I&#8217;ve had less than stellar luck
with nxhtml: It works well enough, but way to slow for me to
incorporate it in my normal workflow.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, what do I do now?  I&#8217;m going to continue on with my experiment.
I&#8217;m moving to vim over the next week, and I&#8217;ll spend a few weeks
emersed in that environment.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I&#8217;ve learned a few things, and you can check out my
&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/bryanl/emacs-config/tree/master&quot;&gt;emacs configs&lt;/a&gt; on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I recommend everyone gives Emacs a try at least once.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2009-01-07:33208</id>
    <published>2009-01-07T15:52:00Z</published>
    <updated>2009-01-07T15:58:12Z</updated>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2009/1/7/i-m-addicted-to-google-reader" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>I'm addicted to Google Reader</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Bryan, and I have a problem.  I&#8217;m addicted to Google Reader.  Every morning when I wake up I have to look at it.  During work breaks I look at it.  When I get home from work I look at it.  And most nights I look at it right before going to bed.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem here is that I&#8217;m addicted to information.  No just any type of information&#8212;I&#8217;m addicted to &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;/strong&gt; information.  I need it all the time.  I&#8217;m a cable news junkie as well.  I prefer Fox News due because their views are so different than mine.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m not sure how to approach my problem.   I see some value in reading my feeds; they provide me lots of new information I wouldn&#8217;t normally come across on a daily basis.  I tried a cold turkey approach, and it hasn&#8217;t been working too well.  I&#8217;m very hesitant to unsubscribing to anything.  I just don&#8217;t want to miss out.  My next course of action will be to separate my &lt;em&gt;professional&lt;/em&gt; feeds from the chit chatty ones.   I&#8217;ll keep them in two different accounts.  I&#8217;m not sure that will work, but I need to do something.  I&#8217;m going crazy over here.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2009-01-02:33147</id>
    <published>2009-01-02T20:06:00Z</published>
    <updated>2009-01-02T20:07:29Z</updated>
    <category term="humor"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2009/1/2/alternative-bailout-plan" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Alternative Bailout Plan</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Even if you have been barely paid attention over the last few weeks,
you will have noticed that we are in a period of bailout frenzy.  From
banks to car maker&#8217;s folks are standing in line to get their money.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m proposing we do something different.  In the past these banks and
car makers have failed.  Now we&#8217;ve given them money and most likely
they&#8217;ll fail again.  Since we aren&#8217;t guaranteeing success, we should
give the money to other groups of people.  So here is my top 5 list
of groups of people who should be receiving bailouts.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;1.  Alternative engergy vehicle companies.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Sure the batteries have crappy output, and all the cars are very
expensive.  That isn&#8217;t the point.  The point is that these companies
are doing something different.  And when they fail, hopefully it&#8217;ll be
because their ideas weren&#8217;t sound, rather than failing due to
greed and over indulgence.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;2.  Silicon Valley Startups&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Do we need another social network?  Of course we don&#8217;t.  But aren&#8217;t we
all entertained to hear about how easy it is to share the smells of
our farts with other like minded folks?  I&#8217;m sure tagging and photo
sharing are on the verge of something great.  If only someone would
chip in another billion or two.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;3.  Reality TV production companies&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m sorry, but the current breed of reality shows kind of
sucks. Imagine what gems could be produced with billion dollar
budgets?  Forgot home makeover show.  I&#8217;m talking about neighborhood
makeover shows and even more crazy stunts on shows like Wipeout.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;4.  Stem cell research companies&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m sure something good can come out of stem cell research.  I&#8217;m not
sure sure what that might be, but deep down somewhere inside of me,
something is telling me that stem cell research is good.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;5.  Me&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I have all sorts of ideas for a bailout check from the government.
I&#8217;ll setup a chain of pay day loan companies.  What better way to
stimulate the environment by providing people access to money &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-31:33092</id>
    <published>2008-12-31T13:10:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-31T13:12:01Z</updated>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/31/since-no-one-really-reads-blog-posts-on-new-years-eve" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Since no one really reads blog posts on New Years Eve</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Today marks the close of another great year. This has been a really
good one for me.  A new job (which I still like) and a new kid (which
I really like).  I&#8217;ve learned so much about so many things things
year.  My wife and I also celebrated another great year together.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So now at the last day, I&#8217;m inclined to think what is in store for
2009.  A couple of big things are on tap for the upcoming year.  First
and foremost, 2009 will be the year of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TATFT&lt;/span&gt;.  I have three projects in
the planning phase, and I&#8217;m going to be really excited to see these
come together.  Rails 3 is also high on my &#8220;excited to see how it will
turn out&#8221; list.  I also want to spend more time trying to figure out
where my professional life is headed.  I have some good indications,
so I&#8217;ll make sure to make sure I&#8217;m headed in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;As for improving myself, I&#8217;m gonna set out to learn Lua and how to
touch type on Dvorak.  I&#8217;m not going to buy anything in the store that
I can buy for cheaper online.  I&#8217;m not going to read more or reflect
more or give up more time to charity.   I also hope to engage even
more discussion about topics relevant to me.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, have you reflected on what 2009 has in store for you?  Was this
year a good year for you?&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-30:33070</id>
    <published>2008-12-30T17:33:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-30T18:02:04Z</updated>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/30/tmotb-test-more-often-than-bryanl" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>TMOTB - Test more often than BryanL</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;For quite some time, I&#8217;ve been asking you 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://whendoitest.com&quot;&gt;how often you test your codes&lt;/a&gt;, and I&#8217;ve also been encouraging you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://smartic.us/2008/8/15/tatft-i-feel-a-revolution-coming-on&quot;&gt;test all the fucking time&lt;/a&gt;.  Now
I&#8217;m curious about something.  How often you do you test?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&quot;http://twictur.es/i/1086192425.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;image provided by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twictur.es&quot;&gt;twictur.es&lt;/a&gt; | original tweet &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ezmobius/statuses/1086192425&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Do you test more often than I do?  I&#8217;ll share with you how often I
test, and I&#8217;ll let you tell me if I&#8217;m doing too much or not enough.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I test rake tasks&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I test my Rails initializers if I can&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I write tests for test code.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I truly spend more time writing tests than I do writing implementation code.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I used to test my associations, but I&#8217;ve stopped due to learning that you should test for expected behavior and not how it is implemented.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I test file uploads.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I test file downloads.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I test stuff that happens on the filesystem (my method sucks, but it does work)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I write additional tests for projects when I don&#8217;t quite understand how they work&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve developed a style for writing tests to demo code&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I have some test code for creating acceptance tests from &lt;a href=&quot;www.pivotaltracker.com/&quot;&gt;Pivotal Tracker&lt;/a&gt;  stories.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, what have you?  How often do you test?&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-26:32958</id>
    <published>2008-12-26T02:14:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-26T13:12:24Z</updated>
    <category term="leopard"/>
    <category term="ruby"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/26/so-if-you-are-using-a-mac-wanna-know-why-you-are-using-the-wrong-ruby" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>So, if you are using a mac, wanna know why you are using the wrong ruby?</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 12/26/2008&lt;/strong&gt;: It appears that Apple has patched their ruby.  I&#8217;m not sure which vulns have been addressed, but they have worked on it.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve heard it too many times recently:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt; I use Leopard ruby because macports is broken&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt; Leopard ruby is good enough&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt; macports only installs ruby 1.8.7&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt; blah blah blah&#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately you are wrong, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vimeo.com/2632609&quot;&gt;I&#8217;m gonna show you why&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vimeo.com/2632609&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://smartic.us/assets/2008/12/26/vlog_20081225.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-25:32931</id>
    <published>2008-12-25T00:35:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-25T00:44:37Z</updated>
    <category term="rubyonrails"/>
    <category term="vlog"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/25/what-i-think-about-rails-3-merb" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>What I think about Rails &lt;3 Merb</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve slept on it, and thought about it some more.  After 24 hours, here is what I think:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vimeo.com/2624854&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://smartic.us/assets/2008/12/25/vlog_20081224.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vimeo.com/2624854&quot;&gt;vimeo&lt;/a&gt; to see my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-24:32900</id>
    <published>2008-12-24T00:46:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-24T00:49:45Z</updated>
    <category term="vlog"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/24/whats-happenin-with-bryanl" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Whats happenin' with BryanL</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;I wanted to do a podcast for a while.  But I really don&#8217;t have any time.  So I decided to do a video thing instead.  We&#8217;ll just call it a social experiment.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Today, I talk about &lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.rubyonrails.org/2008/12/23/merb-gets-merged-into-rails-3&quot;&gt;Rails &amp;lt;3&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.harlanhogan.com/&quot;&gt;Harlan Hogan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/2616497&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://smartic.us/assets/2008/12/24/vlog2008122301.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-23:32871</id>
    <published>2008-12-23T02:38:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-23T02:40:16Z</updated>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/23/my-portable-sound-booth" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>My portable sound booth</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I was recording some audio for some screencasts, and I noticed a hiss caused by my Macbooks.  Moving the mic further from my work area isn&#8217;t really possible, so I set out to find a solution to the hissing noise.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;A quick search on Google led me to an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.harlanhogan.com/portaboothArticle.shtml&quot;&gt;contraption&lt;/a&gt; build by Harlan Hogan.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://smartic.us/assets/2008/12/23/portaboothFullFront.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;After reading the description, I decided that is was potentially what I was looking for.  I went to order page, and I was greeted with a huge shock:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://smartic.us/assets/2008/12/23/portabooth.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This thing was &lt;strong&gt;$129&lt;/strong&gt;.  That seemed a bit crazy, so I set out to build my own box.  The first thing I did was made a trip to Ikea.  They always have everything I&#8217;m looking for, and they didn&#8217;t fail me this time ($4.00).  Next I went to the local music store looking for some sound proofing foam.  They had some in stock at $25 a sheet.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It actually only took me about 15 minutes to assmeble my box.  For $29, I built something that would have cost me $100 more.  And I have the satisfaction of building it myself.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://lh4.ggpht.com/_Ri_cptRkGek/SVBOMK4vXvI/AAAAAAAAAHc/ISFwc1FHKp0/s720/DSCF3819.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Now I&#8217;m off to record some hiss free voiceovers.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;There are more pictures &lt;a href=&quot;http://picasaweb.google.com/bryanliles/MySoundBox&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;#&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-21:32785</id>
    <published>2008-12-21T22:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-22T16:28:26Z</updated>
    <category term="textmate"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/21/i-m-not-moving-from-textmate-to-emacs-or-vim" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>I'm not moving from Textmate to Emacs or Vim</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;Well at least not this week anyways.  I wish someone could give me a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; reason to move.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve really been working hard trying to figure why anyone would want to move from &lt;a href=&quot;http://macromates.com&quot;&gt;Textmate&lt;/a&gt; back to 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vim.org/&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; (or anything else for that matter, but those two are the ones I hear about the most).  Textmate is one of those things I really enjoyed when I made Mac &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OS X&lt;/span&gt; my full time development environment back in early 2006.  As an editor, it was easy to use and extend, and it was fairly &lt;em&gt;pretty&lt;/em&gt; to boot.  Plus, back in the &lt;em&gt;early&lt;/em&gt; days, updates were coming out like crazy, and it seemed inevitable that Textmate would morph into the greatest editor ever.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Now we fast forward to late 2008, and I&#8217;m still using Textmate.  I have my issues with it, but it is still that great configurable editor I found back in 2006.  I guess that is the gift and the curse.  It&#8217;s pretty much the same editor I was using back in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I thought I would I try to understand why people wanted to move.  I have some sneaking suspicions, but are those nuances really annoying enough for me to move back to Vim or Emacs?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s start with my number one problem with Textmate:  no split windows!  This bugs the hell out of me.  At least five times a day, I can think of some task that would have been way easier to accomplish if I had the ability to do split screen and work on the same file in multiple locations, or even edit two files side by side or top to bottom.  I&#8217;ll admit, the search for split windows has made me want to move on multiple occasions.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;What other problems do I have with Textmate?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The project search is terrible.  The good thing is that this is easily fixed by installing the &#8220;Ack In Project&#8221; plugin or one of the others which make searching much quicker.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Textmate chokes on large files.  I&#8217;ve trained myself to not click on files I know to be large.  This is a nuance, but nothing to make me rant and rave.  Textmate also chokes on large projects.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Extending Textmate isn&#8217;t very obvious.  At least at first it isn&#8217;t.  The work that is happening on the dialog plugin is interesting at least, and a taste of what is to come might be demonstrated in the &#8220;GetBundles&#8221; plugin.  The problem is you can&#8217;t extend it down to level of adding split windows or anything like that.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, why haven&#8217;t I moved yet?  The answer is simple.  Both Vim and Emacs offer great solutions to some of the individual problems I have, but neither offer a total solution (that is easy to cobble together at least), and neither of them look as good as Textmate out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The previous answer was just too easy.  I can really give you some concrete examples of what is wrong with Emacs and Vim as well.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s start with Emacs:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Emacs is complex.  Extremely complex.  And to configure it correctly, you have to learn Lisp.  Lisp is interesting in its own right, but I want to be able to configure my editor in the language of my choosing, and one of the nice things about Textmate is that it allows me to do that.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Emacs looks like dog poop out of the box. (on the Mac at least)  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://aquamacs.org/&quot;&gt;AquaMacs&lt;/a&gt; project has taken some steps in fixing these problems, but it isn&#8217;t there.  I actually prefer &lt;a href=&quot;http://homepage.mac.com/zenitani/emacs-e.html&quot;&gt;Carbon Emacs&lt;/a&gt;, and it looks like total crap on the Mac.  Some concessions must be made due to the fact that Emacs wasn&#8217;t written for the Mac, and it works on a myriad of platforms the same way.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;There are some people out there trying to ease the transition into Emacs a bit.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/technomancy&quot;&gt;Phil Hagelberg&lt;/a&gt; is doing some cool stuff with his &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/technomancy/emacs-starter-kit/tree/master&quot;&gt;emacs starter kit&lt;/a&gt;, and if the rumors are true, I believe he is working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://peepcode.com&quot;&gt;Peepcode&lt;/a&gt; as well.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/defunkt&quot;&gt;Chris Wanstrath&lt;/a&gt; has released  &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/defunkt/textmate.el/tree&quot;&gt;Textmate.el&lt;/a&gt;.  At first these projects seem real cool (and they are.  i&#8217;m definitely glad these guys are there releasing these extremely cool codes for &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt;), but in my mind it seems like the mob&#8217;s mindset is to move away from Textmate while keeping Textmate&#8217;s features.  Pragmatic Bryan just figures that he would stick with Textmate, and have less to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Emacs has really weird key combinations.  To tell you the truth, after a while, you get used to them.  But just starting out, you&#8217;ll wonder if you are just setting yourself up for early case of carpal tunnel.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Now on to Vim:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Vim is great.  I actually use it every day.  But not every often to do heavy coding.  My problem with Vim is that it feels like a 1000 piece jigsaw puzzle.  Sure, you can put the middle together and see the picture, but it isn&#8217;t complete, and will take you a long time to make it complete.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;As with Textmate, Vim requires you to learn a language to configure it.  I&#8217;m not down with that.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Vim is cryptic.  Cryptic is cool when you have awesome finger memory.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I&#8217;m sure I have more, but this rant is about something positive.  I&#8217;m not bashing Emacs and Vim.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Now on to a lesson I would like to share with everyone.  It is something I learned a long time ago.  I&#8217;m sure I read it somewhere like the Pragmatic Programmer or something, but I&#8217;m not sure:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The evolution of a person from neophyte to mastery of development of some programming technology isn&#8217;t just dependent on how well you know the language.  Or even in many cases how you apply the language.  The great developers (at least the ones I&#8217;ve met) are truly one with their editor (or &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IDE&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Your editor is just an extension of you.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;You have to master an editor.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It has to become second nature to you.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://whendoitest.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TATFT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-12-17:32597</id>
    <published>2008-12-17T20:57:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-12-17T21:03:47Z</updated>
    <category term="tatft"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/12/17/tatft-live-and-in-person-at-actsasconference" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>TATFT Live and In Person at ActsAsConference</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ll be speaking about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actsasconference.com/speakers/bryan-liles&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TATFT&lt;/span&gt; in real life&lt;/a&gt; at ActsAsConference down in Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.actsasconference.com&quot; title=&quot;Rails For All presents acts_as_conference&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.actsasconference.com/images/badge_xl.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Come see me and other smart Ruby geeks speak.  This was a fun conference last year, and I&#8217;m excited to be apart of it this year.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-11-25:31507</id>
    <published>2008-11-25T17:58:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-25T18:01:52Z</updated>
    <category term="selenium"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/11/25/running-selenium-1-0-beta-1-with-firefox-3-under-mac-os-x" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Running Selenium 1.0-beta-1 with Firefox 3 under Mac OS X</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;This morning, I set out to get &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seleniumhq.org/&quot;&gt;selenium&lt;/a&gt; working on my Mac.  It didn&#8217;t work right out of the box, so here is what I did to get it working&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Selenium won&#8217;t work with firefox 3 without some configuration.  It is actually hardcoded to firefox 2.  So I&#8217;ve updated the configuration to work with firefox 3.0.x, and created a new &lt;a href=&quot;http://smartic.us/assets/2008/11/25/selenium-server.jar&quot;&gt;jar&lt;/a&gt; to assist anyone who is going down this path.  If you are working with ruby and have the Selenium gem installed, you can replace $GEMHOME/gems/Selenium-1.1.14/lib/selenium/openqa/selenium-server.jar.txt with this jar.  After that, everything should run great for you.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that you&#8217;ll have to make some changes to the path if you are running a newer version of the Selenium gem.  Let me know if you run into anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-11-24:31430</id>
    <published>2008-11-24T16:47:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-24T21:43:04Z</updated>
    <category term="cucumber"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/11/24/cucubmer-and-test-unit" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>Cucumber and Test::Unit</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;The new hotness coming out of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rspec.info&quot;&gt;RSpec&lt;/a&gt; camp is &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/aslakhellesoy/cucumber/tree/master&quot;&gt;Cucumber&lt;/a&gt;.  In their own words, &#8220;Cucumber executes plain text documentation of code against that code.&#8221;  In normal people speak, Cucumber provides an extremely easy way to write acceptance style tests for your applications.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;To get started, I installed Cucumber per their directions.  I&#8217;m using this with a Rails project, and the steps from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/aslakhellesoy/cucumber/wikis/ruby-on-rails&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; put me on the right track.  (I did already have RSpec installed, but we won&#8217;t be using that here) I&#8217;m using this with a Rails 2.2, project, so I&#8217;ve added the following to my environment.rb:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;config.gem &quot;cucumber&quot;, :version =&amp;gt; &quot;0.1.9&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Next, I bootstrapped Cucumber, and started working on my &lt;em&gt;features&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Seeing as how I don&#8217;t do much Rspec these days, I wanted to see if it would be possible to use Cucumber with Test::Unit.  Fortunately for us, this is a very easy task, and I&#8217;ll share my notes with you.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;1. Make sure the &#8216;require&#8217; spec line is commented out in features/support/env.rb.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;2. Modify the steps in features/step_definitions/webrat_steps.rb&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Mostly, what you will do here is convert the matchers to thier Test::Unit equivalents.  For instance, response.body.should_not =~ /#{text}/m is synonymous to assert_no_match(response.body, /#{text}/m)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;3. There is no step 3.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So I&#8217;ve using this for a few days, I&#8217;ve noticed nothing weird, and I will be using this in &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; my projects.  Thanks to RSpec team for creating such a cool project.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-11-08:30337</id>
    <published>2008-11-08T22:21:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-12T01:05:30Z</updated>
    <category term="couchdb"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/11/8/couchdb-basic-authentication" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>CouchDB basic authentication</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://incubator.apache.org/couchdb/&quot;&gt;CouchDB&lt;/a&gt; comes with no authentication out the box, and in this video, I show you how to hook up authentication, so you can actually move your sweet &lt;a href=&quot;http://incubator.apache.org/couchdb/&quot;&gt;CouchDB&lt;/a&gt; based application to production.&lt;/p&gt;


&amp;lt;object height=&quot;251&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;param /&gt;&amp;lt;param /&gt;&amp;lt;param /&gt;&amp;lt;embed src=&quot;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2189840&amp;amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;amp;fullscreen=1&quot; height=&quot;251&quot; width=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/embed&gt;&amp;lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/2189840&quot;&gt;CouchDB basic authentication&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user472736&quot;&gt;Bryan Liles&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 11/11/2008&#8212;there may be an issue with design documents, i&#8217;m investigating it now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://smartic.us/">
    <author>
      <name>bryanl</name>
    </author>
    <id>tag:smartic.us,2008-11-07:30294</id>
    <published>2008-11-07T18:21:00Z</published>
    <updated>2008-11-07T19:37:04Z</updated>
    <category term="tatft"/>
    <link href="http://smartic.us/2008/11/7/tatft-lives-the-movie" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <title>TATFT Lives -- The Movie</title>
<content type="html">
            &lt;p&gt;I&#8217;m a coder.  I write code.  I&#8217;m starting a new project, and I&#8217;m asking for everyone&#8217;s help.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;blockquote&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;If someone asked you what you thought about the state of testing in the Ruby community, what would you say?  Are you for more testing, or are you testing enough?  Are we doing it wrong, or are we on the right path?  Or, is this a tired subject, that needs no more discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/blockquote&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I want to hear it all, and put it in a documentary I want to make next year.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, now you&#8217;ve heard my spiel, and you want to know how you can help I bet.  This is real easy.  If you see me, pull me aside, and tell me what you have to say.  I always will have my camera on me, or you can upload your video and send me a link, or we can do Skype.  The point is that I want &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;YOU&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to be heard.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think? Share your ideas and your videos with me at tatft@smartic.us.&lt;/p&gt;
          </content>  </entry>
</feed>
