<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl" type="text/xsl" media="screen"?><?xml-stylesheet href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css" type="text/css" media="screen"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ship's Log</title>
    <link>http://terralien.com/blog/rss/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>The main blog feed for Terralien's Ship's Log.</description>
    
      
        <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/terralien-ships-log" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
          <title>Sprint or Marathon?</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;Both sprints and marathons have starting lines, and the people lined up behind them are equally pumped up to start running the race. Adrenaline courses through the veins of a marathon runner on the starting line as surely as it does through the runner of a sprint waiting for the gun. And each kind of runner looks towards the finish line for their race, the end goal in sight.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;And yet &amp;#8211; what happens between the start and finish of a marathon and a sprint couldn&amp;#8217;t be more different. In a sprint, the effort is focused in to mere seconds or perhaps minutes, and the runners push hard, giving everything they&amp;#8217;ve got with each foot traveled. It doesn&amp;#8217;t matter if they collapse after only running a few hundred yards &amp;#8211; so long as they got over the finish line first, they&amp;#8217;ve won. The start is critical, as it makes up a huge percentage of the race, and as the race is run, a tiny stumble spells doom. It&amp;#8217;s a very unforgiving race &amp;#8211; everything must be done just right, or there&amp;#8217;ll be no trophy.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;A marathon is something altogether different. Everyone knows as they leave the starting line that they&amp;#8217;re going to be running a long time, and that if they don&amp;#8217;t pace themselves they&amp;#8217;ll never make it to the end much less have the best time. The start is important, but pales in comparison to sustained progress. Even a large stumble disappears in to the noise of the race so long as it doesn&amp;#8217;t result in any physical damage. And the race is as much against the clock as it is against the other runners, with everyone striving towards their personal best.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Now, I&amp;#8217;m more of a sitter than a runner, so I know these things not from experiencing them but rather from watching &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082158/"&gt;Chariots of Fire&lt;/a&gt; and talking to people who have run marathons. But what I do have lots of first hand experience with is building businesses, and I can tell you that there are important, enduring lessons to be had in this comparison for anyone thinking of starting a business. The external view of entrepreneurship, and the view of many just starting out in it, is that it&amp;#8217;s a sprint: all the energy focused in to a small period of time for a huge pay-off at the end. Yet once you have a few months of a new business under your belt you&amp;#8217;ll discover that it&amp;#8217;s really a marathon, with the focus being on endurance and constant progress. Going really fast turns out to be overrated, and envisioning and constantly moving towards a finish line that is well out of sight is what separates the winners from the losers.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Those who approach business as a sprint quickly burn out. They run the first few months, maybe even the first year or two, with a gusto that seems enviable. And yet, as time wears on, they tire and start to get discouraged, and often collapse well before the half way point. Those who realize they&amp;#8217;re embarking on a marathon, however, get off to a good start, and yet quickly fall far behind the sprinters. But soon enough they catch up, and then gradually leave those less prepared behind.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;As you think about the business you want to start (I know you have one!), are you prepared for it to be a marathon? Are you ready to stick it out for years to make it a success? Big, sudden success stories are usually the product of years of quiet persistence, or &lt;a href="http://www.gather.com/viewArticle.jsp?articleId=281474976794753"&gt;as Sam Walton said of Wal-Mart&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;#8220;Like most other overnight successes, it was about 20 years in the making.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So which are you planning to run? A sprint, or a marathon?&lt;/p&gt;
              
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2009/01/12/sprint-or-marathon/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/510076983/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2009/01/12/sprint-or-marathon/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Nathaniel at acts_as_conference</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll be keynoting at acts_as_conference in Orlando, Florida in February, and I can&amp;#8217;t wait! &lt;a href="http://blog.talbott.ws/articles/2008/12/17/keynoting-at-acts_as_conference"&gt;More details over at my personal blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
              
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 19:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/12/17/nathaniel-at-acts_as_conference/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/487949027/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/12/17/nathaniel-at-acts_as_conference/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Codename MC</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;Terralien&amp;#8217;s building a product! Come follow along at &lt;a href="http://codenamemc.terralien.com/"&gt;Codename MC&lt;/a&gt; to get a peek at what we&amp;#8217;re building and the process we&amp;#8217;re building it with.&lt;/p&gt;
              
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 20:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/12/08/codename-mc/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/478844320/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/12/08/codename-mc/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Now or Never</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a lot of uncertainty right now about the economy, about jobs, and more immediately for some folks, about paying for Christmas. Economic times are tough, or so they tell us, and all the talking heads (who were, it should be noted, saying how great things were six months ago) are telling us the sky is falling. Regardless of how sound your personal financial position is, it&amp;#8217;s hard to not accept at least a part of that vibe in to your own thinking, and start panicking inside over what might (or might not) happen.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;And yet, the amazing thing is that today is pretty much like yesterday, and this month is pretty much like last month. The only real difference is in our perception and understanding (right or wrong) of reality.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So the question is, why aren&amp;#8217;t you starting that business you&amp;#8217;ve been contemplating for months? Or maybe it&amp;#8217;s been years? Is it because of the current economic news? I doubt it. If it was, you would&amp;#8217;ve started it before we realized things were bad, and it would already be in process now.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The story we tell ourselves is key, and while we might be getting bombarded with a particularly sour story right now externally, it&amp;#8217;s the internal story that prevents (or enables!) us to build something successful. And that&amp;#8217;s why a whole bunch of smart people with way more experience than me are saying that right now is a great time to start a business, &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2008/09/looking-for-a-r.html"&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/badeconomy.html"&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt; being just two of them.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Regardless of what you decide to do, I know what I&amp;#8217;m going to do: lean in to the wind of popular opinion and use this time to build something great. I hope you&amp;#8217;ll join me!&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Of course, I have an ulterior motive in encouraging you to get started, since it&amp;#8217;s startups and entrepreneurs and small agile businesses that we focus on here at &lt;a href="http://terralien.com"&gt;Terralien&lt;/a&gt;. If you need help on the software design+development side of things, I hope you&amp;#8217;ll &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/contact/"&gt;drop me a line&lt;/a&gt; so we can figure out how Terralien can help you succeed regardless of what the pundits say.&lt;/p&gt;
              
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 21:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/12/04/now-or-never/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/475086967/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/12/04/now-or-never/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Smart Asset Management for Rails Plugins</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;Many Rails plugins require that certain files like images, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt;, and JavaScript get copied to the public folder during installation. The typical way to do this is add code to install.rb, which then gets executed when you first install the plugin in your Rails project. What happens when the assets in a plugin you&amp;#8217;re using change, though? You end up having to manually copy files around anytime the plugin gets updated, which is an extremely error-prone process (if you remember to do it in the first place!).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I got tired of mucking around with install.rb and having to sling files around whenever a plugin changed, and so I wrote &lt;a href="http://github.com/pelargir/asset_copier/tree/master"&gt;asset_copier&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a generator that runs against your plugin and installs an asset management system that gets checked in with the rest of your plugin code. Once installed, any Rails app your plugin is installed in gets a plugin_name:install task that intelligently copies over any files located in the /files subdirectory in the plugin. Files will also be copied over every time the plugin is reloaded or Rails is restarted in development mode. When running in production mode, warnings will be printed to the log for files that are missing or have changed.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;You can check out the &lt;a href="http://github.com/pelargir/asset_copier/tree/master#readme"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for installation instructions and additional documentation, and I&amp;#8217;d love to get any and all feedback you have as you start using it in your own plugins.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if you&amp;#8217;re looking for a plugin using asset_copier, look no further than the &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/10/29/announcing-the-textile_toolbar-plugin/"&gt;textile_toolbar&lt;/a&gt; that Terralien announced recently.&lt;/p&gt;
              
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 20:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/11/14/smart-asset-management-for-rails-plugins/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/453370262/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/11/14/smart-asset-management-for-rails-plugins/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Announcing the textile_toolbar Plugin</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m tired of settling for a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/span&gt; editor in my Rails apps. Plugins like &lt;a href="http://www.fckeditor.net/"&gt;FCKeditor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://tinymce.moxiecode.com/"&gt;TinyMCE&lt;/a&gt; work moderately well for the end user, but they can generate ugly &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTML&lt;/span&gt; on the backend. I hate dealing with that. &lt;a href="http://hobix.com/textile/"&gt;Textile&lt;/a&gt; is so much better, but our clients often dislike dealing with the markup. Isn&amp;#8217;t there a way to bridge the niceness of Textile with the end user experience of a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/span&gt; editor?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It turns out that there is: it&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://github.com/pelargir/textile_toolbar"&gt;the new textile_toolbar plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Extracted from a recent Terralien project, the plugin adds a handy toolbar to Textile-enabled form fields. The buttons on the toolbar generate the appropriate Textile markup for your users. For example, clicking the &amp;#8220;Bold&amp;#8221; button will surround the highlighted word with the correct Textile markup to make it bold.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;textile_toolbar lets you retain the benefits of Textile while at the same time offering your users a friendly interface for generating markup. The plugin is a great way to learn Textile, but even if your users don&amp;#8217;t want to bother with memorizing the markup, the toolbar will still be there to assist them with their editing.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s easy to get started with textile_toolbar. To install the plugin in your Rails 2.1 (or greater) project, run:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
script/plugin install git://github.com/pelargir/textile_toolbar.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;To add the toolbar to an existing text area, change the text_area or text_field helper call to textile_area. It&amp;#8217;s that simple! Be sure to check out the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;README&lt;/span&gt; for further integration guidelines and options.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; A live example of a Textile-enabled text area can now be found &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/projects/textile-toolbar/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
              
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 21:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/10/29/announcing-the-textile_toolbar-plugin/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/436314254/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/10/29/announcing-the-textile_toolbar-plugin/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Radiant CMS Extensions</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;Up until recently I had admired the &lt;a href="http://radiantcms.org/"&gt;Radiant Content Management System&lt;/a&gt; from afar but hadn&amp;#8217;t had a chance to really dig in to it. While &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/"&gt;the Terralien website&lt;/a&gt; runs on Radiant, a lot of the power of Radiant doesn&amp;#8217;t come to the fore until you want to extend it, and our website&amp;#8217;s needs are very vanilla. So when an opportunity came along for us to do the back-end for a content heavy site for &lt;a href="http://ignitesocialmedia.com/"&gt;Ignite Social Media&lt;/a&gt;, I jumped at the chance to put Radiant through its paces. In particular I got to do a bunch of Radiant extension development, both writing an extension from scratch as well as doing heavy hacking on some existing extensions, and I&amp;#8217;d like to talk some about that process as well as highlighting the (all open source) extensions that came out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;First, a little about the site we built: it&amp;#8217;s a marketing site for a newly launched product, and we were tasked with taking comps from Ignite, implementing them in Radiant, and hooking up the various dynamic pieces of the site. Those dynamic bits included a quiz visitors can take, blog comments, various mailer forms, site search, a site map, etc. All fairly standard stuff, but the goal was to build out exactly the back-end that was need for the project rather than using a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt; that provides everything and the kitchen sink and ending up with a cluttered, confusing admin interface. Of course Radiant being Rails-based was also a big draw: almost every project needs to &amp;#8220;draw outside the lines&amp;#8221; at least once, and we think it&amp;#8217;s ever so much nicer to do custom development in Ruby than it is in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, the lingua franca of most popular &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CMS&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;After getting Radiant up and running on our staging server &amp;#8211; a completely painless process &amp;#8211; work commenced with the &lt;a href="http://github.com/ntalbott/radiant-quiz-extension/tree/master"&gt;quiz extension&lt;/a&gt; which I wrote from scratch. The experience was mostly painless, but there were two aspects I think can be improved on. First of all, the &lt;a href="http://wiki.radiantcms.org/"&gt;available documentation&lt;/a&gt; is a bit spotty, and while this didn&amp;#8217;t bother me too much (I&amp;#8217;m an avid code reader) I could see it causing issues for some folks. The other thing I found somewhat disconcerting when getting started was the lack of direction on how best to implement the mechanics of an extension. Some extensions post back to a custom page type, some extensions provide their own controllers, and error handling is all over the map. I think some of the issue is just that generic component-based development is hard, but that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean that a &amp;#8220;best practice&amp;#8221; extension style couldn&amp;#8217;t be adopted and encouraged. I ended up settling on a particular style that I think works well, but it still has some significant drawbacks, and I&amp;#8217;ll definitely be continuing to noodle on the issue as I work on future extensions.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;After the quiz extension, I moved on to some areas that already had existing extensions available, in particular &lt;a href="http://github.com/radiant/radiant-mailer-extension/tree/master"&gt;mailers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://github.com/artofmission/radiant-comments/tree/master"&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://github.com/ntalbott"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; was the star that stole the show here, since I ended up forking both of these extensions and hacking on them extensively to get them working like I wanted. Since the comments extension was already on Github I was then able to submit the changes to it right back to the original author, and he incorporated them in to his repo. Currently you can only get my mailer changes from &lt;a href="http://github.com/ntalbott/radiant-mailer-extension/tree/master"&gt;my Github hosted fork&lt;/a&gt;, but a little birdy has told me that Radiant will be moving wholesale to git in the near future, and when it does I&amp;#8217;ll be contributing my changes back.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Of course, we also used a bunch of extensions completely as-is, in particular the &lt;a href="http://gravityblast.com/projects/radiant-copymove-extension/"&gt;Copy Move extension&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://github.com/radiant/radiant-reorder-extension/tree/master"&gt;Reorder extension&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="http://github.com/radiant/radiant-search-extension/tree/master"&gt;Search extension&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks so much to the authors of these extensions as well as the ones we forked: you saved us so much time!&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;And we&amp;#8217;re not done yet: in the works we have a &amp;#8220;ratings extension&amp;#8221;, and we&amp;#8217;ll also be doing some serious hacking around &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/span&gt; editing and asset management. You can keep up with the latest by watching &lt;a href="http://github.com/ntalbott"&gt;my Github page&lt;/a&gt;, or I&amp;#8217;ll try to post an update when we push out our next batch of extension-y goodness.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, have you tried out Radiant? What did you think of it? Any cool extensions you&amp;#8217;ve found whilst poking around the internet that we should be sure to take a look at? Have you written an extension yourself? I&amp;#8217;d love to hear your thoughts!&lt;/p&gt;
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 09:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/06/18/radiant_cms_extensions/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/315825769/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/06/18/radiant_cms_extensions/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Ruby Hoedown!</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;If there&amp;#8217;s one thing that we believe in (and have benefited from in a big way) at Terralien, it&amp;#8217;s the power of the Ruby community. Since I attended the first RubyConf in Tampa in 2001, I&amp;#8217;ve been constantly amazed by the vibrancy, passion, and all-around &lt;em&gt;niceness&lt;/em&gt; of Rubyists when they gather in groups, whether virtually or physically. And so it is with great pleasure I point you to the second annual &lt;a href="http://rubyhoedown.com/"&gt;Ruby Hoedown&lt;/a&gt;, the southeast region&amp;#8217;s premier Ruby conference, taking place this year in Huntsville, AL. The organizers already have &lt;a href="http://rubyhoedown.com/schedule.html"&gt;the schedule&lt;/a&gt; up and &lt;a href="http://rubyhoedown.eventwax.com/ruby-hoedown-2008/register"&gt;registration open&lt;/a&gt;, so head on over there, check out the top-notch offerings, and make your plans to be in Huntsville in August this year. While I&amp;#8217;m not helping to organize the conference this year, I&amp;#8217;m definitely going to be attending it, so I&amp;#8217;ll see you there!&lt;/p&gt;
              
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 09:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/06/11/ruby_hoedown/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/315825770/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/06/11/ruby_hoedown/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Prices: To Publish, or Not to Publish?</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s an age-old question for services companies: should we publish our prices, at least some of them, or should we wait until we&amp;#8217;ve had a conversation with a potential client before discussing price? Recently at Terralien we&amp;#8217;ve changed our answer to that question and decided to start publishing some of our prices, and I thought I&amp;#8217;d write a bit about the thought process that went in to the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Actually this process started at least a year ago when I added a little drop-down box to our contact form that had general budget information in it. The options started at $10k and went up from there, and the reasoning was simple: I was getting at least one request a week from people looking to get their huge projects done for $2k (more or less). Talking to people with such unrealistic expectations was a complete waste of time: no, we&amp;#8217;re not going to do your 400+ hour design/development project for $5/hour. Really. And just putting that little $10,000 budget as the lowest option immediately cut these requests out almost completely.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;#8217;ve taken it a step further: on our &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/about/product-outlining"&gt;Product Outlining&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/about/launch-cycles"&gt;Launch Cycle&lt;/a&gt; pages you&amp;#8217;ll find a published price for each of those services. These prices, and a price for our Background Work, also show up on our updated &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/contact"&gt;contact page&lt;/a&gt; as well. Of course, all prices are negotiable &amp;#8211; we&amp;#8217;d love to customize a project for you that fits your budget and your timeline. That said, we think that providing at least a starting point for negotiations helps potential clients to envision and plan what it would take to get their idea live, and that&amp;#8217;s important for an entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;We had some interesting internal discussions about publishing prices, and I&amp;#8217;m not 100% sure it&amp;#8217;s something we&amp;#8217;ll do long-term &amp;#8211; for now it&amp;#8217;s very much on probation. There are concerns that it makes us appear as a commodity instead of the custom software shop we are. On the other hand, there was a lot of internal excitement about being so transparent. As entrepreneurs ourselves, we know how useful it can be to get an initial peek at what it might take to launch our ideas before diving in to details negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So what are your thoughts? Should services companies publish at least some of their prices? Should Terralien? Does it help or hurt?&lt;/p&gt;
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 11:22:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/06/04/prices_to_publish_or_not/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/315825771/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/06/04/prices_to_publish_or_not/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
        <item>
          <title>Refining and Refreshing</title>
          <description>
            
              &lt;p&gt;We just launched a refresh of the content on our &lt;a href="http://terralien.com"&gt;main site&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; do check it out! While the changes aren&amp;#8217;t very drastic, they do reflect a significant refinement to how we do business and I wanted to take the opportunity to talk a bit about why we made them&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;As any business owner will tell you, two years of running a business will net you a lot of learning, and that&amp;#8217;s certainly been true with Terralien. As I&amp;#8217;ve worked with clients and crew members over the past two years, I&amp;#8217;ve been able to start recognizing some patterns in the requests that we get, and in the expectations that our clients have. In particular I&amp;#8217;ve found that our clients highly value three things: insight, predictability, and transparency. Every successful Terralien project has had a high level of these three things, and every failure of any size has been lacking in one or more of them. I&amp;#8217;ve come to realize that if Terralien can consistently deliver all three, we stand a good chance of making each and every project a raging success, which is of course our ever-present goal. So how are we addressing each of them?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;In the area of insight one of the primary ways we&amp;#8217;ve failed in the past is at the start. We&amp;#8217;re not big fans of lots of up-front planning, but me whipping out an estimate in a couple of hours was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; cutting it. Part of the difficulty is the snow-ball effect &amp;#8211; if the project gets started off on the wrong foot, it&amp;#8217;s a lot more likely that things will get worse than that they will get better. Thus we&amp;#8217;ve started going through an explicit &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/about/product-outlining"&gt;product outlining&lt;/a&gt; process with most clients where we spend some quality time understanding what needs building before we try to build it. As an added benefit, product outlining generates portable insight: clients can take what we learn and use it to get estimates from shops other than Terralien. Definitely &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/about/product-outlining"&gt;check out the details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Predictability is a real conundrum since we haven&amp;#8217;t yet figured out how to predict the future, and reading &amp;#8220;Prognostication for Dummies&amp;#8221; didn&amp;#8217;t seem to help much. Regardless of the difficulties, though, this is one of the most immediate concerns clients have, and every project starts out with the same questions: &amp;#8220;How much will it cost and how long will it take?&amp;#8221; While we can&amp;#8217;t predict the future, past experience has taught us that we can almost always launch a useful product in about two months. We call these two month time boxes &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/about/launch-cycles"&gt;launch cycles&lt;/a&gt; and we&amp;#8217;re finding they really help clients to both know what their budget will be for initial launch and to stay focused within that window.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Finally, there&amp;#8217;s the all-important quality of transparency. Transparency isn&amp;#8217;t so much about one big thing; rather, it&amp;#8217;s about a lot of little things that add up to a big thing. If a client is paying us they deserve to know how the work is going and to feel comfortable with our progress, and there are lots of small ways we&amp;#8217;ve learned and are learning to keep them in the loop. Most important is just making sure they&amp;#8217;re comfortable telling us when they&amp;#8217;re not satisfied so we can fix it, and I personally am learning a lot about making myself open and available to hear the concerns. It&amp;#8217;s not always easy to do, but it&amp;#8217;s always worth it.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve really tried to capture the essence of these things in the site refresh, so please have a look and let us know if we&amp;#8217;ve succeeded. &lt;a href="http://terralien.com/contact"&gt;Feedback is always welcome!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
            
          </description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 14:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/05/05/refining_and_refreshing/</guid>
          <link>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/terralien-ships-log/~3/315825772/</link>
        <feedburner:origLink>http://terralien.com/blog/articles/2008/05/05/refining_and_refreshing/</feedburner:origLink></item>
      
    
  <feedburner:awareness>http://api.feedburner.com/awareness/1.0/GetFeedData?uri=terralien-ships-log</feedburner:awareness></channel>
</rss>
